- Start Where You Are.
Our second guiding principle
is to start where you are.
This is a really important
guiding principle
because whenever you get
into an organization,
even if you're a brand new hire,
they already have existing
processes and services in place
and if you're brought
onboard to help improve that
through an improvement initiative,
you have to remember that
we don't want to start
with a blank slate each time.
We want to start where we are.
If I had you come in and
I hired you to figure out
the best way to create
a new service or process
to do voucher fulfillment for my students,
every time somebody comes to our website
to buy an exam voucher,
you would have to look at the way
the current process is done.
Then you can figure out
what is the better way to do it, right?
But if you don't start with
where we currently are,
and you just start from a blank slate,
you're going to spend a
lot of time and resources
doing stuff that isn't the
way that we currently do it.
And there's probably some amount of value
in the way we currently do it.
So whenever you're engaged
in an improvement initiative,
I don't want you to start over
without first looking at
what is already available
to be leveraged,
because something there
is probably valuable.
Now when you have a
decision on how to proceed,
you have to think about this based on
the accurate information that's obtained
through your direct observation
supported by appropriate
and effective measurement.
Again, if I have you come in,
you're going to look at
the way we currently do
voucher fulfillment.
If you looked at us about a year ago,
the way we did it was
a student would buy it
through our shopping cart on our website,
that would send an email to me,
I would then go and order the voucher,
take that voucher, put it in an email,
and email it back to the student.
It was a very manual process.
Now if you came in and
looked at that, you'd say,
"Hey, I can make this a lot better.
"I can automate this.
"We can do five or six different ways
"of doing this process."
But if you looked at the
way we were doing it,
you'd at least know the proper steps
that need to be included,
which was we had to buy
the voucher from Axelos,
we then had to give that
voucher to our student,
and we had to collect
money from our students
for that voucher.
So we'd have to figure
out what those steps are.
By figuring out what the current steps are
and how fast it is or how slow it is
or what pain points there are,
you can then overcome them as
you're trying to go forward,
and some of those parts
of starting where you are
are useful.
Some of those you're going
to decide aren't useful
and you'll push them away.
All of this is done by
measuring what you have,
and measurements should be
used to support your analysis
of what you're observing
rather than just simply replacing it.
Not everything can be measured
with zeros and ones and numbers.
Some things in data analytics,
we rely on way too much
and we oversee some of the basic things
that we should be observing
with our own eyes.
Again, if you came in and
looked at our voucher process,
it was very simple, right?
But that worked when we started out
because we were selling
maybe two vouchers a week.
Now we're selling a
lot of vouchers a week,
and if we had to do that all
manually it wouldn't work.
The timeline to deliver to our students
would take way too long,
so instead we've looked
at that using measurement,
we've gotten our time down
where now we deliver a voucher
in about five minutes, and
a lot of it is automated.
Now there's still some
parts of the process
that are still manual,
but that's just because of the way
that those systems operate,
and we're going through and
we're constantly improving that
to reduce that time down
to give a better value and
experience for our customers.
Now, the act of measuring
can affect your results
and this is something that's
important to think about
because as you go through and
you try to measure everything
that's currently going on,
sometimes the people you're measuring
will change the way they're working
because they know they're being watched.
This happens a lot inside
the service desk area.
If you're doing something like measuring
how quickly a call is resolved,
what you'll start seeing is
that your first level agents
will close out trouble tickets
even before things are
solved for your consumers.
That means that your measurement
is going to go up, saying,
"Oh, look how quickly we've been able to
"resolve all these calls,"
but in reality your customers
aren't getting the value
they want because their
calls aren't being resolved.
I've seen this even at some places
like drive-through restaurants.
If you've ever gone through a McDonald's,
they have a counter and
they have a measurement
of 30 seconds to deliver
the food to you in your car
to get you on the road again.
But if they can't get
that, what do they do?
The tell you to pull off to a parking spot
so they can mark your order as complete,
and that way their timer stops,
even though you still
haven't gotten your food
and that way they can
help the next person.
You may be sitting there for
10 minutes to get your food.
Because they know they're being measured,
that's going to affect the results
because they're going to cheat the system.
Now when you set measurements,
another thing I want you to think about
is that when the
measurement becomes a target
it ceases to be a good measure.
Going back to that McDonald's example.
If I say every car has to get
their food within 30 seconds
and that becomes the target,
we're no longer trying to give good food
or good value to the customer.
Instead we're just trying
to get them in and out
within 30 seconds.
So that is something
you have to be wary of.
Measurement is great in business.
We use measurement a lot.
But you want to make sure you're
measuring the right things
and it's not the target in and of itself.
You're measuring things to determine if
you're making progress towards the outcome
that you really want.
We talked about that
before when we talked about
measuring outputs versus
measuring outcomes.
This is an important concept to remember.
When we talk about starting where you are,
how do we really apply
this guiding principle?
First I want you to look at what exists
as objectively as possible.
You may come into a
new place and they say,
"You're going to come
in because our current
"service management system sucks.
"It's bad, it's horrible,
"so we're hiring you as the new manager.
"Come in and overhaul the place."
You may come in and your
first thing you want to do
is just delete everything
they have and start over.
Please resist that urge.
Instead look at what is there,
figure out what is useful
and what you can build upon.
You can determine if there
are successful practices
or services in place that
can be replicated or expanded
across the organization,
and you can determine the
things that are not successful
and those things that need to be changed
or deleted or removed.
You want to be applying your
risk management skills here
in your decision making progress
because if we decide to
just throw everything away
and start from the beginning,
we're going to spend a lot more
time and assume a lot more risk
because it is a lot
easier to fix something
than it is to create something new.
Also you should recognize that sometimes
nothing from the current
state can be reused,
and you are going to simply
have to create a blank slate.
Now when you're going to do that,
you're going to have
to think about the way
to make that transition happen.
A good example of that
is my current website.
As we're filming this video
we're actually going through
a major website redesign
and overhaul, and it's not just a redesign
of the website itself and
how it looks and feels,
but all of the underlying
services are being rebuilt
from the ground up.
The current provider we were on
was great when we had just a
couple of hundred students,
but as we've grown they can't
support the demand anymore
and their processes just don't work well
for the long-term vision of our company.
So instead we're building
a brand new system
from the ground up.
We have a brand new operating system,
brand new servers, a
brand new cloud provider,
and we've built the
entire application layer
that does the course delivery ourself.
All of that means we've
taken a huge amount of risk
because we're migrating from
something that we know works
into something that we're
trying to make work.
So because of that we have
to use proper risk management
and do mitigations.
One of those is we broke
up the phase deployment
of moving things over in pieces,
so as we brought up the new site
we brought over the homepage first
but we didn't bring over the shopping cart
and we didn't bring over the
content and lesson delivery.
Next we're bringing over
the shopping cart pieces,
making sure that all works,
and then we're going to
bring over the big bulk
which is our learning management system.
We're doing this over a
two or a three month period
in very deliberate phased approaches,
and by the time we're done
most of what we had on the old site
is not going to be reused.
It's going to be thrown away
because a lot of that doesn't
apply on the new systems
and the new services we've built.
So that sometimes is
where you're going to be,
but I would implore to
you always think about
what can be reused from the current system
to the old system.
In our case, a lot of our old training
was able to be brought over.
Our practice exams were
able to be brought over.
Our PDFs and our videos were
So we didn't have to
recreate 20 classes again.
But a lot of the services and the support
that underlaid that system
is being rebuilt again
from a blank slate because
that could not be reused.
As you go through your organizations,
you need to think about what can I reuse
when I start from where I am
and what do I need to start over on?
That's the guiding principle that we use
as our second guiding principle.