- It's finally time to take some action.
We have our vision, we have our baseline,
we have our goals, and we have our plan.
Now in step five we're
going to take action
and put those plans into motion.
When you're taking action you can do this
under a traditional waterfall approach,
where a large improvement initiative
is broken down into phases,
a lot of planning and
preparation is performed
and then a large sweeping change occurs
over a very short period of time,
and you transition to the new system.
This may work when you needed
to take a really old system, for example,
and completely replace it.
But, most of the time, you're
probably going to take action
in smaller iterations, using
a much more agile methodology.
In this case, you're
going to deliver smaller
product and service improvements,
but you're going to do
them much more frequently
creating incremental but
smaller wins and value.
Either method'll work
and it really depends
on your situation on which
one you're going to use.
During this effort there needs to be
a continual focus on
measuring your progress
towards the vision, managing
your risk during those changes,
and ensuring visibility and
awareness of the initiative
is spread throughout the organization
so everybody knows what's going on.
Once the improvement
initiative is complete,
we then can move on to step six
and find out if we were successful or not.