- Capacity and performance management.
This is another one that
you don't need to know
for the foundation level exam.
But we're going to cover it so
you have a good understanding,
because it is one you're
going to run across
inside the real world.
So, the purpose of capacity
and performance management practice
is to ensure that services
achieve the agreed-upon
and expected performance,
satisfies the current and future demand
in a cost-effective way.
When we talk about performance,
this is a measure of what's
achieved by delivering a system,
a person, a team, a practice or a service
to do some sort of function.
So, if I'm talking about
service performance,
this is associated with a
number of service actions
performed in a given timeframe,
and the time to fill that service action
at a given level of demand.
Going back to my voucher example,
when you order a voucher,
our service performance metric
is that you have it in your
hand within ten minutes.
That's really quick, right?
Generally you're going to get
it in less than 30 seconds,
but sometimes it's a little longer.
Now, when we talk about
capacity, on the other hand,
and we look at our service capacity,
this is the maximum throughput
that a configuration item
or service can deliver.
So, if I'm talking about the
capacity of your hard drive,
it's how much data you can store.
If I'm talking about the capacity
of your network connection,
it's how fast it is.
Is it 100 megabits per second?
Is it one gigabit per second?
Whatever it happens to be,
that would be your maximum throughput
for that configuration item.
Now, as we go through and
we look at our capacity
and our performance management,
this is where a lot of the
metrics come into place.
If you're working in a technical realm
and you're measuring server capacity
and server performance,
there's going to be lots of different
metrics you're going to get.
I want to warn you again,
don't just measure the outputs,
measure the outcomes.
What is important of all these
metrics and measurements?
Why are we measuring them?
What are we hoping to achieve?
Often times in capacity
and performance management,
people lose sight of the bigger picture
and they focus so hard
on the individual metrics
of capacity and performance
that it becomes useless.
So, I want to warn you against that,
but in the real world
you are going to run into
capacity and performance management a lot,
especially if you're
a system administrator
or a network administrator.
Because those are things
that, you're trying to meet
those particular standards
inside capacity and performance
to meet the metrics you're given.