- Now that you've finished
the ITIL 4 Foundation,
you may be wondering what comes next.
Well, the ITIL path has
several different exams
that link you up to what we call
the ITIL Master Certification.
And you'll see here on the screen,
there's actually two distinct paths.
There's a left path and a right path.
Let's go ahead and start
with the left path.
Now on the left side,
you're working up from ITIL
foundation up to what's learned
as the MP or ITIL managing professional.
The ITIL managing professional,
to earn that certification,
you have to earn four ITIL
specialist certifications.
Each one of these has
their own exam for them.
Now the ITIL specialist for
create, deliver and support,
ITIL specialist for
drive stakeholder value,
ITIL specialist for high velocity IT
and ITIL specialist for
direct, plan and improve.
As you take all four of these
exams and you pass them,
once you get all four,
you are now known as an
ITIL managing professional.
Now if we look on the right side,
you can also become an
ITIL strategic leader.
An ITIL strategic leader is
mostly focused on management
and leadership and has only
two requirements for that.
You'll have to get the ITIL
specialist for direct, plan
and improve and the ITIL
leader certification
for digital and IT strategy.
Now you may have noticed
that one of those exams
is shared on both sides of the chart.
We have the ITIL specialist
for direct, plan and improve
which is found on both the
managing professional path
and the strategic leader path.
So when it comes down to it,
if you've already gotten
the managing professional,
it's only one more exam, the ITIL leader
that will then get you to
being a strategic leader
and when you put both of those together
that then brings you up
to being an ITIL master.
So the entire pathway
is laid out before you.
Which should you go for next?
Well, that's really up to you
and what you do in your organization.
Based on the job that you're doing,
you're going to want to pick
the ITIL specialist or
ITIL leader certification
that most aligns to the role you're doing
and then you'll learn the other roles,
be able to get their
certifications as well
and work your way up to
being an ITIL master.