- Congratulations you did it,
you've reached the end of the course.
Together, we have spent a lot of time
as we've gone through 100 lessons
of videos and quizzes to teach you
everything you need to know
for the ITIL 4 Foundation exam.
Now, if you're like most students
you're getting ready to go take that exam,
what should you being doing now?
First, you should make sure
you have that study guide
from lesson one of the course.
In there we have all of
the definitions you need,
and all of the purposes
and all of the terms
that are memorization items,
as well as all of our
notes from the course.
If you've been following
along as we've gone through
the course and that guide,
you've probably highlighted it
and taken notes, which is great.
Then, I want you to take
some practice exams.
I've included a couple
of them in this course
and I want you to make
sure you're taking those
and seeing where you score.
If you're scoring 75%, or 80%, or higher,
you're ready to take the
real certification exam.
If you're not, you may want to get
a couple more practice
exams and keep practicing,
because that exam is expensive
and so another 10 or $15
to get some practice exams
might be worthwhile so
you can practice more
with some new questions.
Once you feel confident, I
want you to get your voucher
and schedule your exam.
Set a date in stone so you know
when you're going to take it.
That will help you study
better and more efficiently.
As I said back in our
first lesson together,
we're always going back
and improving this course
based on the feedback of our students.
If I didn't explain something well enough
or go into enough depth
based on the exam you took,
please let me know
because we're constantly
adding more to this course to make it
the best course there is for
anyone studying for ITIL 4.
So, once you pass the exam,
let me know how you did,
I'd love to hear about it,
and I hope to see you in a
future course, good luck!