- In today's digital economy,
every organization in the world
has become a service organization.
You may think your organization
isn't a service organization,
but when you really look at
what it does on a daily basis,
it truly is a service organization.
For example,
you may work for a grocery store,
and you may think you're in the business
of selling milk and cereal,
which are both products,
but in reality you're probably really
a service organization too.
Most of the services,
if not all of the services
that your company
currently owns and manages,
is done to co-create
value with your customers.
And these are enabled by
information technology.
Now, how can I make this claim?
Well, let's consider the
large retailer like Walmart,
who sells a large variety
of different products,
from diapers to groceries to
electronics and car tires.
Walmart has been wildly successful
in selling all of these
different products,
but the particular products Walmart sells,
doesn't really matter that much.
Instead the real reason that
Walmart has been so successful,
is that their available
to provide a service
to their customers that no one else
has been able to do the way they have.
And that is a collection of
services that's enabled by IT.
Walmart, for example,
has created a wonderfully robust
distribution and logistics system
to get their products
to their stores quickly,
efficiently and more cost
effectively than other people.
And this allows them to rely
on complex inventory tracking
and logistic systems,
that are all run by various
IT components and services.
They've been able to do
this to provide products
at their everyday low price,
which is actually the service
they provide to their customers.
Walmart's service is
bringing you the products
you want or need at the
lowest price, always.
Other stores can't bring
that to you at the same level
or the same cost that Walmart can.
So in a price battle,
Walmart is going to win every time,
because of their ability to embrace IT
to enable their services.
But how is Walmart
co-creating value with me,
the customer?
Lets say I was having a party tonight,
and I've invited you over for dinner.
I might run over to Walmart to
buy all the supplies I need.
Things like meat and cheeses,
vegetables and drinks,
and I bring them all back to my kitchen.
I then use all those ingredients
to cook a meal for my party tonight.
The value isn't the ingredients
that I got from Walmart.
It's the outcome that I had
when I co-created value with Walmart.
Walmart provided all the
ingredients at a low price,
and I've provided the
ability to cook it all up
into a delicious meal.
Now the value is the
happiness and the full bellies
of all of my guests at my party.
This is the value co-created
through the service.
Now as you think about all
the different industries
and organizations in the world,
it's really hard to think of any
that aren't providing some kind of service
that is enabled by technology.
Because of this technology
has become common place
in the modern workplace.
But all of this technology
needs to be managed
in order for it to be
effective and enabling value
to your customers by providing services.
And this brings us to the
concept of service management.
Service management is defined
as a set of specialized
organizational capabilities
for enabling value to customers
in the form of services.
The purpose of ITIL 4 is
to provide organizations,
working in this modern service economy,
with guidance from managing
their information technology
and information technology
dependencies effectively,
efficiently and in some coordinated,
structured and integrated way
that combines the agility,
the time to market,
and their ability to
deliver new things faster,
while using their risk controls
and providing insurance
that the services will be
performed properly today,
tomorrow and any day
further off into the future.
Notice this isn't just
about providing a service
fast to a customer,
but it's also about being
able to balance that
with the proper controls so that
that is providing a quality service,
now and into the future.
This ensures that there's
a balance of speed
in control within our
organizations and their services.
Simply put, ITIL 4 provides organizations
with a comprehensive framework
for IT service management.
This framework is designed
to ensure that an effective,
efficient, flexible,
coordinated and integrated system
for the governance and management
of services is established.
It also is concerned with
ensuring that these services
are continually improving
within your organization.
Now, if you're new to the business world
or information technology,
the word, governance,
might be one that you're
not quite familiar with.
Governance is simply the means
by which an organization
is directed and controlled.
This means that it involves
all of the processes needed
to govern or oversee the
running of the organization.
For example, in the United States,
our government creates
rules and laws that are used
as a method to direct the
actions of its citizens.
This is called governance, right?
It's the way that we operate a country.
Well, organizations need governance too.
And at your company,
there's a process probably
for everything you need to do.
Think about it if you wanted
to take two weeks of vacation.
You couldn't simply decide
just to not go to work
for two weeks without
telling your boss, right?
You'd probably end up loosing your job.
Now instead,
you're going to go through the
process to request a vacation,
and that process is going to be different
based on your organization
or my organization.
Because each organization runs itself
and its process is differently.
That way that they run things,
that's known as governance.