- ITIL was first created around the idea
how to conduct service management
within our organizations.
So, it should be no surprise
that we have a specific definition
of what is considered a service.
The definition of a service
is something you should be
able to recall for the exam,
as well as understand it.
According to ITIL four,
a service is a means of
enabling value co-creation
by facilitating outcomes that
the customer wants to achieve,
without that customer having to manage
the specific costs and risks.
Now, let's dig into this
definition one piece at a time.
First, service is a means of
enabling value co-creation.
This portion of the definition
is a reference back to
how value is determined
as a result of the relationship
between the provider of the service
and the customer of the service.
Next, the second portion
of the definition says
that this is done by facilitating outcomes
that customers want to achieve.
Again, this goes back
to the concept of value.
If I'm giving you something
as a service provider
that doesn't help you as the customer,
to achieve your objectives,
well, then it doesn't have any value.
So, going back to the earlier
example of this course,
if it doesn't help you pass
your certification exam,
then the value hasn't been co-created.
After all, the service provider
can't achieve your objectives for you.
You have to achieve them yourself.
The service provider is
only able to facilitate
the achievement of
those customer outcomes.
After all, you have to pass the exam.
I can only provide you with the tools
and the resources you need,
to be successful.
The same holds true with I-T services.
I can ensure your computer is
up and able to run a program.
But if you don't provide
the necessary inputs to that program,
you're going to be unable
to get the necessary outputs
and eventually the outcomes you desire.
Now, the final portion of
this service definition
states that this
co-created value is created
without the customer having to manage
specific costs and risks.
This refers to the whole
reason why a customer hires
a service provider in the first place.
For example, I'm a customer
of a web-hosting company
that hosts all of my training videos.
So, my organization pays
this web-hosting company
a monthly fee for hosting
terabytes of video files for us.
And in exchange for that service,
we pay them a nominal monthly fee.
It's their job as the service provider
to manage all the specific
costs and risks associated
with that service.
For example, our contract
allows for unlimited
data storage on their servers
and unlimited bandwidth to be used,
without incurring any additional
cost to us under our contract.
Because we negotiate a fixed-fee contract.
Now, my company employs a
lot of very technical folks.
I personally have been responsible
for running hundreds of web servers,
domain controllers, mail
servers and file servers
throughout my career.
So, why doesn't Dion Training maintain
and host our own web servers
to host all of our video training courses?
Well, simply put,
we don't want to have
to deal with the cost
and the risk of providing
that particular service.
It just isn't the business
that we're in anymore, right?
Instead, we're focused on training.
Our business is all about training,
not running these large server farms.
So, we don't want to have to deal
with the patching, the
updating, the back-ups,
scaling up and scaling down
based on low demands and all of that.
Instead, for negotiating flat-fee
with our service provider,
we can take all of those
costs and risks from us,
and we can simply pay our contracted rate.
And the service provider
gets to deal with it.
This is exactly what the service
definition is referring to.
So, let's take a look
at that service definition one more time.
A service is a means of
enabling value co-creation
by facilitating outcomes that
customers want to achieve,
without the customer having to manage
specific costs and risks.
So, in addition to services,
a service organization can
actually provide services
based on products that they have as well.
Now, a product is a configuration
of an organization's resources
that's designed to offer
value for a consumer.
I like to think of this as
the collection of services
that were put together to give more value
than they could individually.
Now, every organization works
with a set of resources.
These resources are either
owned by the organizations,
belong to the organization,
or, are managed by the organization.
These resources may even
be supporting services
provided by the organization
suppliers and their partners.
These resources can be leased or rented.
These resources could even be the people
who work in an organization
under a contractual agreement.
Because these people are a resource
to the organization, too.
Now, the way an organization configures
all those resources into a set offering
is the essence of a product.
For example, Amazon Web Services or A-W-S,
has a lot of different service offerings.
Including server-hosting,
under their E-C-two brand.
File storage, under S-three.
Domain name server
systems, under Route 53.
And many others.
But, these services,
they aren't necessarily
considered products.
Now, if you compare
these individual services
with the Amazon Lightsail product,
you can see how Amazon has
combined their E-C-two,
their S-three and their Route 53 services
into a single product that can be sold
directly to a customer in
a defined configuration.
Everything that makes up Lightsail
is available as a service
individually from A-W-S.
But when combined under
the Lightsail product,
Amazon removed a lot of the
complexity and confusion
associated with that typical
new-customers' journey,
into the A-W-S and into cloud computing.
So, I know, we covered
a lot in this lesson.
But there's two key definitions
that we covered that you need to know.
First, is service.
A service is a means of
enabling value co-creation
by facilitating outcomes that
the customer wants to achieve,
without the customer having to manage
those specific costs and risks.
And the second one, is a product.
A product is simply a configuration
of an organization's resources
designed to offer value for a consumer.
Keep those two definitions in your head
because you're going to need 'em,
come test day.