- Service Level Management.
This is another one you
need to know in-depth.
First, let's start with the purpose.
The purpose of the
service level management
practice is to set clear
business-based targets
for service performance
so that the delivery
of a service can be properly assessed,
monitored, and managed
against these targets.
It's going to provide us
with end to end visibility
of the organization's services.
It's going to do this by establishing
a shared view of the services and the
target service levels with the customers,
so both the customers and
us know what to expect.
We're also going to focus on collecting,
analyzing, storing, and
reporting the relevant
metrics to ensure that we're meeting
the service levels.
We also want to make sure
that we're performing
service level reviews, to ensure the
current services continue to meet
the organization and the customer's needs.
We also are going to make sure that we're
capturing and reporting service issues
including performance against our
defined service levels.
So, if I said I want
to have 99.999% uptime,
service level management
is going to measure
my performance and see if
I'm meeting that level.
Now, all of these service levels
are going to be written
down in what's known
as an SLA, or a Service Level Agreement.
A Service Level Agreement is a documented
agreement between a service provider
and a customer that identifies services
required and the expected
level of service.
This is going to tell you
what metrics you need to meet.
The SLA is a tool that's used to measure
the performance of services from
the customer's point of view.
Now, there's a couple of things you need
to do to make sure that
you're going to have
a successful SLA.
First, you want to make sure it's
related to a defined service.
It can't be something generalized,
like customer is happy.
What is the customer happy with?
They're happy with the
email service delivery.
They want it to be fast, what
does fast really mean, right?
You need to make sure
you're defining the outcome
you want, not just operational metrics.
So, if the customer says "I want the
"email to be fast" well, does that mean
if I get it there in five seconds
they're happy, or if I get there in
five minutes they're happy?
I need to be able to define, really
what does fast mean?
And I don't want to just do that from
an output perspective, but also from an
outcome perspective.
Also, we want to make sure our agreement
is between the service provider
and the service consumer, and it
reflects their opinions accurately.
Because if the customer says
"The email service should be fast"
and they say five minutes is fast,
but the customer, or the
consumer in this case,
would think that it needs to be fast
meaning five seconds,
there's a disconnect there.
So we want to make sure
we understand it both
from the customer's
perspective, in our contract
but also from our consumer's perspective,
because that's really what the SLA
should be focused on, is
that server's consumer.
And the final key to writing a good SLA
is making sure you write it simply.
Make sure that it's easy to
understand by all parties.
This isn't a contract, it doesn't need
to be written with legal jargon.
Instead, make it simple and easy,
so that anyone who picks it up
can understand what you're talking about.
When you're writing your SLAs,
you always want to be focused on the
different relationships.
That includes things like
relationship management,
your supplier management, the different
skills and competencies,
the business liaisons,
and the business analysts.
All of that is things that are going to
feed into this SLA, and making sure
we understand who's responsible for what,
and to what level.
Now, our service level management
is built around these
various information sources.
One of those is our SLA, right,
that's the customer engagement
and the agreement we have.
Other things that we have, is going to be
things like our customer engagement
where we're listening
to our customers needs.
We're discovery and capturing the
information they want from them.
We want to get the measurement and
the ongoing process discussions with them.
We also want to ask simple
open-ended questions.
By getting that information, from our
service desk, or our customer liaisons,
we can get a lot of
the information we need
to build a good service
level management program.
And then, afterwards, we want
to get customer feedback.
This can be something like a survey,
or looking at key business-related
measures and metrics.
We might be look at some
operational metrics,
like server uptime and capacity.
We might look at some business metrics,
like monthly recurring revenue, or
lifetime value of a customer.
All of that can go in to this
service level management,
as something that feeds
into this practice.
Now as we look at this, and we see
how it affects our value chain activity,
let's talk about the plan activity.
In the plan activity, your service level
management is going to
support the planning
of your products and your service
portfolio, and your service offerings.
Because all the information you get
about the actual service
performance and trends
is going to feed into all that planning.
When you think about it from
the improve perspective,
service level management can help
be a driving force for continual
improvement and service improvement.
You saw that when we talked about the
different steps of the
continual improvement model.
We had to measure things, and then see
if we met those targets.
That's what SLM is all about.
We think about engage,
service level management
ensures we have ongoing engagement
with our customers and our users
through the feedback processes,
and we're continually getting information
from them for review.
Now when we think about this from a
design and transition perspective,
service level management provides
an input to the design and development
of new and changed services.
If the customer wants fast email,
that's going to be less
than five second delivery,
then we need to design a system
that can meet that requirement.
And so, this is going
to be an input to that.
When we think about obtain and build,
service level management provides
objectives for components and service
performance, as well as measurement
and reporting capabilities for the
products and services we use.
So, obtain and build is going to get a lot
of input from service level management.
And finally, deliver and support.
service level management communicates
the service performance objectives
to the operations and support teams,
so they know what they're
trying to maintain.
It's also going to collect information
and feedback from them as an input
back into the service level management
and service improvements that we're
going to do in the future.
So, this is the way it works.
service level management is all about
these measures and metrics.
Setting up the right ones, doing the
engagement with the customer, to make sure
we're measuring the right things
and seeing if we're going
to meet those measurements.