- In this section of the course,
we're going to cover the
general management practices.
This is the first of three
categories of ITIL practices.
Inside this category,
we're going to cover 14
of the 34 ITIL practices.
First, we're going to talk
about continual improvement,
and this is one that you
have to know in-depth, then,
we're going to talk about
information security management,
relationship management,
and supplier management.
These three are at the
recall level of knowledge,
so you need to memorize their definition.
And then, we're going to
cover all of the other 10
inside this category, and
these are just going to be
for a general awareness.
You don't need to know them for the exam.
This includes architecture management,
knowledge management,
measurement and reporting,
organizational change management,
portfolio management, project management,
risk management, service
financial management,
strategy management, and
workforce and talent management.
Now, all of these general
management principles
have been adopted and adapted
for service management
for more general business
management domains.
For example, project management
and portfolio management are not something
that only occur inside the IT world.
We use these across all
business organizations.
And that's why these are considered
general business management domains.
And that's why we're
going to cover them here
in the category of general
management practices.