- IT Asset Management.
In this lesson, we're going
to talk about the practice
of IT Asset Management.
And this starts the
ones that we're going to
talk about from the recall only.
So what you need to know from this lesson
is really to memorize the
purpose of IT Asset Management.
And that is to plan and
manage the full life cycle
of IT assets.
To help the organization
maximize value, control costs,
manage risks, support
decision-making about purchases,
re-use and retirement of
assets, and meet the regulatory
and contractual obligations.
But in addition to memorizing
that purpose, you also need
to memorize the term IT Asset
that was used in that purpose.
What's an IT Asset?
Well, an IT Asset is
any valuable component
that can contribute to the delivery
of a IT product or service.
Now, when we think about
IT Asset Management,
what I want you to think about is the fact
that it's like inventory.
We want to know all of
the different components
that are out inside our organization
and what they're doing for us.
Because if I know what they all are,
I can help maximize the
value, I can control the cost,
I can manage the risks, and
I can support decision-making
about future purchases.
So, if I think about it
in my company, we've got
a bunch of computers that we use.
Well, I need to keep
track of that computer
and how old it is.
So I know that, hey in three years I need
to replace that computer,
that's going to cost
x amount of dollars.
So we need to start budgeting for that.
IT Asset Management helps us do that.
It helps us plan and manage
the full life cycle of these
IT Assets, from purchase,
to use, to retirement
and then replacement.
That's the whole concept here.
And again, any asset that
is a valuable component
can be considered an IT Asset.
It's going to contribute to
the delivery of an IT service
or a product, it's part of our IT Assets.
That might mobile phones,
servers, network gear, racks,
switches, computers,
laptops, desktops, monitors,
you name it.
It's probably an IT Asset.