- Supplier Management.
The supplier management practice
is the last one you have
to remember from the
general management section.
As we talk about this,
you need to remember the definition
of the purpose of supplier management.
The purpose of supplier
management is to ensure
the organization's suppliers
and their performance
are managed appropriately to support the
provisioning of seamless,
quality products,
services, and components.
Really what this means is
that we are going to make sure
that we have a good
relationship with our suppliers,
and that way, we can
ensure that we're creating
these close, collaborative relationships
with those key suppliers
to uncover and realize
new value and reduce our risk of failure.
If I rely heavily on a certain person
to provide us a service or a supply,
we want to make sure we
have a good relationship
so we know when things
might not be working right.
If we have that, they'll be
able to come and tell us,
'Hey, you know what? We know we
promised that we were going to
have this delivered to you
by Friday, but we're running
behind and it's now going
to be until Monday.'
I'd rather them tell me that
now, so I can plan for that,
than Friday comes along, and
the thing doesn't arrive.
This is the idea with supplier management.
By having good relationships,
we can ensure we get
better products, more quality products,
and better service and supplies.
So again, remember, the purpose
of the supplier management
practice is to ensure the
organization's suppliers
and their performance
are managed appropriately
to support the provision of
seamless, quality products,
services and components.
Keep that in mind for the
exam and you'll do great
on any supplier management questions.