- The continual improvement model.
Now the continual improvement model
is a seven step methodology
that provides us
a framework of how we should
do improvement operations
within our organizations.
Now what we're going to do in this lesson
is focus on what those seven steps are
and then we're going to spend time
on each one of them individually
in their own lesson following this one.
So what is this model?
Well, it all starts out
with step number one.
What is the vision?
Then we move into step
two, where are we now?
Step three, where do we want to be?
Step four, how do we get there?
Step five, take action.
Step six, did we get there?
Step seven, how do we
keep this momentum going?
And then we restart it all again
because continual improvement
is an ongoing process that never stops.
We're going to continue
to go time and time again
until we get the best
product we ever can have.
And guess what, we're never
going to reach perfection.
There's always new features.
There's always better
ways of doing something.
And so by doing this
continual improvement,
we're constantly trying to get
better and better and better
to get to that ultimate vision,
that nirvana if you will,
but we're never quite going to reach it.
We'll talk about that
more in the next lesson
when we discuss what is the vision.
But for the exam, I wanted to
give you just this quick video
to go through these seven steps.
Why is that?
Because on the exam, you're going
to get questions about this.
They might describe one
of these seven steps
and you're going to have to pick
which of the seven steps it is.
They might say what comes next
after where do we want to be
and you're going to have
to say how do we get there.
You need to know these seven steps.
This is a memorization item for the exam.
But beyond memorizing them,
you need to understand
what these seven steps are
and that's why we're going to spend time
in the next seven lessons going through
each one individually.