- Progress Iteratively and with Feedback.
This is our third guiding principle.
Now, what this tells us is
that if we work in a time-box
iterative manner, getting feedback loops
embedded into this process,
it's going to allow us to
have greater flexibility,
much faster responses
to our current customer
and business needs, as well
as the ability to discover
and respond to failures earlier
and improve our overall quality.
This is all about doing things in an
agile method of working.
When we go into project
management, there's two basic ways
we can build something.
We can do it is a waterfall
method which is more like
a standard Sprint 2 methodology.
Or we can do it in an agile
way of working which is more
like a Sprint 2 agile methodology.
Now, with a waterfall I want to
figure out the entire thing I
need, break it down into smaller
chunks and then build each
of those chunks towards that final vision.
But nobody gets to use the
thing until it's all done.
For example, if I was going
to build a house for you,
that's the way I would do it.
I would figure out where
the house is going to go,
we would say okay, there
are lots of different things
that need to happen before
I can give you that house,
and before you can move in.
I need to make sure the
basement has been poured.
walls has been put up.
The electrical has been installed.
The plumbing has been installed.
The dry wall, the
painting, all the fixtures.
Everything has to be ready
and then you can move in.
So, it might take me 12
months or 18 months before
the house is ready to be delivered to you.
Now, on the other hand, if
I did things in an agile
way of working, maybe I'll
be able to make one room
of the house first and you can move in
and live in that room.
And then we can start building the rest
of the house around you.
That will be the way we
can one room at a time
and keep giving you one room
then two rooms and three rooms
and four rooms and eventually
you'll have the whole house.
That doesn't work very well on a house
but in services and IT, you
can do that often times.
So when you're building a
service in IT you want to think
about that and how you can progress
iteratively with feedback.
This means we're going
to organize the work into
smaller manageable sections.
If I'm going to make an
iPhone app fore instance,
it may have just one
function when I release it
and then I'll add the second function,
and then the third function.
I can do this sequentially
or simultaneously.
I can make this in manageable
smaller chunk of code
and as I put something out,
I can get feedback from my audience
that hey, "We don't like
this, we want more of this."
And that gives me some
tangible results to figure out
I'm I hitting the bulls eye?
Or do I need to pivot something else.
Also, it's better because
I get timely feedback.
If I put out one feature it
may have only taken me a month
or two to build.
And you can tell me, you
know, I really don't like that
feature because it needs this other thing.
Whereas if I wait an entire
year to deliver something
that had 20 features, you then look at it
and go, "No, I don't like it."
And we have another year's worth of work.
So the idea here is to use smaller pieces
and build upon them for
future improvements.
Now, this feedback loop
is critical inside of this
because as I'm delivering
these small modular chunks,
I'm getting feedback from my end users
or from my stakeholders.
And this feedback loop is a
situation where part of this
output is now activity that's
going to be used for a new input.
So as I gave you a piece
of software you can say,
I like the software but
the fact that it has
a blue icon is bad.
I wanted it to have a red icon.
That now becomes input that goes back into
the second version that's
going to come with a red icon.
A good example of this is
feedback surveys that you get
from customer support.
If I'm running a help
desk or a service desk,
after I'm done with the call
I'm going to get feedback
from the user I helped that says,
were you satisfied or not?
And if not, why not?
I can then use that to build
into the process other things
that are going to help
improve those scores.
Now because we're doing
things in iteratively manner
and we're doing things
in these smaller chunks
and getting that feedback,
we're going to be able
to have these initiatives
and all the components that make it up
broken down into these smaller chunks.
And these are going to be
continually reevaluated
to reflect changes in our circumstances.
Maybe the requirements
are going to change.
Maybe the market place has shifted.
If you went back five or 10
years the Deal of the Day Sites
like Groupon were huge.
Everyone was making them.
And so, everyone would just
put them out really quick
and see what happened.
But if you tried to make the
Deal of the Day Sites today,
you're probably not going
to do very well with it.
So instead if you put that out
and saw there was no market
place intake of it, nobody
wanted that service.
You could say, "Mm-mm,
what out if this can I use
"and make into my next service?"
Now, because we are trying
to progress iteratively,
we're going to have all
these things broken down into
smaller chunks of code
like we've talked about.
So this might be smaller systems
or processes or services.
Now we're going to take
our initiative and break it
down into these different components.
And throughout each of these
iterations as we're building
them we're going to be getting feedback.
Now as we get that feedback,
we're going to continually
reevaluate what we've put out
and based on that feedback
we're going to reflect changes into
our next version of products.
Now as we're seeking out
on that feedback we need
to make sure we don't just
collect and do nothing with it.
We actually want to use that feedback.
We want to use it before,
during and after building each
of these iterations of the service.
And so as we keep using
these feedback loops between
all these participants,
it helps us understand
where the work is coming from,
where the output from
the service are going,
and how it affects the ultimate consumer,
and their affected outputs.
By understanding all of that
we're getting more feedback
which allows us to build better.
This is all about doing
things in an agile way
because it's quicker to market.
So, some of the key takeaways I want you
to have from this lesson on
Progressing Iteratively and with Feedback
is that as you're going through
you're going to do things
by comprehending the whole
but doing small pieces
towards that end goal.
So if I think about
this again like a house,
I need to think about what
the whole house will look like
but right now I'm focused
into building one room, right?
And that will be the way
we can build one room
and then the second room
and then the third room.
If you do that in a
software or a service realm,
we're building these components,
putting them together
to give us the complete service.
When we think about this, also
remember that your ecosystem
is constantly changing so
feedback becomes essential.
As I'm putting something to
the market I may find half of
my consumers they don't
care about that feature,
they don't care about that service.
And so we need to pivot
and so something different.
The other thing is I want
you to remember that first
does not mean incomplete.
Even though I'm only giving
you one chunk or one feature,
that feature should be complete.
And it can be do that all
function that it needs to
in and of itself.
But then the next iteration
might be able to add
a second feature or a third feature.
That doesn't mean that one
feature was incomplete,
it was a complete and ready
product for version one.
And now version two has two functions.
And version three has three function
and you keep adding as you go.
Remember, the whole concept
here is that we can get things
out to market faster, we can get feedback
and then incorporate that
into our future versions.