- Back when you attended
school as a child,
you may have learned about
the industrial revolution.
The first industrial
revolution occurred in the
18th and 19th centuries, all
across Europe and America.
During this period, humanity moved from
an agrarian-based rural society of farmers
into an urbanized, industrial area,
that later developed into
some of our country's largest cities.
This movement was brought
about by the development
of mechanization in the form
of iron and textile industries,
as well a the power of the steam engine
for our transportation needs.
The industrial revolution was
only the first one though,
by the end of the 19th century,
and continuing until World War I,
or the Great War, as it's known in Europe,
humanity moved into the
second industrial revolution.
During this time, our industries expanded
to include steel, oil, electricity,
and electrically-powered equipment to aid
in the mass production of goods.
During this time period,
cars were developed
with their internal combustion engines,
that made transportation even
more convenient and efficient.
At the same time, the light bulb
began to replace candlelight,
allowing us to work longer into the night.
And of course, communication
across great distances,
became possible through
the use of our telephones.
Life was better than it
had ever been before,
but humanity wasn't done
exploring and inventing yet.
Technology continued to expand in its use,
but there weren't any
real major breakthroughs
until the end of the 20th century.
It was around 1980 and technology
had jumped to yet another level.
This was way beyond what existed in the
second industrial revolution.
It was at this time that the
third industrial revolution,
known as the digital
revolution, truly began.
With the advancement of analog
and digital electronics,
humanity began to utilize
life-changing technologies
on a daily basis, including
the personal computer,
the internet, and the entire spectrum
of information and
communication technologies.
Many of these things are the things
you're responsible for
within your organization,
and it was during this
third industrial revolution
that ITIL was first created.
ITIL was first developed as a series of
best practices and guidance
on how to run an information
technology organization.
In fact, ITIL, as it was
originally developed,
was an acronym that stood for
Information Technology
Infrastructure Library.
ITIL began in the 1980s
as a way for organizations
to create processes and procedures
to better run their IT systems.
Throughout the last three decades,
ITIL became the defacto standard
around the world for
IT service management.
As we moved as a society from the
first industrial
revolution, to the second,
and then onto the third,
we're now at a crossroads again.
Now, we're moving into the
fourth industrial revolution,
and it is happening right now.
The fourth industrial revolution is marked
by the creation of cyber-physical systems,
where a fusion of technologies
has blurred the lines
between physical and digital realms.
This includes the use of technologies like
robotics, nanotechnology,
artificial intelligence,
the internet of things,
autonomous cars, and so much more.
This explosive growth in technology
in the early 21st century has transformed
our world economies, as well as ourselves.
So, you may be wondering right now,
'Why are we spending time
talking about the history
of various industrial
revolutions that occurred
over the past few hundred years?'
Well, it's to make this point:
ITIL 4 is not considered ITIL version 4,
instead it's ITIL for the
fourth industrial revolution.
ITIL is no longer considered an acronym.
ITIL is a brand name.
It simply means ITIL, it doesn't mean
Information Technology
Infrastructure Library anymore,
because ITIL is more
than just infrastructure.
This is a major shift in
the way ITIL approaches
the challenges of IT service management
based on this as well.