- So now that we've
covered all four dimensions
and the external factors
throughout this section,
I want to put it all together
in a real world example,
to really drive the point home
of how these all work together.
So we talked about our four dimensions,
organizations and people,
information and technology,
partners and suppliers,
and value streams and processes.
As well as those six external
factors that all are focused
in how we look at our
products and services.
To co create value with our consumers.
Well let's consider the
process of incident management.
How are we going to deal
with incident management
when something happens to
our service or our product?
Well, if we look at it
through the organizations
and people lens or that dimension,
we're going to ask the question of
how we're going to organize our teams?
Is this something the service
desk is going to handle?
Are we going to have different tiers?
Like Tier 1, Tier 2, Tier 3 support?
Or are we going to have
a flat organization?
These are all things
we have to figure out.
How're we going to organize
our communications?
How is that Tier 1
representative going to transfer
the information they collected
to the Tier 2 representative
if you're going to use a tiered
or vertical organization?
How're you going to escalate
it up to the next level?
At which trip points?
How about the people you need?
How're you going to decide how
many people you need to run
the incident management
for a particular service?
What competencies do they need?
Is this service going to
be something that uses AWS,
do you need Amazon Web
Service certified people?
Or is this going to be something
that we're goin to use local services?
How about the qualifications?
How about the way they're
going to interact?
How are you going to motivate the people?
How are you goin to hire the right people?
How are you goin to keep the right people?
How are you goin to pay them?
And how are you going to make
sure that they're capable
of doing the incident management
that you want them to do?
All of these are things you
have to think about from
the organizations and people lens
or perspective or dimension.
Now when I look at from the
information and technology side,
let's think about it from
the process stand point.
How am I going to register the incident?
Am I writing it down on a piece of paper?
Am I putting it in a internet portal?
Am I using a certain piece of software
or hardware to do that?
How about the relationship
between incidents.
How do I know that this
incident with this printer,
that happened today,
is related or not related to the one
that happened three weeks ago?
Well maybe I have some kind of technology
or information management
software that does that for me.
That contract the
incidents in the problems.
Or the incidents and the
particular configuration item,
meaning that printer.
Or the incidents and the different users
who were being affected.
Maybe when we get all of these calls
and we put them together,
we find that all of the users affected,
always added Building 1
and not in Building 2.
So maybe it's a problems with Building 1.
And so we can look into that, right?
How about incident management
tools for information flow.
How're we going to do work flow?
How're we going to use knowledge bases?
How about diagnostic tools.
How're we going to detect these events,
and process these events?
How're we going to
communicate with each other?
organize and share data?
All of this is stuff that goes under
that information part of the information
and technology portion of this dimension.
Then we get to our third dimension.
And we start looking at our
partners and suppliers, right?
Because nobody is self sufficient,
we talked about this before.
Maybe this printer is broken
because it ran out of supplies,
there's no more paper,
there's no more toner, right?
So those are things that
we have to think about.
We think about partners and suppliers,
we have to think about the external teams
that are going to contribute
to the success of our service.
Maybe in this case, we
have outsourced completely
the management of the printers,
and that company isn't doing a good job.
And so we need to evaluate their contract.
If we outsource a service,
how're we going to
escalate incidents to them
once something is broken?
Or maybe we escalate top tier service.
So we handle minor incidents in house,
but we're going to outsource
those major incidents
and so we have to escalate it to them.
How do we get information back from them
when they fix something, right?
Two way street between
partners and suppliers and us.
All of this is things
we have to think about
and we start considering
how're we going to operate
with our partners and suppliers, right?
And then we have our final
dimension to look at.
Which is going to be our value
streams and our processes.
Maybe we look at that value stream
and see that this whole
process of printing,
actually has issues with it,
because it's not optimized properly.
There's too much waste in it.
Maybe we've looked at it
and we said " Y'know what,
we can take out step number two
and just make it step
one and three and four
and that will solve the problem."
All of those things are things
that we would've evaluate
as we look at it from the four dimensions.
And then finally, we
might want to look at it
from those external perspectives.
One of those,
the E,
stood for environmental.
Maybe we have somebody
who doesn't like the fact
that we're printing and
wasting a bunch of trees
by printing out a lot of stuff.
And so somebody might've
jammed the printer on purpose
to break it, because they are
an environmentalist, right?
That's kind of crazy, but
you kind of get the idea
of what I'm talking about.
We can start thinking about
all of these four dimensions
and these external factors and
how they're going to effect
a simple service,
something like printing or something like
an incident management.
And as we look at this,
that's how all of this
ends up tying together.
And that's the whole idea of
using these four dimensions.
When you're thinking about your processes,
your people, your
organization, your technology,
your information, all of that stuff,
so you can make sure that
your products and services
are delivering the value
that they are suppose to.