- As I stated in the last
section of this course,
ITIL is a framework for
information technology
service management, known as ITSM.
According to ITIL Four,
service management is defined
as a set of specialized
organizational capabilities
for enabling value to customers
in the form of services.
Whenever we speak about
organizational capability,
such as in this definition
of service management,
this is referring to an organization
having both the capacity and the ability,
to perform the functions required.
Service management, whether
you're performing it
using ITIL Four as it's framework,
or another ITSM framework,
is focused on how to best create value
within an organization,
to provide the desired
benefits to your consumers.
Now, to do that, an organization
must organize it's people
to best support the
organization's activities,
practices and processes.
These activities, practices and processes,
are the engine that drive the creation
of the organization's
products and their services.
But, none of these activities,
practices and processes,
could be done in isolation.
Instead, we have to consider
the service relationships
that are built, created and nurtured
throughout the service management process.
In this section of the course,
we're going to discuss
these generalized concepts
of service management, that
apply to both ITIL Four
and other frameworks.
Then, we're going to spend a bit of time
going over the concepts of outcomes,
risks, utility and warranty,
to help build a solid foundation,
before we move in to the
specific ITIL Four concepts,
that are covered throughout
the rest of this course.
Now remember, even though
the concepts in this section
are generalized for IT service management,
it doesn't mean they won't
be on the ITIL Four exam.
In fact, we're going to cover
all three parts of Learning Objective One,
in this section of the course.
This includes Learning
Objective one point one,
which states that you're
going to have to be able to
recall the definition of
service, utility, warranty,
customer, user, service
management and sponsor.
You can also expect to get two questions
from this learning objective,
on your certification exam.
Under Learning Objective one point two,
you're going to be required
to describe the concepts of
cost, value, organization, outcome,
risk, utility and warranty.
On your exam, two questions will come from
this particular learning
objective as well.
Finally, we're going to cover
Learning Objective one point three,
which requires you to be able
to describe the key concepts
of service relationships,
including service offerings,
service relationship management,
service provision, and
service consumption.
On the certification exam,
you can expect to receive
one question from this
particular learning objective.
So let's get started learning
about service management
and it's key concepts.