- The Release Management practice.
This is another one that you
have to recall the purpose of.
So, what is that purpose?
Well, the purpose of
Release Management practice
is to make new and changed services
and features available for use.
Basically, it's going to
provide us some set of processes
that we're going to have to go through
to get the thing from the
design all the way out
until it's finally live
in the environment.
Generally, this will involve
having a release plan,
will have the newer
changed infrastructure,
newer changed software,
and newer changed documentation
and training given to us
and then we'll be able to put it into
the deployment and release process.
And this is where we're going to review it
and eventually release it
so that it can be deployed
into the environment.
That's the whole purpose
of release management.
We don't want things to just get put out
into the environment
without us knowing about it.
We want to properly transition them
and take them from design,
through testing and transition,
out and then be released
into the operation environment,
and make sure that the service
desk is ready to support it
inside deliver and support.