- Optimize and automate,
this is our 7th and final
guiding principal and we
have this one as our 7th one,
because it is really one of
the ones you want to do last,
cuz you're going to
implement a lot of the other
guiding principals and
then optimize and automate.
But, what is optimize mean?
Well, it means to make
something as effective
and useful as it makes sense to do.
Before an activity can
be effectively automated,
you first want to make
sure you're optimizing it
to whatever degree is
possible and reasonable.
By doing this, you're going
to make sure that you're
not just doing things
automatically and quicker,
but you're doing them the
best way and then you can
make them automated and quicker.
And so to do this we really
want to understand and
agree to the context
before the optimization,
by figuring out what that process is,
by keeping it simple
using our 6th principle.
We then can go through and
assess the current state
to understand where it can be improved.
That sounds familiar, that
was one of our earlier
guiding principles right,
starting where you are.
And then we want to focus
on simplification, again,
keeping it simple, and get
a value that's involved to
agree to our future state.
That might be something
like focusing on value
then we want to insure
that we optimize it for the
appropriate level of stakeholder
engagement and commitment.
So that goes back to
collaborating with other people.
Then once we do that, we're
going to execute all of those
improvements in an iterative
way, progressing iteratively,
using metrics and other
feedback to check our progress
and stay on track to adjust as needed.
And once all of that's done,
we're going to continually
monitor it to identify any opportunities
to improve our work methods.
You can see that by optimizing
things, we really are pulling
in areas from all of the
other guiding principles.
Now, once we've optimized it
and we have the best process
in the least amount of steps
that's ready to be automated,
we're going to move into automation.
Now, automation is the use of
technology to perform a step
or series of steps
correctly and consistently
with limited or no human intervention.
By automating, we can automate
frequent and repetitive tasks
to help our organizations
scale up and free up those
human resources to be used for
more complex decision making.
In the last lesson I was talking about the
incident management desk.
You may automate the
first three categories
or something like password resets.
That frees up people to be
able to do more of the harder
complex decision making and
problems solving techniques.
In my company we did this
exact same thing with our
voucher for filming system.
At first, it was a manual method.
You would order a voucher,
I would then order it from
the company, I would turn
around take that, package it up
in an email and send it back to you.
Over time, we started getting
a lot of people who were
buying vouchers, and so it
was eating up a lot of my time
as a person, and then it
started eating up a lot of
my assistants time when
she started doing it.
And so what we ended up doing was
we ended up automating that system.
Now when you go to our
website and you buy a voucher,
there is no human involvement.
Its going to go through, pull
the next available voucher
for our inventory, put it in an email,
give you the directions,
email it back to you,
and all of that happens in a
matter of seconds or minutes.
The simplest form of automation
is always going to involve
standardizing and streamlining
all of these manual tasks
to allow decisions to
be made automatically.
In our case, that's exactly what happened.
The all the decision it
needs to do is figure out did
you order an idle 4
voucher, an idle 3 voucher,
a prince 2 voucher.
Based on that it pulls the
right one and sends it back
to you, its all automated.
That's the beauty of it, because
now I was able to free up
those powers of human labor to go do other
more important things like
make study guides for you,
or make new slides, or new
videos, or do video editing,
or answer student questions.
All of that is being able to be done,
because we automated simple process.
So when you think about this,
how are you going to apply this principle.
Well first you're going
to simplify and optimize
before you ever automate.
You don't want to take
something that has 1000 steps
and automate it, because
now its just doing that
bad process faster.
That's still costing you time,
and its still costing you money.
Instead, we want to take that process,
get it down to the simplest
steps, and then automate it.
Because that's going to
save you the most time
and the most money.
Next, I also want you to look for
anything that's done
manually and repetitively.
If you for instance get an email every day
for an email newsletter and
you always have to take it
and drag it to your trash can.
That takes up maybe 2 or
3 seconds of your time,
but you could apply an
automated filter that
any time that email comes in
it automatically moves
it to your trash can
or you can go and unsubscribe right.
But you get the idea,
anything that you see
yourself doing day in and day out,
there's probably a computer
program that can be done to
optimize it and automate it
so you don't have to do it.
Second, I want you to
always define your metrics.
What does good look like?
If were talking about my
voucher for filming system,
our metric is that you're going
to get your voucher within
5 minutes of ordering, and
that's pretty generous,
usually it takes about 60 seconds.
Again, define your metrics
so you can then look
at your systems and see
if they've been optimized
and automated properly to
meet the metrics you have.
Also, you want to make
sure you're using the other
guiding principles when
you apply this one.
As I said, we're going to use a
lot of these other principles.
We're going to think
and work holistically,
cuz we look at the whole
system as a whole we
can figure out where the
optimizations can best be taken.
We're also going to look
at starting where you are,
because we need to know where we are
to figure out how we can
get to the next level.
We also want to keep it
simple and practical,
because we want to eliminate
steps that aren't needed
or aren't practical.
Then, we want to build on that
by progressing iteratively
and with feedback, and
finally we always have a focus
on value, we always want to
make sure that what we're
doing is for a reason.
Were doing this process to give
more value to our consumers,
or to our organization or to both.
So that was our 7 guiding
principals, and they all get
kind of get summed up here at the end with
Optimize and Automate,
because we really do
dig into all those principles as
we work through optimizing
and automating our systems.