- Information Security Management
Our next general management practice is
Information Security Management.
For the exam, you simply need
to recall the definition of
the Information Security
Management practice,
and that definition,
is that the Information
Security Management practice
is there to protect the information needed
by the organization to
conduct its business.
What is Information Security Management
really all about then?
Well, its all about understanding
and managing risks to
your Confidentiality,
Integrity, Availability,
Authentication and Non-repudiation of your
information systems.
If you think about it this way,
Information Security is
all about cyber security.
We want to prevent things
like data breaches,
and hackers from attacking us.
When we think about
confidentiality, we want to
make sure our data remains
confidential, which means
its safe from prying eyes.
We do this usually by encrypting our data,
and that way, somebody can't go in,
steal it, and look at it.
When we talk about integrity of our data,
we're really focused
on making sure the data
doesn't change, either
in transit, in use or
when its being stored.
To do this, we usually do
a hashing function against
the information,
and that gives us a
digital fingerprint so we
can know whether a file has been changed
by a malicious attacker.
When we talk about availability,
we're thinking about
things like making sure
that a customer can get
access to the data when
and where they need it.
So, if I had a website that
had great confidentiality
and great integrity, but
you could never access it,
well, then it has horrible
availability and it means
that service is going to fail.
So availability is really important.
The way that we get good
availability is by making
sure we have redundant systems,
and highly available systems,
such as ones that have
multiple connections to the outside world,
so we might have 2 internet connections,
we might have 2 sets of switches,
and 2 sets of servers, so if 1 goes down,
the other one can carry the load.
The next one we're going to
talk about is authentication,
and authentication is
concerned with making sure that
you are who you say you
are, when you're requesting
access to the information.
The most common form of authentication is
a username and password, but there's lots
of other ways to do authentication.
You might use a biometric
thumbprint, like I do
on my iPhone when I login,
or, my wife has an iPhone
X, she uses her face,
which again is a biometric method.
You might have a system where
when you login with your
username and password, it emails
back a code to your email,
that you then have to access
and then put that code in
to access the system.
That's a form of 2 factor authentication.
Other systems like this might send you
a text message code,
and so that way you can
verify you have your
phone, something you have,
and you know your username and
password, something you know.
Again, this is the whole
idea of authentication.
Proving you are who you say you are.
And that brings us to our
last one, Non-repudiation
With Non-repudiation,
we're trying to make sure
that you are who you say you are,
and you can't say you
didn't do what you did.
Non-repudiation is really
focused on the fact of
if you took an action
on a website, you have
no way to say you didn't do it.
Now, there's lots of ways
to ensure Non-repudiation,
and most of them involve
having some form of proper
authentication.
For example, if I wanted
to have Non-repudiation
of an email I sent you, I can
digitally sign it with my private key,
and if I do that, it
means that nobody else
could've signed it with that private key,
because I'm the only one who has it,
and that means you know
I actually sent it.
So even if I said, "I
didn't send that email.",
you can go "Yeah you did,
I have proof right here."
That's the concept of Non-repudiation.
Now again, for the ITIL 4 exam, you only
need to know the purpose of
Information Security Management.
Again, that purpose is to
protect the information
needed by the organization
to conduct its business.
This is something you
want to make sure you have
down in your notes,
and you're memorizing before the exam.