- Our seventh and final
step is to determine
how do we keep the momentum going?
We probably just spent a lot of time,
a lot of money, and a lot of working hours
trying to improve something
in the organization.
If we met the goal, we don't
want to necessarily stop, though,
but we want to keep improving, right?
'Cause we always want to get better.
And, if we didn't meet our goal,
then we need to go back
an readjust and figure out
how we can improve to meet our goals.
If this happened, we might
return to an earlier step,
create a new goal, or create
a new plan and then try again.
But let's think positively
for a few minutes here.
Let's assume that we met
our goals that we set out
in step three with our
key performance indicators
and our critical success factors.
Things are going great.
We improved, and everyone is happy.
Well, if we don't do something,
oftentimes people are going to revert
to their old ways of doing business.
For example, maybe our customer
service satisfaction scores
weren't very good, and so we set forth
on an improvement initiative,
and we raised the scores
by 50% and things are going really well.
So we decide to shift our focus
to a new initiative, and now, guess what?
Since nobody's closely monitoring
the customer support metrics anymore,
the call center agents
stop trying as hard,
and the satisfaction scores
start going down again.
Now, this is the opposite of what we want.
Or maybe, whenever the
initiative that you did
worked so well within one department
we decided we want to
keep the momentum going
by instituting that change
across multiple departments
by issuing a new company policy.
Either way, we want to make sure
the improvement gains keep going forward
and we keep up with the
progress we're making.
This is what step seven is all about.
It's about creating
and implementing a plan
to keep that positive
momentum moving forward
and keeping us to get more
improvements down the road.
And then you're going
to notice in the diagram
that we return to the top
of the model once more.
Why is this?
Well, this is because we
always want to be improving.
This is our goal, constant
and continual improvement.
This model is cyclical in nature.
We continue to go round
and round and round again,
gaining more efficiencies,
more effectiveness,
and more value as we go along.
That's the whole goal here inside
the continual improvement model.
We want to keep improving always.