- Service Catalog Management.
This is another one that you don't need
to know for the foundation level,
but we're going to cover it briefly here.
The practice of providing a single source
of consistent information
on all of your services
and all of your service offerings
and insuring that's available
to the relevant audience,
is what's known as Service
Catalog Management.
So, for example, if
you come to my website,
you can see our service catalog.
You're a relevant audience.
You're going to see all of
the different courses we have
and the different types
of practice exams and labs
and the different types of video courses.
All of that is shown as
part of our service catalog
and you can make a choice based on that,
of which offerings you want to use
and which ones are relevant for you.
Now, if I was running a
large IT organization,
I would have a lot of different
things in my service catalog
I might have a desk top component,
I might have a laptop component,
I might have the fact that
I need a mobile component
like a smart phone.
You could go into the
service catalog and say,
"I need one iPhone that gives
me X amount of band width
and X amount of service
so I can do these things."
You can order that from
the Service Catalog
based on that particular service offering.
As you go and look at any
IT company you deal with,
I want you to look at
what offerings they have.
You're going to see that this
Service Catalog Management
is what's at the heart of it.
This is where we're going to say,
we're bringing on a
new product next month.
We'll list it in the catalog
now, so you know it's coming
or we're going to retire
this product next month.
We're going to list that now
that this is ending soon.
So, if you want to order
it, you better get it now
because it's going away in three months.
This is the idea here when you talk about
Service Catalog Management.
Telling people what is coming,
what is being taken away
and what is currently available.