- The third value chain activity
inside the center of the value chain
is deliver and support.
This is where a lot of us work
if we work in the IT world.
If you happen to work in IT support,
you probably work inside
of deliver and support.
The purpose of deliver and
support as a value chain activity
is to ensure that the services
are delivered and supported
according to the agreed specifications
and stakeholder expectations.
I like to think about
this as service operation.
We want to make sure the end user
is getting the service and
support that they need.
And that's why we call
it deliver and support.
I am going to deliver
some sort of capability
and support that end user.
When you're watching one of my videos,
you're using the deliver
and support process.
We are delivering that video to you,
and if you have a problem, we support you.
That's part of that particular service.
Now, as we design the next video,
that would go back to
design and transition.
As we're trying to film
and edit that next video,
that's obtain and build.
But once we have it ready and
you're ready to consume it,
that becomes deliver and support.
And the same thing works
inside our IT services.
If I'm building a new email server,
that's an obtain build.
Once it's out and you're
using that email server,
we're now in deliver and support.
So, what are some of the inputs
inside of deliver and support?
The first one is any new and
changed products and services
that are provided by
design and transition.
Remember, obtain build
is going to build it,
pass it back to transition,
and then transition is going to make sure
it gets smoothly put into the marketplace,
so that deliver and support
can then run it from there.
We're also going to have our
contracts and our agreements
with external and internal
suppliers and partners
provided to us from engage.
As engage does all the
external engagements,
we're then going to use those contracts
to get the things we need
inside of deliver and support.
We also are going to
get service components
provided to us by obtain and build.
As they built that new email server,
it's going to be
transitioned and eventually
we are going to get it here
in deliver and support.
Then we're going to get things
like improvement initiatives
and plans that are going to come out
of the improve process or
a value chain activity.
We're also going to get
improvement status reports
from the improve value chain activity.
We're going to get user
support tasks from engage,
because any time we're talking to a user,
that's an engagement function.
And we're also going to be looking at
the knowledge and information.
The knowledge and information
about our new and changed
service components and services
from design and transition
or obtain and build,
or the knowledge and information
about third-party service components
from our engage partnerships.
All of that is the way
we're going to get things
into this value chain activity.
Now, on the other side, we're
going to output a lot of things.
And we're going to output things
like the services that we're delivering
to our customers and users.
This is the thing that
you're actually using.
When you go to the website,
you're in the deliver and support
because you're taking
advantage of the delivery.
You're also going to get
the outputs of information
on the completion of user
support tasks for engage.
So if you have a problem and
you submitted a support ticket,
at some point, you're going to
get a result coming back to you
through the engage process
that says your ticket has been solved,
and here was the resolution.
Another thing you're going to get
is product and service
performance information
that comes out of engage and improve
as those value chain activities.
All of this needs to get
back out to that end user.
We're also going to output things
like improvement opportunities.
And as we figure out,
hey the way we're delivering
our videos isn't the best,
maybe we should do it this other way,
we would give that
improvement recommendation
and opportunity over to improve,
which then can consolidate
that, prioritize that,
and figure out how we're
going to better ourself
for the long term.
When we talk about improvements
for contracts and agreement requirements,
that's going to go into the
engage value chain activity.
And, if we look at all the
different change requests,
any of those that come in as
part of delivery and support,
we're going to output those
over to obtain and build,
so that they can obtain or build the thing
and change it to the way we need.
All of this are things, as you can see,
that interlock together.
They're all very much going
in and out all of the time.
And the last output we have
for the deliver and support activity,
is the service performance information.
We're going to collect a lot of
information about our services.
Maybe we're running servers
and we're finding out
how much space is left on a share drive,
or the uptime, or the
availability, or the capacity,
or the throughput.
All of that is service
performance information.
And as we collect all of that,
we're going to process
it and then pass it back
over to the design and transition phase.
Why would we give it to
design and transition?
Well, because they're constantly looking
at what capacity you have
and do you need more?
For example, if we had
one single web server
and we started seeing that the trend was
that we were using 80 or
90 or 95 percent capacity,
we want to make sure we're designing
version two of that web server,
with additional capacity.
Maybe that's moving to
a cloud architecture,
maybe that's moving to a
multi site homed environment,
or using a content distribution network.
Whatever that is, it has to be designed.
And so by feeding this service
performance information
back to design and transition,
they can help us design
what the next version
of our service is going to look like.