- Knowledge Management.
This is another one that is not covered
by the ITIL 4 exam, but it's
one that we're going to cover
briefly to give you a general awareness.
Knowledge management
is focused on providing
and understanding of all
of the different elements
that make up an organization
and how those elements
relate to one another.
So when I think about
knowledge management,
I'm thinking about
collecting all of the data
and everything that's
inside the organization.
In fact, when we talk
about knowledge management,
there are four things that we look at.
We have the baseline of data,
and then built from
data, we get information.
When we get more information,
we can consolidate
it together in context to get knowledge,
and then from knowledge,
we can get to the top thing
we want, which is wisdom, where
we can make good decisions.
Now, let me give you a
good example of this.
Let me give you a piece of data, 90.
By itself, 90 doesn't
mean much to you, does it?
But if I give you that data
with a little bit of context,
it can become information.
For example, I could say 90 degrees.
Now, you know that it's a temperature.
And maybe I told you that
it's 90 degrees outside.
Now you know it's the weather temperature
for the outside area we're in.
Now if I take that
information and I combine it
with some other information,
I might be able to get
knowledge out of this.
90 degrees is a hot temperature outside.
I may decide now that
I want to wear shorts
and a t-shirt instead of
long pants and a jacket
because 90 degrees is pretty hot.
Now, if I take a bunch
of knowledge together,
I can combine it to get
wisdom, and this will allow me
to make forward looking decisions.
For example, because
it's 90 degrees outside,
there may become a larger number of users
who decide to skip work
today and go to the beach.
Knowing that we're a company who provides
wireless service around
the beaches as well,
we better be prepared to increase
the available bandwidth and be prepared
for additional phone
calls from mobile users
because they're going to
be out on their phones
instead of on their desktops today.
You can see how we could
take this information from
data into information,
information into knowledge,
and knowledge into wisdom.
Knowledge management is a huge field.
In fact, there are entire
people whose full time job it is
to figure out how we're going to take data
and turn it into information,
information into knowledge,
and knowledge into wisdom.