- We've come a long way
throughout this course,
and in this lesson, I want
to put it all together.
We started out talking about our
four dimensions of service management,
which include organizations and people,
information and technology,
partners and suppliers,
and the value stream and processes.
Then, we talked about the
ITIL service value system.
This included our opportunity
and demands as our input,
and those are shaped by
our service value chain,
our governance, our practices,
our guiding principles,
and our continual improvement,
and out the other side, we got value.
Now, we also dug into the
service value chain itself,
as part of the service value system.
We explored the different
parts of it, like engage, plan,
improve, design and
transition, obtain and build,
deliver and support, and
our products and services.
And then, we spent the last
three sections of the course
looking at the 34 different
practices across ITIL 4.
But now, it's time for us
to put it all together.
So let's walk through
a real-world scenario
with an incident that
needs to be resolved,
and see how everything
we talked about so far
will be integrated together
to create the desired value.
Now, let's pretend we work
for a large logistics company,
something like Walmart or
Amazon, and we're part of
their IT service management
organization within the company.
They have a warehouse
that uses a wifi network
in order to allow the forklift driver
to receive instructions
on his mobile device
that tells him which aisle
and which rack the product is
that he needs to go pick up.
Unfortunately, the wireless
access point that supports
the wifi in this area of the warehouse
isn't working so well, and
so the driver's mobile device
can't get the information that he needs.
Now, this has a significant
impact on our business
because whenever that
forklift driver can't receive
the instructions quickly
enough, there's a risk
that a tight business
deadline might be missed.
After all, some companies like Amazon
rely on their super-fast shipping
as a core function of
their business model.
Now, while this may seem like
a relatively straightforward incident,
it can't be resolved simply
by following the steps
of a predetermined incident
management procedure.
Instead, there's a lot of interconnections
among the practices and the activities
for this wireless network to get fixed
and returned to normal operations.
So let's get started with the
service value system first.
First, we're going to see
that we have a demand,
and in this case, the warehouse manager
and the forklift driver
discovered the wifi coverage
isn't working properly
in a certain portion
of the warehouse.
This means the forklift
driver needs to drive
back to the manager's office
in between each pickup,
so he can find out the
location of his next product
within the warehouse.
This is causing delays,
and that could cause delivery
deadlines to be missed.
This is an incident.
From this demand, we now
move to the engage activity,
where the warehouse manager
is going to call up the service desk.
The service desk agent
listens to the issue
that's being described
by the warehouse manager,
they log it as an incident in
the incident management system
and they categorize that
incident as a high priority.
The agent then lets the
warehouse manager know
that they're going to
escalate the issue to
the technical support
team that's responsible
for that wireless network,
and they provide him updates
every two hours until that issue is fixed.
Now, the service desk
agent escalates the ticket
for the wireless network
up to the wireless network support team.
These are the folks who have
the delivery and support
function in the value chain activity
for this wireless network.
This allows the service
desk agent to provide
the information to the
network support engineer,
and the diagnosis and
analysis of the incident
is going to begin by that engineer.
Next, the network support
engineer identifies that
the wireless access point has failed,
and she decides to replace it with a spare
from the existing spare parts inventory.
This action alone is going
to involve several practices.
First, we have the IT
asset management practice,
so that she can update the serial number
in the configuration item database.
Then, she goes through
the service configuration
management practice,
because she needs to configure this device
based on the approved
baseline, and install it.
She's also going to go through
the change control practice,
since she's going to install
a new piece of equipment
into the network, and of course,
she's going to go through
incident management,
because she's working on
resolving an incident.
Let's assume that the replacement
of this wireless access
point is considered
a standard change, so no
additional approvals are needed.
If it was a normal change, then
we would have to go through
and get approval through the
change management process,
or escalate that issue
as an emergency change.
Either way, all of this would occur
within the change control
practice, though, right?
Finally, our network engineer
replaces the access point,
verifies that it's working,
and she updates the
incident management system.
She then calls the service
desk agent, and tells her
that she believes the
incident has been resolved.
Now that the engineer
has fixed the incident,
she sits back and thinks
about what happened,
and she thinks about
any possible ways that
she could have fixed
this more efficiently.
If she thinks of any, she might
add those to the continual
improvement register as suggestions
for future improvements.
If she does this, this becomes part of
continual improvement practice
and the improve activity.
Now, the service desk
agent, on the other hand,
goes back to the engage activity
by contacting the warehouse manager,
and she tells him that
the wireless network
should be working again.
She asks the manager to verify that
the forklift driver's mobile
phone is working again,
and gets the confirmation
of this, and when she does,
she can then close that incident fully.
Now, when we look at the final block
on the service value system, that's value.
The value's being co-created by ensuring
the wireless coverage is
restored, and the forklift driver
can now perform his job
more efficiently once again,
by using that mobile device
to identify the location
of the product that he
needs to pick up and move.
About an hour later, that
warehouse manager might receive
a brief email, asking for
a user satisfaction survey.
This might ask for his
feedback on the incident
and its resolution.
This would become an engage
activity again, right?
Well, if he fills out the
survey, we can then take that
and based on the feedback
received, we can identify
trends and patterns based
on satisfaction scores
in the user's comments.
This would fall under our improve area,
and we're going to be determining
if our incident management
system and our processes
are working effectively.
So, that was a lot.
As you can see, all of this ties together,
and we enter and leave
different activities
and different practices all
throughout this single incident
and its single resolution.
It isn't a simply linear
process, but instead,
we're bounced from engage
to the deliver and support,
back to engage, over to improve,
and many other practices,
several times during this quick example.
Remember, identifying and understanding
all of these interconnections
is the key to establishing
and promoting good service management.
So when you're looking
at one of your processes,
or one of your workloads,
you need to consider
all of these things as
you're laying it out,
so you can make sure you're doing it
the most efficient and
effective way possible.