- Opportunities, demand, and value.
When we consider the service value system,
it's going to take some inputs,
which come from opportunities and demands,
do a bunch of processes, activities,
using the guiding
principles, the governance,
and continual improvement to
eventually give us an output,
which we hope is value
that we can share with our
consumers and our customers.
Now, when we look at those inputs,
the first one we have is opportunities.
Opportunities represent
options or possibilities
to add value for stakeholders
or otherwise improve the organization.
Some examples of this, is if
we're going to find new markets,
or find new customers.
We might create a new service,
or create a new product.
There's lots of different ways for us
to figure out what
those opportunities are,
and then bring those to market
so we can help add value.
For example, when I first
started teaching ITIL,
I didn't have the ability, as a partner,
to be able to sell
vouchers to my students.
And so, my students, when they
finished taking my course,
would go to PeopleCert or
they would to to Pearson View,
and they would order their voucher,
and pay for their exam directly there,
and then take the exam.
The problem with that
is that made them have
to pay full retail price.
Now, one of the things we've done,
is we've been able to
partner with PeopleCert
and partner with Axelos so
we can get those vouchers
and buy them in bulk, so
we can buy a lot of them,
and pay a much lower price,
and pass the savings on to our students.
So now our students can
come to our website,
buy those vouchers, and save
about $50 off the retail price,
because they're buying it through us.
It was a way that we were able
to give our customers more
value by offering a product.
It wasn't necessarily a service,
because it's not something
that we were doing,
we're just buying them in bulk,
and then reselling them to you,
and passing those savings on to you.
But it added value for our students,
because now they can buy
their training and their
certification exams
through us at a much cheaper rate.
That was an opportunity we
saw, and we decided to take it,
and so we built different
processes in place
and practices to make that a reality,
so you can get your vouchers that way.
Now, the other input we have is demand,
and demand is when there is need or desire
for products and services
among your internal or external consumers.
What does this look like?
Well, I get this on a
daily basis in our company.
I have students who finish an exam
and they send me an email and
say hey I passed this exam,
do you offer this new other certification?
Or I would love it if you
offered this certification.
And so they have a demand,
an external consumer,
who wants something from our company,
and they're telling us about it.
Hey, I passed ITIL and
I want to take Prince2,
do you offer that?
Well, because enough students asked us to,
we went and did a Prince2
course, and we offer that now.
So, we do take input from our students,
and that helps us shape
what products and services
we're going to do.
One of the things students
have asked a lot for,
is they want more hands on practice
in our IT certification courses,
so we're building labs
where students can login
and do actual actions instead
of just watching it on video.
Those are the kind of
things that demand has fed
and now we have put that through
our service value system,
and through our service value chain
to create products and services
that can come out the other side
and give value to our students.
Which brings us to the outcome
of the service value system,
which is the value,
that's the output, right?
The output or the outcome.
And when we look at that,
the service value system is
going to enable the creation
of many different types of value
for a wide group of stakeholders.
So, when I think about value,
and I look at it from
a service perspective,
there is a value that we,
as an organization, get.
For example, when we talk
about the exam vouchers,
well, there's a value that
we get from doing that.
By buying those all and
doing all the processing,
we do keep a little bit of money,
and we make a little bit
of profit off of that.
So there's value for my
company in doing that.
Because again, we have
to pay our employees
and we have to make some
overhead to do that.
There's also value
for our other stakeholders, our students.
Instead of paying full retail
price, you get $50 off,
and so that saves you money
and it gives you the
thing you need, right?
We're giving you value there.
We might have value from
other organizations.
I actually have some
deals with some colleges,
and when they go through and
they teach their students IDIL4
they want to be able to
buy those vouchers as well.
But they don't buy it
in the same bulk we do,
because we buy thousands
and tens of thousands
of these vouchers a year,
and so we get a much lower price.
So we actually sell those
vouchers, some of those,
to these colleges for their students
in groups of 20 or 50,
and they get a little bit of a lower price
than you as an individual student do,
because they are buying
so many of them, right?
And so, again,
we have value for a bunch of
different stakeholders here,
with the same exact product or service.
Because of the way that
service value system works,
that can happen, right?
Amazon built an entire server
farm to house their website,
and then they go, hmm,
I bet we can sell this
to other companies too, and they do.
It's called amazon web services,
and that means they can take that,
and give different value
to different stakeholders,
that's the idea.
So, we look at this service
value system from left to right.
We're looking at inputs of opportunities,
what new markets, new
customers, new services,
and new products can you have?
As well as demand,
what things do these people want to buy,
internally or externally?
And then on the output
side, we have value,
for those internal and
those external consumers,
for the business, for the organization,
for all of your customers
and all of your consumers.
That's the idea of the
service value system.
Take something in, add value,
and put it out the other side.