- Value streams.
We've talked a lot about
the different activities
inside the service value chain
and you saw where there
was a lot of overlap
and coordination where one
activity fed into another
and then it took that input and created
another output that went to
a different value chain activity.
So there's a lot of interconnections here.
Whenever we're trying to
carry out a certain task
or respond to a particular situation,
we create what's known as
a service value stream.
This service value stream
is a specific combination
of activities and practices and each one
is designed for a particular scenario.
So I might have something that
takes five steps to complete.
It might start in the engage activity
and do three steps there, and then move on
to the deliver and support activity,
where two more steps are conducted.
Now, there may be a different scenario
and a different activity when
we get it from the engage
and there's only two steps
in the engage activity.
And then it passes it over
to deliver and support,
where there's two other steps.
As you can see, we can
break these things up
in any way we want, and
we can pass information
from one to the other.
As each value stream is made
up of different combinations
of value chain activities and practices,
we're going to make sure
that we understand what
the input and the output is,
because understanding what
the input and output is,
is specific to each
particular value stream.
For the two streams I show here,
where you have stream A and stream B,
they're going to go through
a different set of processes
and steps internal to
each of those activities.
And, that's going to create
a different output based on
the input it gets.
This is the idea of how we put
all of these things together
and create all of these
different value streams,
which are basically going
to be different procedures
or processes as they take
whatever the input is,
do a bunch of things to add value,
and output value on the other side.
That's the whole idea here.
And that's why the service
value chain is so important.
It's because of all of these
interrelations that occur
as we move through the
process and add more value.