- Our next practice is project management.
Now unlike portfolio management,
where we're trying to figure out what are
the different projects
and products and services
that we should create,
project management is
focused on a single product
or service or project that
we're trying to get through.
Project management is
the practice of ensuring
that all of our organization's projects
are delivered successfully.
So, when I decided to make this course,
this course became a project.
We then went through our
PRINCE2 methodologies,
and we built the entire course based on
that project management life cycle.
As we moved it from our idea,
through the different phases,
to finally getting it completed,
and getting it out to you,
that took the project from idea
all the way through to delivery.
And if we do that properly,
and we can do it successfully,
if we're using a good
project management process.
Now why is project
management so important?
Well, let's say you need to install
a brand new network for your organization.
It's going to be hundreds of computers,
dozens of servers, lots of
racks of network equipment
and all of that kind of stuff.
Well, if you were doing
it all by yourself,
you might not need project management.
But you're probably going
to have a team of five or 10
or 50 people working for you.
And if you have a large
team, everyone needs to know
what their role is and
what pieces need to be done
and when those pieces need to be done,
at which piece of time.
Do I need to get the servers in first
or the racks in first?
Do I need to get the work stations online
before or after the servers?
All of those things are things
that are going to be handled
within project management.
They're going to figure out the timing,
the sequencing and making sure we can get
from the idea and the plan
to the final execution, successfully.
Project management is a huge field
and if you're interested
in project management,
I recommend looking into
the PRINCE2 courses,
which are focused on project management
or doing something like PMP,
which is Project Management Professional.
Depending on where you live in the world,
one of those two certifications
is going to be more popular.
Here in the United States,
PMP tends to be a little bit more popular.
If you're in Europe or Asia,
PRINCE2 seems to be more popular.
So if you want to get
into project management,
those would be my recommendation,
looking at those two courses.