- Keep it simple and practical.
This is our sixth guiding principle.
You may have heard the acronym K I S S,
or KISS, Keep it Simple Stupid.
Well, that's really what
we're talking about here.
When we're talking
about keeping it simple,
I want you to think with the end in mind.
We call this outcome-based thinking.
By starting with what the outcome is
and then back your way into
all the different steps you're
going to need to achieve,
to be able to get from the
input to the outcome you desire.
So we want to use outcome-based thinking
to produce practical solutions
which are going to
deliver valuable outcomes
while using the minimum number of steps.
Now to do this, we have to go back,
to our fifth guiding principle though,
and think of things with a holistic view
of the organization's work in mind.
If I don't understand end to end
how the organization functions,
I can't get a simple and practical process
that's going to be
working for our services.
Now when I first start creating
a process or a service,
I want to start with an
uncomplicated approach.
We can always add more to it later.
But we want to start out with
the fewest amount of steps,
because that means that's
less steps that can break,
and it's less development
that we have to put
on the left side of it to see
if it's actually going to work for us.
Now as we go through and
develop our approach,
I want you to build it for the
most common scenarios first.
You don't want to try
to produce a solution
for every single exception.
For example, let's say that you're running
the service desk at your organization.
You are running the entire
incident-management front end
for that company.
As people make a phone call in
and tell you about their problems,
you're going to see if it
matches one of three categories:
The first category might be
something like a password reset.
The second one might be that
their computer doesn't boot up.
And the third one might
be that their computer
doesn't have network access.
You might create procedures
for each of those three
most common situations.
But, not every call is going
to be one of those three.
You might have some that fall
into the fourth category,
meaning, something else.
Well, I don't want you
to produce a solution
to every single something else.
Instead, just create this fourth bucket
that says, if somebody is
calling for one of these
other things, then it goes
into the manual process.
And that's where we're
going to have a human
take control and do something about it.
There's those first three, we
might end up getting it simple
making sure it's practical,
and then automating that solution.
Now by doing this,
we can be mindful of how we're
going to complete the objectives
and the outcomes that we desire.
This is the whole benefit
of keeping it simple.
By starting it easy,
you can get quick wins,
you can ensure value,
and the simplicity
is really the ultimate sophistication.
By doing fewer things, you
can do them really well
and really fast.
And for that small amount
of things that doesn't fit
into the major three categories,
you can then focus your
team's dedicated time to those
by using skilled labor.
This is going to respect the
time of the people involved.
For example, going back
to password resets,
when I was running a large service desk
for an organization of 10 to 15,000 users,
about 90% of our phone calls was because
people needed to reset their password.
So we created an automated way to do that,
and we simplified that process.
It was better for them.
It gave them more value.
It got them back to work quicker.
And more importantly, it
freed up 90% of my labor
because they weren't
taking calls from people
trying to reset their password.
Instead, I could take those people,
and dedicate them to the other problems,
the hard problems that
needed their assistance.
So, by keeping it simple,
it makes things easier to understand,
more likely to be adopted,
and it really is the best route
to achieving those quick wins
and getting people to
adopt what you're doing.