- Service Validation and Testing.
This is our final
practice in this section.
Now again, this is not one
you need to know for the exam
but just for your general awareness.
Service validation and testing
is the practice of ensuring
that new or changed products
and services meet the
defined requirements.
Now, what does that mean?
Well, let's say I was going
to build a new website.
Before I put it out
there for public release,
I would want to make sure we went
through some sort of service validation
to make sure everything's
working properly,
and we'd go through some beta testing
to ensure we tested it in-house,
we brought in some external testers,
and it was doing everything
the way that we need it to.
That's the idea in service
validation and testing.
Before you go and transition
this into the live environment,
you want to make sure everything
is operating properly,
and then, once you've transferred over
to the live environment,
you go back and validate it
to make sure it's still operating
the way you designed it.
That's all service validation
and testing really comes down to.
It's making sure you're testing things
before you release them
and after you release them
to make sure they're operating
the way you designed them.