- Service Continuity Management.
Again, this isn't on the exam,
but it's a good one to know.
The purpose of Service
Continuity Management
is to ensure that the
availability and performance
of a service is maintained
at a sufficient level
in the event of a disaster.
Now, what exactly is the disaster?
Well, it's a sudden,
unplanned event that causes
great damage or serious
loss to an organization.
This might be a natural disaster
like a hurricane or an earthquake.
Or it could be a disaster of a more
modern technological flavor
like a hacker or a data breach.
Either way, if it causes
a sudden, unplanned event
that causes great damage or serious loss,
this would go under your
service continuity management.
This practice is going to
provide you with a framework
for building your
organization's resiliency
and ensure that you have
the capability of producing
the effective responses
needed to safeguard
the interests of your key stakeholders
and your organizations reputation,
your brand and your value
creating activities.
So, my website, for instance,
we have multiple copies of that server.
We have em backed up, online and offline.
We have redundant servers
and load balancers
so that hopefully, even
if one server goes down,
the other ones can carry the load
and get us through the
disaster until we can
recover the server.
That's the idea when
you're talking about this
service continuity management.
What things are you
doing to make sure your
availability and your
performance remain up
at a sufficient level so
you're not going to lose time,
money, or value for your customers
whenever there's a disaster.