- Utility and warranty are two terms that
every ITIL student simply has to know.
They're going to come
up time and time again
throughout your training
and in the real world.
Utility refers to the
functionality offered by a
particular product or service
to meet a particular need.
This really is what the
product or service does.
Utility is what we refer
to as fit for purpose.
Now, let's take a look
at warranty for a moment,
and then we're going to compare and
contrast these two terms,
because comparing and
contrasting these terms
is something you're
going to see on the exam.
Warranty is the assurance
that the product or service
will meet the agreed upon requirements.
It is how a service performs.
Warranty is concerned
with the services ability
to accomplish what it needs to do.
This is often referred to as fit for use.
Now, to compare and
contrast these two terms,
let's use the example of a car.
As a consumer,you have
a requirement to drive
a car from Point A to Point B.
You want it to get at least
35 miles per gallon of fuel efficiency,
and you live somewhere that
gets really hot in the summer,
and really cold in the winter,
so you want a good cold
air conditioning system,
and a really nice warm heater.
Now, let's consider these requirements,
and determine if it meets
our utility standard.
Remember, utility is about
something being fit for purpose.
And if I have a small family,
I may be able to fit
my wife and my two kids
in a four door sedan like a Toyota Prius.
So, to carry the family
from Point A to Point B,
the Prius would be fit for purpose,
and it would meet my utility functions.
In addition to this,
if I bought a brand new Prius,
it would certainly have
high enough fuel efficiency
and have a really nice air
conditioner and heating system,
so it's going to meet my
warranty requirements as well.
Remember, warranty is
all about fit for use.
Does it meet the requirements
stated by the consumer?
So, since, I'm the consumer,
I'm going to say it had to have at least
35 miles a gallon of fuel efficiency,
and a working air conditioner and heater.
And this brand new Prius will
certainly meet those requirements.
This means it's deemed fit for use.
Now, let's say that I bought the car,
a few years go by,
and my wife has another child.
Uh-oh.
We already had two kids,
so this little Prius isn't
going to be very good
for carrying my entire
family around anymore.
It no longer is going
to be fit for purpose.
Because any time I want to go
out for dinner as a family,
we're now going to have to take two cars,
because we all can't fit
into the little Prius.
The warranty might still be there,
because the air conditioner still works,
and the heater still works,
and it still gets over
35 miles per gallon.
But, the intended purpose
of getting us all from
Point A to Point B simply
can't be accomplished.
There is not enough seats,
and not enough seat belts.
And since utility is concerned
with fit for purpose,
this Prius is no longer
meeting my utility needs.
So, hopefully this little
example helps you understand
the difference between
utility and warranty.
Remember for the exam that
what a service does is utility.
That's driving from Point A to Point B.
On the other hand,
how this service does it needs
to be considered as part of warranty.
That's getting 35 miles per gallon,
and keeping the inside of the
car at the right temperature.
Not too hot and not too cold.
Now, one of the important
things to remember
is that you need both
utility and warranty for
a service to operate successfully.
In the IT world,
we often see people focus on
the warranty and they
simply forget about utility.
If I have a service that
runs on a wonderful and
elastic cloud infrastructure,
that can handle millions
of users simultaneously.
That is warranty.
IT people like warranty.
Because it's easy to measure.
If you require that a
service has a defined
and agreed upon condition,
and you meet those conditions,
you have good warranty.
Warranty simply requires
that a service support
the performance of the consumer or removes
the constraints from the consumer.
If the service can be used
effectively by the users
to share their latest social
media posts on the other hand,
that would be considered utility.
If the service is always up,
meaning it has great warranty,
but it doesn't perform the service that
the customer wants it to do,
meaning it hasn't gotten good utility,
then the service is simply
going to end up failing.
You can't run a successful service without
both utility and warranty.
Now, for the exam,
let me give you a couple of tips.
A dead giveaway that they're
talking about warranty
is if they start mentioning
things like availability,
capacity, security levels, and continuity.
These infrastructure measurements
are almost exclusively
in the domain of how a
service does what it does.
And it makes it fit for use.
Therefore, these are
warranty considerations.
On the other hand,
if it starts talking
about the way it performs,
and the fact that it allows somebody
to accomplish some outcome,
then they're usually
talking about utility.
Which is your fit for purpose.
Again, going back to our car,
can it drive from Point A to Point B?
That's utility.
How many miles per gallon
it gets and how long
the engine stays up and how cold it gets.
Those are all warranty.