- Strategy management,
this is another practice
for your general knowledge,
and it's not covered by the exam.
Strategy management is the
practice of formulating the goals
of an organization, and
adopting the courses of action
and allocation of resources necessary
for achieving those goals.
Strategy management is simply responsible
for establishing the
organization's direction,
focusing our effort to finding
and clarifying our
organizational priorities,
and providing consistency or guidance
in response to the environment.
Normally, strategy management
is going to be done
at very high levels in your organization.
You're going to get
direction from the CEO,
as well as the other C-Suite executives,
on which way the
organization should be going.
And they're going to do this
based on the changing environment
that they see outside of the organization.
For example, let's go
back to the early 2000s
and think about the company called Kodak.
Kodak was a film company,
and around the early 2000s,
digital cameras were
starting to outpace the way
that traditional film
companies were operating,
because most people were moving
from a regular camera to a digital camera.
Well, if you think about
it nowadays, here in 2019,
how many people have
a film camera anymore?
Almost nobody, right?
Well, that would put
Kodak out of business,
because their major
profit center was film.
And so, what they had to
start doing was figuring out,
with their strategy, should they pivot?
Should they move from
film to digital cameras?
And they tried to do that,
but they did it a little bit too late.
And so, they didn't
really get enough of a go,
and that company ended up not
doing well in the long-term.
The reason for this was
they didn't see the writing
on the wall, they didn't
pivot quick enough
because their strategy
didn't change quick enough.
Strategy management is
focused on doing that.
It's being able to see what the future is
and turning the organization
before that future hits you.
That's the whole goal here.
We want to be able to focus our effort
to find our organizational priorities
and make sure that we're all
aiming towards the same vision.