- Outcomes.
Back when we discussed the
definition of a service,
we said that a service was a means
of enabling value co-creation
by facilitating outcomes
that a customer wants to achieve
without the customer having
to manage the specific costs and risks.
Now in this lesson, we're
going to dig into a single word
from that definition, the word outcome.
An outcome is a result
for a stakeholder enabled
by one or more outputs.
This is focused on the
customer's desired outcome,
not the service provider's though,
and this is important to understand.
Now, outcomes are important
to consider as part
of the balancing act between
the supported outcomes,
the removal of costs,
and the removal of risks
against unwanted or undesirable outcomes,
the cost, and the risk
that could be introduced
by the customer if they
decide to instead set up
and manage their own resources.
Now, let's consider an example
of what we're really discussing here.
In my local area, we have two
major ride-sharing companies
that operate, we have
Uber and we have Lyft.
Now, whichever you prefer
here really doesn't matter,
but I tend to take Uber
more often than Lyft myself.
Now, I really like these
ride-sharing services,
especially when I'm traveling
to a large downtown area
for a conference or a
convention or when I need
to get from the airport to my
house or something like that.
Now, as a customer, I
have a desired outcome.
I want to get from point A to
point B in the least amount
of time with a fair amount of cost.
For example, the last trip
I took to San Francisco,
I didn't even need to rent a
car because I simply used Uber
and Lyft to get from
the airport to my hotel
and from my hotel to various
locations around the city
that I needed to go to for my work.
Now, this allowed me to get
the outcome that I desired,
which was getting from point A to point B
in less time and with less hassle.
Now, because I used the Uber
app, I was able to reduce
my overall costs because I
didn't need to have a rental car.
I didn't need to spend
$75 per night to park
that rental car at my
hotel and I didn't need
to buy gas for that rental car.
I didn't need to purchase
insurance for the rental car.
You're getting the idea here.
I was able to remove a lot
of the costs because as
a customer, I simply paid
for the service every time
I needed it and I was able to
achieve my desired outcome,
getting from point A to point B.
Now, if we consider the risks involved,
I was able to reduce
some of my risk as well.
For example, I tend to
find it very difficult
to park in large cities,
especially near the areas
of town that I need to
visit for a work trip.
So when I used Uber, I
could eliminate the risk
of not finding adequate parking when I got
to my desired location.
Instead, I just get out
of the car and I'm there.
I also eliminated the
risk of somebody stealing
my rental car while it's
parked or breaking into it
and stealing my luggage.
All those type of things are eliminated
and it's no longer a risk for me.
Now, I think you're starting
to get the idea here.
There's lots of different costs
and lots of different risks
that can be reduced if
you're using a service
and I can gain the benefits
of the service as a customer
by using this ride-sharing
app instead of renting
my own car whenever I
travel to a big city.
Now conversely though, I
need to balance this with
the other side of the equation.
There's certain costs and
risks that I'm assuming
by choosing to use Uber or Lyft instead
of renting my own car.
First, there's cost imposed
upon me by the service provider.
Beyond the actual service
cost to get from point A
to point B, there's also a
requirement that I maintain
a smartphone to run the
app and I have to ensure
that I have a data plan on that smartphone
and I have to make sure that my smartphone
has enough battery power.
All of this are things that have to happen
so that I can connect
the app from my phone
to their central server in
order to order that Uber
to my location and have them pick me up.
Now, this goes back to our original point
about value, right?
Value is co-created and a
service is all about co-creating
value by facilitating those
outcomes that the customer wants
to achieve without the
customer having to manage
the specific costs and
risks of that service.
So, as a customer of this
ride-sharing service,
I need to co-create the
value of the service
by having a smartphone
and an active data plan
and enough battery power to run it.
Now, Uber on the other
hand, needs to ensure
that all the other technical
details of the service
are taken care of.
They're going to provide the
servers that enable the service,
they're going to enable the
technology and the software coding,
all of that other stuff.
Now, I mentioned that the
customer doesn't want to manage
the specific costs and risks.
What risk might there be
with using an Uber instead
of having your own rental car?
Well, I've had an occasion
or two where I've had to wait
for my Uber to arrive because
there's none in the area,
and sometimes this'll
take me 10 or 15 minutes.
Now, if I'm running a
really tight schedule,
there's a risk that I can miss my meeting.
There's also a risk
that a driver just isn't
in the area when I need one.
And so if you happen to go to
a city center where there's
a lot of Ubers and you
travel to a location
in the suburbs where
there's not a lot of Ubers,
well this can become a
problem when you're trying
to get a ride back to the city.
This is a risk that
you're going to assume.
If you had a rental car,
you wouldn't have this risk,
because you could simply jump in the car,
turn the key, and start driving.
Now as we have these costs
and risks that the service
has now imposed upon
me, as their customer,
I now have to decide whether
I should ultimately use
their service or say
it's not worth the effort
and I'll simply rent a car
and drive myself around.
Now, this is the idea that we're
all going to be thinking about
when we think about a service,
whether we're the one using the service
or the one providing the service.
That decision is going
to be based on value.
All of this comes back to value.
If the value's being co-created to achieve
the supported outcomes, then
the removal of the costs
and the removal of risk has to be greater
than the unintended consequences.
And if that's true, the
introduction of these new costs
or the introduction of new
risks has to be balanced
and shifted in the favor of
the consumer if you want them
to buy the service from
the service provider.
In this case, ordering
an Uber or a Lyft instead
of renting a car.
It's all just about
balancing this value, right?
If we're the service provider,
or a service provider organization
like Uber in this case,
we need to make sure that
we're giving more value
and removing more costs and
risks than we're introducing,
and this way, the customer
will want to use it.
Now, in order for the
customer to see the value
that we're generating,
this has to be true.
It has to tip the scales
towards the customer side.
Now, as the service provider,
we want to make sure
we're getting value in this, too.
If we're the customer,
we need to make sure
that we're not creating additional costs
or risks for ourselves
that outweigh the benefits
of the service that
we're going to consume.
So, if I'm going to go ahead
and outsource my servers,
I want to make sure that it's
cheaper for me to do that
and provides me more
value for me to do that
than just to simply
run the servers myself.
Now, each personal
organization is going to weigh
the value proposition and
they're going to determine
if it makes sense for them.
If it does, were going to have
a valid business agreement
and we're going to be able
to go into business together.
You're going to provide me a
service and I'm going to pay you
to do that as the
consumer or the customer.
So, going back to my
example of Uber or Lyft,
I find it works great
for me when I'm traveling
in a big city where
the parking prices tend
to be very high, the
traffic tends to be heavy,
and the number of drivers
around is quite abundant
so it's easy for me to
get a Lyft or an Uber
when I need one.
But when I travel to
more remote locations,
I prefer to have my own
rental car because it solves
the problem for me much
more efficiently because
there's less risk of me not
finding a parking space,
because parking is low-cost in those areas
and traffic is less of an
issue because I'm outside
the city center.
This is the whole idea
of balancing those pros
and those cons so we can make the idea
and figure out what
gives us the most value.
So, we've talked a lot
about outcomes so far in all
of these examples, but there's
also a similar concept known
as output that it's
important to understand
when you take the exam.
An output is a tangible
or intangible deliverable
or an artifact that's
created by an activity.
Now, for the exam you have to understand
the difference between
an output and an outcome.
Services facilitate outcomes
through one or more outputs.
So, what does that mean?
Well, an output could be a report,
it could be a bill that
you receive at the end
of the service that you've consumed,
or it can even be an email if you're using
a webmail service.
All of these things
are considered outputs.
They're that tangible item that comes out
of using that service.
Now, I like to think about this in
a more tangible way, though.
Consider this course.
When I'm writing and filming
this lesson, the output is
the final video that
you're watching right now,
but this isn't the outcome,
it's just the output.
So if the video isn't
the outcome, what is?
Well, it's the desired
value that you're trying
to achieve from this video.
In the case of this video and
the others in this course,
the outcome for a student
like you is to be able
to pass your ITIL 4 Foundation exam.
If you're able to do that
after watching these videos,
then you've achieved the
outcome that both you
and I have desired.
This is an important concept
and one that people often
confuse because the
output is easily measured,
but often the outcomes are not.
It's easy for me to create
an outline and list all
of the videos that we're going
to produce for this course.
We can say, for example, there's
going to be 100 videos in
this course and if I've already
filmed 12 of those videos,
then I'm 12% complete
with creating this course,
and so I have outputted
12% of the product.
Now, this is measuring
outputs though, right?
It's not measuring outcomes.
Do we know that 100
videos is the right number
to help you as a student?
Get from the beginning to
the end and pass the exam?
Well, if the outcome we want to achieve
is a student passing, then
100 videos might not be
the right measure.
Maybe it only takes 25 videos
or maybe it takes 200 videos.
We'll have to figure that out
and measure that as we go.
And as we figure out
what things are working,
what things aren't, we add
or we remove to the course
to make sure that our students
are always going to be able
to pass the exam.
Now, output is part of an
outcome, but there's more to it
than just outputs.
So, when you think of outcomes,
I want you to remember
that it's what you're able to achieve
as a result of the activity.
As a result of this interaction.
Not just the outputs
that are being created.
Going back to my Uber and Lyft example,
the outcome is me getting across town
and to my meeting on time
because of the service provided
by those companies.
The outcomes of taking
this course isn't to say
that you sat here and watched
100 videos for X number
of hours or whatever it happens to be.
But instead, it's focused
on you passing the exam.
That's the outcome that both
you and I want to achieve here.
Now, because of this, outcomes
can be a bit more intangible,
where outputs tend to
be much more tangible.
They're things you can
touch and feel like papers
and reports and things like that.
It also means that outputs
are easier to measure because
they're the results of an activity.
So, when building your service metrics,
be careful not to measure
just outputs, but instead,
you need to put some thought
behind how you're going to measure
your outcomes as well, because otherwise,
you're going to have
people working for you
that game the system.
They're going to be
pushing different things
to make it look like all
those outputs are really high,
but you're never going to
achieve the outcomes you want.
So really think about that as
you're building those metrics
and be sure to measure your
outcomes, not just your outputs.