- Information and Technology.
It's our second dimension,
and when we talk about these dimensions
it's the perspective that we're looking at
those products and services through
so we can co-create that
value for our consumers.
We look at it from information technology.
These are two different things.
We have the information,
and we have the technology
that we're going to
hold the information in.
Let's start with technologies
'cause that's the one
that's probably easier to understand.
When we talk about technology,
this is all the things
that an information technology specialist
is going to deal with on a daily basis.
That's the servers, the
mobile phones, the laptops,
the desktops, the routers, the
switches, all of that stuff.
But when we talk about technology,
it's really split up into
two different things.
There's technologies
that are going to support
the IT Service and there's
technologies that are going to
support the IT Service Management.
Notice there's a difference there.
Now I talk about the IT Services.
Let's say that you're Uber.
You're going to be a ride sharing service.
What technologies do you
need to provide your service?
You have to have a website.
You have to have an app.
You need to have servers
and infrastructure.
You need to have applications
and communication systems,
maybe some artificial intelligence
to send the right driver
to the right location.
You might be using cloud
computing and cognitive computing.
You may even be using Blockchain
if you're accepting Bitcoin for payment.
All of that stuff is the
stuff that we need to do
to get that service in the
hands of your consumer.
Now on the other side of
things, we have technologies
that support Service Management.
And when we're talking about
technologies supporting
IT Service Management, we're
talking about the things
that allow the business
to do it's function.
That's things like work flow management.
It might be your customer service tools.
It might be remote
collaboration so you can log in
to those IT services, those
servers and cloud services,
to go in and configure them.
It might be things like mobile platforms
or inventory systems so you can figure out
where all your spare parts are.
All the things that aren't
going to necessarily deliver
the service to the end user,
but are things the business needs anyway.
For example, you might have
an Intranet SharePoint site
that serves as your
knowledge base, and if so,
that would be a supporting IT
Service Management technology,
not an IT Services technology.
Now some of these
technologies will be the same.
You might be using cloud
computing in both areas.
You might be using artificial
intelligence in both areas.
But there is that difference there.
There's those things that
are supporting the end user,
those IT Services, and then
those things that are supporting
your internal staff so they
can support your end user,
and those things are going to be
the IT Service Management technologies.
That's the technology side of things.
Now, let's consider the
information side of things
as we look at our products and services.
For some of our services,
information management
is probably the primary means
of enabling that customer value.
For example, if you're a
newspaper that's online,
what are you delivering to your customers?
You're delivering information.
And so information management
is critical to that.
You might be a data analytics company
and you're providing data analysis
and the results of that data
analysis as information.
And so if that's the case,
information is very important to you.
Information management has lots
of different challenges though,
because when you talk about information,
there's all these different things
we need to make sure are there
so the information can get
to where it needs to be
to add that value.
That's things like ensuring
we have availability
of the information,
reliability of the information,
accessibility of the information.
The information needs to be
timely, it needs to be accurate,
and it needs to be relevant.
All of these are factors
that we judge information by.
And if we can get all those six factors,
we probably have some
highly valuable information.
But, to maintain all those is a challenge,
and it's difficult.
To be able to do that,
we have to make sure
that we're providing good security for it,
and good IT services that
underlie those informations.
We meed to make sure we're meeting all the
regulatory compliance requirements
and the legal requirements.
All of this is things
that we have to consider
when we think about the
information dimension,
or that perspective as we look at
building out our products and services.
When we look at this
and when we look at
information and technology,
what are some of the considerations
that we should be thinking of?
We should be thinking of
is this compatible with
the current architecture?
Is this going to work with
the technology we're already using?
Does it raise any kind of
regulatory, legal, compliance,
or information security control issues?
If I start holding a lot of
people's personal information,
how am I going to protect it for instance?
Because there's laws that
say I have to protect it.
The next thing is will
it continue to be viable
in the foreseeable future?
If I'm going to invest a
lot of money into moving
to this new server, is
this going to be good
for the next three to five years?
Or is this something that's
only going to be good
for three months?
If it's not good for
the foreseeable future,
we may want to rethink it.
When we think about new
technology, is it going to align
with the service provider or
the service consumer strategy?
We have to have a strategy
of where we're going.
For example, in my
company, we have a strategy
of what kind of courses we want to teach.
Even though I can teach probably 50
or even a hundred different courses,
there's only about 20 or 30 courses
that we have in our portfolio.
And the reason is, that
aligns with our strategy
where some of the other things don't.
And when you think about
this from your business,
you have to think about what's
in line with your strategy
and what isn't.
If you're a computer
company you probably want
to be doing things that build computers.
You don't want to start
doing healthcare services.
It doesn't align with your brand.
Next we're going to think about
does the organization
have the right skills
to support and maintain the technology?
For example, if you're going
to move all your stuff to the cloud,
do you have people who know
how to run Azure and AWS?
Because those are skills
you're going to need,
and running cloud servers is different
than running your own server farm.
The next consideration
we have to think about
is is it going to have enough
automation capabilities
that you can develop it, and
deploy it, and operate it
with less people in the future?
Because we're always trying
to minimize our overhead
and lower our costs.
Anything that can be automated,
we probably want to automate it.
Another thing we have to think about is
does it have additional
capabilities that we can leverage
for other products and services?
This is an interesting one.
If you think about this,
this is actually how Amazon
Web Services Started.
Amazon had to start
building large server farms
so that they could start selling
more product as amazon.com.
But as they did that they
built up a lot of capability,
and they go oh wait I bet
other businesses would like
to have this capability too.
And they started selling it is
AWS, or Amazon Web Services.
Maybe that might apply
to your business as well.
As you're doing some
kind of new capability,
you're going to buy
something for one capability
but it brings you other capabilities.
And that now may add to your
product or service line,
just like Amazon did with AWS.
And finally we want to think about
does this new technology
introduce new risks
or new constraints to your organization?
If I'm going to move
everything to the cloud,
how is that going to work
from a data loss prevention strategy?
How is that going to work
from a regulation compliance strategy?
All of those are things we have
to think about in the risk.
When we think about risk,
we're actually going to go back
to our last dimension as well.
It's going to go back to
our organizational culture.
Depending on the nature of
your organization's business
and the culture you have,
you may be more or less risk averse.
For example, if you're a small start-up
out in Silicon Valley,
you're probably willing
to take a lot of risk,
but if you're a big established company,
you probably don't want
to take a lot of risks.
You want to make sure things are stable,
accurate, and reliable.
Those things are things
you have to consider
which technologies you're
going to implement.
Are you going to get the cutting
edge, which is more risky,
or are you going to get
something that's more stable
and tried and true?
Again, these are all
different considerations
to think about.
But the bottom line,
especially for the exam,
is that one of the dimensions we're going
to be thinking about when
we're building our product
or service is based on the
information and technology,
and figuring out how that
information technology
is going to impact the
service for the long haul.