- At this point in the course,
we've already mentioned
the word risk a few times,
but I wanted to dive into it
in a little bit more
detail in this lesson.
Risk refers to a possible
event that could cause
harm, loss, or make it more difficult
to achieve your objectives.
Essentially, it's any possible
event that could impact
our ability to co-create that
value through our services.
Generally, when most people think of risk
and service management,
they think about it
from a new insallation
or a project perspective.
But risk is also present in
the form of our services too.
From a service provider
perspective, our goal is to
minimize risk for our
customers who use our services.
In this way, risks are similar to costs.
But just like costs, our
customers will assume
that some new risk is going to occur
as part of their
consumption of our services.
For example, if we go
back to my Uber example
where I was a customer using the app
to get rides all over San Francisco,
I removed the risk of not
finding a parking space
for my rental car since
the service removed my need
for me to have my own rental
car in the first place.
However, I now run the
risk of not being able
to call an Uber if the app malfunctions.
Or, what if I'm in an area where
there's no cellular service?
Or, what if my phone battery dies?
All of these are new
risks that are introduced
into my desired outcome of
traveling around San Francisco.
Now as a consumer of the
service, I can also contribute
to reducing the risk by taking
some mitigating actions.
For example, I can carry around
a spare battery pack with me.
By doing this as a consumer, I am reducing
the risk that I won't be
able to call for an Uber
when I need one because
of my battery dying.
At the same time, I might also communicate
to Uber that I'm finding it difficult
to use their service in more rural areas.
Maybe when I'm outside the city,
I'm not getting enough
Uber drivers in that area.
By more clearly articulating
my needs and my requirements,
then the service provider can determine
if they're able to better meet them.
Maybe Uber is going to decide that
they're going to pay a premium
or a bonus to their drivers who will work
in those more rural areas
outside the city center.
That might increase the number
of drivers on those streets
and make it easier for
customers to get a ride.
Now as a consumer, it's up to me to
clearly communicate my needs
to that service provider
and to clarify the outcomes
that I want to achieve.
I also need to make sure I'm
communicating any constraints
or critical success factors
that I may have for that service.
This means I'm putting requirements
on that service provider, right?
Well, guess what?
This service provider may also
put requirements on me as a customer too.
In the example of Uber, they require me
to have a cell phone, a valid data plan,
and the ability to send my
GPS location to their drivers
by using the location
tracking feature on my phone.
This is a two way street after all.
We're both working to co-create
the value and reduce the overall risk.
Now, since risk is a possible
event that could cause harm
or make it more difficult for
us to achieve our objectives,
we can do some things
to mitigate that risk.
Well, what are those
things that we can do?
There's actually 4 things
we can do with risk.
We can avoid risk, we can accept risk,
we can transfer risk,
or we can mitigate risk.
Now, when we avoid risk, we're aiming
to actually remove it
completely from the service.
Now, in reality, we can't remove
all the risk for a service
because risk is something
that's inherent in everything
that a business does to
some level in some degree.
But, there are certain risks
that we can avoid completely.
For example, let's say that
you're running a service
that allows people to read your blog.
Maybe you're worried about
the new privacy regulations
and don't want to have to
worry about maintaining
all of the blog reader's
information securely
and properly under the
new GDPR provisions.
Well, you could avoid
those issues completely
if you turn off tracking on
your reader's information
by disabling any cookies,
and you can also remove any
requests for their email addresses
and other things like that.
If you're not collecting their
information, you no longer
have to protect that information.
Now, this may not be the
best business decision, right
because most businesses
want to be able to track
their customers and contact
them by email with offers.
So, while you can avoid
this whole situation,
it's probably better if we found
a better way to handle this risk.
And that brings us to
simply accepting the risk.
With this option, you look
at the cost of protecting
against the risk and you look
at the possible bad outcomes
and determine that it's
simply cheaper to pay
to accept the risk and pay up
if you're going to get caught.
Now, going back to our privacy
example, I have a friend
who is in an Australian based company,
which is outside of the European Union.
Because of this, he's
taken the position that
he's not worried about
complying with the GDPR policies
because he's an Australian
living in Australia
and he has an Australian company.
He isn't actively targeting
European customers,
but if they happen to
go to his site, too bad.
He's calculated the risk
and he believes the risk
is low that the EU is
going to try to fine him
or even collect if they do.
So he's taken no actions in regard
to changing the way his website works
or the way his business works.
He's going to do it the exact
same way he did before GDPR
to the way it is after GDPR.
Now, this is called risk acceptance.
Now, the next thing we could do is we can
instead decide to transfer the risk.
Maybe you don't want to be
responsible for collecting
and storing all this private information,
but you still want access to that data.
Well, in that case you can hire
a service provider to collect it for you,
to store it securely,
and to give you access.
This would be a form of risk transfer.
Another option might be
that you take the approach
that my Australian friend
did and he simply is going to
pay some insurance in case
you get sued or fined.
This transfers the risk
to the insurance company
because you paid them a monthly premium
to take that risk on for you.
Our final option with risk
is what's most commonly used.
It's known as risk mitigation.
With risk mitigation, we
put in place some actions to
reduce the risk even if it
doesn't eliminate it completely.
In our privacy data example, we may add
new technology systems that
are going to better protect
the data and implement new processes
in the way that we handle the data.
This will help us reduce the risk and
hopefully make the
information much more secure,
which is one of the intended
outcomes of GDPR anyway.
But, a hacker can still
break into our network
and steal all of the customers' data.
If this happens, we might
have reduced the risk
but we didn't eliminate the risk.
That's the idea of risk mitigation.