- Service relationships, this is what
being a service provider is all about.
To create value, an
organization has to provide more
than just a service.
They have to work with their
consumers and their customers
to build an ongoing relationship.
Now, in the business world,
just as in our love life,
relationships are challenging
and sometimes difficult.
In this lesson, we're going
to take a look at what
a service relationship is and
why it can be so complicated.
First, let's cover the definition
of a service relationship.
A service relationship is a cooperation
between the service provider
and a service consumer
that includes service
provision, service consumption
and service relationship management.
This is a fairly straight forward concept.
Basically, it's when two
organizations want to work together,
they have a relationship that's formed.
During this relationship,
one of these organizations
might assume the role
of the service provider
and the other becomes the consumer.
Right now, you and I have
a service relationship.
I'm the service provider
and you're the consumer
of the training service
that we're offering.
But like I said, it can be
much, much more complicated
than that.
But I'm getting a little
ahead of myself here.
Let's first talk about service provision.
What is service provision?
Well, service provision is the
activities that are performed
by an organization to
provide the services.
This includes things like
managing the service provider's
resources, configuring them
to deliver the service,
providing access to the
resources to the users
and fulfilling the agreed
upon service actions,
as well as conducting
service level management
and even performing continual
improvement to their services.
Service provision can even
include supplying goods
to the consumer as well.
Now, let's consider when you
go and buy a new cell phone
from your cell phone service provider.
You walk into the store
and they give you a phone,
which is good, and they
activate your phone
by giving you a brand new phone number
and this is actually called
account provisioning.
This establishes your new user account,
your new phone number in this case.
And they assign different
features, such as voicemail
and text messages and a
data plan and other things
to your account.
By the time they're done,
you can walk out of the store
with your new phone, your new phone number
and working cellular service.
That is all service provisioning
by your service provider.
Now, when you walk out the
door, you're going to use
your new cell phone and now,
you're going to become a consumer
who's beginning to do what is
known as service consumption.
Service consumption includes
all the activities performed
by an organization or a single person
in the case of your new cell phone,
and this is going to allow you
to consume those new services.
Service consumption includes
things like the management
of the consumer's
resources that are needed
to use the service, such as you
paying your bill every month
to make sure the service
stays working, as well as
all the other actions
you perform to utilize
the provider's resources,
such as checking your email
or making phone calls
on your new smartphone.
Or it can even be requesting
new service actions
to be fulfilled.
For example, you might
be getting ready to fly
from one country to another
and you need your service provider
to enable data roaming on your phone.
This, again, is one of
those things that can happen
inside of service consumption.
When the consumer is doing something,
this is called service consumption.
Now, in addition to service provisioning
and service consumption,
there are some activities
that are done by both the service provider
and the service consumer
and when they do these things
together, they're trying
to enable value co-creation
to occur based upon the agreed
and available service offerings.
This is known as service
relationship management.
The most basic of the things
here are things like having
the consumer paying their bill on time,
so their monthly subscription
doesn't get canceled
and the service doesn't get turned off.
Or it may be that the service
provider needs to ensure
they're communicating with the consumer
about a possible network
outage that's going to occur
because this weekend there's
going to be a server upgrade.
This back and forth communication
is what we call service
relationship management.
So, now that we know a little bit
about service relationships,
including service provisioning,
service consumption and service
relationship management,
let's dig in to the complicated
portion of this topic,
the service relationship model.
As I said, business can be
complicated and because of this,
we have to consider the
different relationships
that are involved in any single service.
For example, let's consider
my website, diontraining.com.
We offer training services
over video to our students,
students just like you.
Now, if you're watching this
video on diontraining.com,
that means there are a lot
of different service relationships
that have already
occurred behind the scenes
to enable that to happen.
Let's place you in the Organization D spot
here on the far right.
Now, you want to watch this
video, but for that to happen,
the video has to get to you.
Well, that happens because you
have a service relationship
in place with our company.
In this relationship, you are the consumer
and we are the service provider.
Well, to make this work, we
rely on service providers
as well.
We don't host our own videos,
for example, but instead
we outsource that to a very
large video streaming company
with cloud servers all over the world
to ensure that you get the best quality
with the lowest latency.
Let's put them up here as Organization B.
Now, in the relationship
between Dion Training
and the video streaming
company, we are the consumer
and the video streaming company
is the service provider,
but that video streaming service we used,
they don't even own their own servers.
No, instead they rely on Google Cloud.
And that means the video streaming service
is actually a consumer, too.
Well, Google is going to
be their service provider,
but to make it even more
complicated, there are departments
inside of Google that work on IT systems.
Well, some of those people
are actually members
of my website and they take
this very same training
that you're in right now.
And so, when you're logged into my website
to watch those videos,
they're now going to be the consumers
and I'm the service provider once more.
You can see how this
interrelationship can get really messy
and really complicated.
The bottom line here is
I want you to realize
that in most cases,
organizations are going to be
both a service provider to someone
and as service consumer themselves.
This is what this diagram is showing
with just these four companies
we discussed in this example.
If I was going to draw
out every relationship
for every service offering
within my company,
I would have to fill 100
or more of these screens
because of all of the different
relationships we have,
and we're just a small company.
If you think about how messy
this would be for somebody
like Facebook or LinkedIn
or Microsoft or Google.
It can just blow your mind.
So, for the exam, I want you to remember,
your organization may
be a service provider
or a service consumer or it can be both.
It all depends on the scenario
and the service relationships
that are involved.