- Relationship management.
Our next practice is
relationship management.
And for the exam you do need to understand
the purpose of relationship management,
and memorize this definition.
The purpose of relationship management
is to establish and nurture the links
between the organization
and its stakeholders
at strategic and tactical levels.
Now, we do this by identifying, analyzing,
monitoring, and doing
continual improvement
of those relationships
between various stakeholders.
The most common of these relationships
is the one between the service provider
and the service consumer.
So, in our relationship,
I'm the service provider and
you're the service consumer.
I want to make sure that you're happy.
I want to make sure
that your needs are met.
And by understanding all of that,
and having a proper
relationship between us,
I'm hoping that you're
going to come and take
more courses from us,
and that you're going to pass this exam,
and you're going to be happy
and tell all of your friends.
If that happens, then I have some good
things that come out of this
relationship management practice.
Now, when we look at
this about stakeholders
at strategic and tactical levels,
it's not just service provider
and service consumer though.
There are a lot of other ones in there.
So, as I'm going through and I'm building
those relationships, I need to
monitor those relationships.
I need to identify the needs
of those relationships.
What exactly does that stakeholder need?
There may be a stakeholder who is asking
for a new product or service.
Well, as part of relationship management,
we're going to talk to them and identify
exactly what all of those
needs are that they have.
We can then put that into our requirements
and figure our how we're
going to build to those.
As we do that, we're
going to monitor that,
and make sure that we're
meeting all the things
we needed to, and then,
we're going to make sure
that it's done properly,
and we'll go through continual improvement
to make that go through again,
and get it better than it was before.
The whole idea here with
relationship management, again,
is to establish and nurture
the links between the
organization and its various stakeholders
at strategic and tactical levels.
If you remember that for the exam,
you're going to do great.