- Focus on value.
Focus on value is our
first guiding principle.
It states that everything
the organization does
should link back, directly or indirectly,
to value for itself, its
customers, and its stakeholders.
Now how do we apply this focus on value?
Well there's really a four
step method that I like to use
when I think about focusing on value.
First, I want to understand and
identify the service consumer.
Who is it that I'm trying to serve,
because if you remember from value,
we're trying to co-create value
between the service provider
and the service consumer.
Now once I identify who
that service consumer is
and how they plan on using my service,
I can then understand the
consumer's perspective of value.
For example, if my service
consumer is a student
who wants to be able to watch videos
to learn how to pass the ITIL four exam,
then I need to understand how
you plan on consuming that.
Are you planning on sitting
at your desktop all day,
or are you going to be on a mobile device?
And if you're on a mobile device,
do you have enough data to
be able to stream the videos,
or do you want to be
able to download the data
and be able to download all
those videos ahead of time?
These are all things
that we have to consider
as we're building out our service
and how we can best
support and provide value
to our service consumers.
Then I want to map the value
to the intended outcomes,
and those intended outcomes
may change over time.
I used the example before of this exam.
You're taking this course
so you can pass an exam.
Now once you've passed the exam,
you may go back and
watch these videos again,
but now you have a completely
different perspective
and desired outcome,
because you're not
trying to pass the exam,
you've already done that.
Instead, you're trying
to go back and review
and get smarter in certain areas
so you may be able to take that
and apply it inside your organization.
So those give us two
distinctly different outcomes.
One is a set of students
who are watching the videos
to pass the exam.
Another set is students
who are watching the videos
to get better at their job
and be able to apply ITIL four
inside their organizations.
And that brings us to our fourth step,
and the fourth thing I look at
is to understand the customer experience
and the user experience.
Now this goes back to again,
how does that customer use your service,
what are they trying to achieve in it,
and are you doing it the
best way possible for them?
For example, we might
decide to make a mobile app
that will allow you to take
all of your videos on the go
on your iPhone or your Android.
That might work well if
a lot of my customers
consume our content
through a mobile device,
but if we find that most of our consumers
are consuming that content
by sitting at a desktop or a laptop,
then spending money to build
an Android or an iPhone app
is not going to be worthwhile, right,
and so there's not a lot of value there.
So that's the idea as we go
through those four steps.
Now when we look at application,
there's a couple of key factors.
You want to know how your customers
are going to use each service.
You also want to
encourage a focus on value
among your entire staff,
because as your company
and organization grows,
you're going to have different
people servicing your consumers.
That might be tech support,
it might be customer service agents,
it might be sales agents,
it might be business managers,
whatever it is,
the entire staff needs to know
what that value is that we're
trying to get to our consumers
and then we can push that
across the entire staff
as our leading vision.
Also, when we focus on value,
we want to do this during
operational activity
as well as during our
improvement initiatives.
Focusing on value is done every single day
across the entire service,
whether it's to make it work today
or how we can improve it
to make it better tomorrow.
And finally, I want to make
sure that you're thinking
about creating a focus on value
in every step of any
improvement initiative.
If I decide to go back
and refilm this course,
I need to figure out what
parts need to be improved upon,
and I do that by thinking about the value
it's going to create for
my consumer, my students.
If I'm going to go back
and rerecord this lecture,
I need to be adding something new to it
that makes it better,
and helps you understand
the concepts better,
and allows you to get
more value out of it.
That's the idea.
Everything we do is focused on value,
both for our consumer as well as for us,
the service provider.