- Architecture Management.
This is another one that you don't need
to know for the foundation level exam,
but we're going to cover it
to give you a good general
understanding of it.
The practice of architecture management
is one that's focused on
providing an understanding of
all of the different elements
that make up an organization
and how those elements interrelate,
enabling the organization to
effectively achieve its current
and future objectives.
Now, this provides your
organization with the principles,
the standards, and the tools
that will enable us to
manage complex changes
in a much more structured and agile way.
There are five different
types of architectures
that you should consider
inside your business.
These are business architecture,
service architecture,
information systems architecture,
technology architecture, and
environmental architecture.
Business architecture
allows an organization to
look at its capabilities
to determine how they align
with the different activities
that are required for that business
to co-create value for its customers.
Now, service architecture is
going to give the organization
a view of its services
and their interactions to
better understand how they are
all going to interrelate and tie together.
This usually results in a
service model being created
and this can act as a template
or a blueprint for multiple services
across the organization.
When we look at information
systems architecture,
we're focused on the logical
and physical data assets
of the organization,
and how they are managed
and shared to benefit our overall goals.
The technology architecture
is going to find the software
and the hardware infrastructure
that's needed to support
the portfolio of services
and the products the organization offers.
For example, to answer the question
of whether we should use a
self-hosted configuration
for our web servers or if we should rely
on a cloud-based architecture,
would fall under this technology
architecture umbrella.
And finally, environmental architecture.
This is used to describe the
external factors that affect
and impact our organization.
If you remember our
discussion of PESTLE early on,
this model would fall under
the environmental architecture,
things like political,
environmental, social, technological.
You get the idea.
All of those things are
external to our organization,
so they are considered environmental.
(upbeat chiming)