- The Service Value System
In this section of the course
we are going to briefly describe
the service value system.
Now this ties back to one of the
objectives on the exam, which is to
describe the service value system.
So of the exam, you need to make
sure you understand what the service value
system is and the components that
make up this service value system.
So lets start with,
What is the service value system?
Well, the service value system
or the SVS, is going to describe
how all of the components and activities
of your organization
work together as a system
to enable value co-creation.
Now, these components and activities
are all tied together within the
organizations resources and they
can be configured and reconfigured
in multiple different combinations
in this flexible way based
on the circumstances.
Now this is going to require some
integration and coordination of
all of the different activities
and practices and teams
within the organization.
As well as different authorities and
responsibilities for this
to truly be effective.
Some organizations are much more
flexible than others, some are very
tight and stringent in their ways
but depending on your organization
and its culture, you are going to
be able to utilize this system
in a very rigid or very flexible manner
It just depends on your organization
and how you implement it.
Now the purpose of the service value
system is to ensure that your organization
is continually co-creating value
with all of your stakeholders
through the use and management
of the products and services that
you have within your organization.
Now when we look at this
service value system
its made up of three basic blocks
that we're going to see.
You'll see on the left side we
have opportunity and
demand, that's our input.
We have on the right side, value
that's our output and then we have
all this stuff in the middle.
In the middle we have the service
value chain and we are going to dedicate
an entire section of this course
to talking about the service value chain.
Around that service value chain
we also have governance and practices,
we are going to talk a lot about
practices in their own
section of this course,
which is the final three sections
because there are thirty
four different practices
inside of idle four that
we're going to cover.
And then we have governance which is
the way the organization is run.
We've talked a little bit about
governance before and we're going to
revisit that in this section.
And then we have the guiding principles
and continual improvement and again
the guidance principles is a big concept
so we are going to spend an entire
section on that as well.
So before we go any further I just
want to say welcome to the service
value system and we are going to start
focusing on opportunity
and demand and value,
those inputs and outputs,
in the next lesson.