- Availability management.
This is one that you don't
have to recall for the exam.
Instead, this begins the ones
that we're going to talk about
for your general awareness.
What is availability management?
Well, it's a practice to
ensure services are delivered
at agreed-upon levels of availability
to meet the needs of customers and users.
When we talk about availability,
we're talking about the
ability of an IT service
or other configuration item
to perform its agreed-upon
function when it's required.
For example, if you want to
go to my website right now,
you want to make when you
type in diontraining.com,
the website comes up
and you can read things.
That means it's available.
We aim to have 99.999% availability,
which means that our
website is up at least
the entire year minus five minutes.
That's a pretty big ask, right?
To do that, we use load balancers,
we use multiple redundant servers,
and all sorts of cloud infrastructure
to make sure our server is up and running
any time you're trying to get to it.
That's what we're trying
to do with availability,
and availability management
is simply the practice to
ensure that that happens.