- Service request management,
this is the last practice
that we're going to discuss in depth.
The purpose of the service
request management practice
is to support the agreed
quality of a service
by handling all agreed
user-initiated service requests
in an effective and user-friendly manner.
Now, service requests are
predefined and pre-agreed
and they can usually be
formalized with clear,
standard procedures.
That makes things really easy.
For example, you might have one that says,
let's create a new email distribution.
There's a standard process for it
and a standard request method to do it,
or maybe you need a headphone set
to be attached to your computer at work.
This might be, again, a service request.
Maybe you want to go
from a 15-inch monitor
to a 21-inch monitor,
that might be, again,
a standard service request.
There's basically three pieces that go
with the standard service request.
You have initiation,
approval, and fulfillment.
Now, service requests are
normally part of service delivery
and they're not used for failure
or degradation of a service.
That's used in incident management.
Instead, service requests
are asking for things
that are normal, things that we need.
I need more share drive space.
I need a bigger email account.
I need another email address,
I need my account unlocked.
Those are all things that
would be service requests.
A service request is simply
a request from a user
or a user's authorized representative
that initiates a service
action that has been agreed
as a normal part of service delivery.
The fulfillment of that service request
may include changes to
services or their components
and they usually are going to
be considered a standard change
because they're low-risk
and well understood.
Some examples of these would be a request
for a service delivery action,
like get a new computer for
the new employee we just hired.
It might be a request for information.
It might be a request for
provision of a resource
or a service, give me 10
gigabytes of storage space
instead of five gigabytes.
It might be a request to
get access to a resource
or a service, hey, I need access
to the accounting share drive now,
because I just got transferred over there.
That might be a good example, right?
And it can also have feedback,
compliments, and complaints.
All of those might go through
the service request process.
Service requests and their fulfillment
should always be
standardized and automated
to the greatest degree possible.
Again, these are low risk things.
You want to try to do
them as much as possible
through a self-help system,
so you're not tying up good people,
using up full-time equivalent
man hours or person hours
on these standard service requests.
Instead, we want to reserve
those man hours or person hours
or full-time equivalents
for those incidents
that we need to work through.
There's a lot of
opportunities for improvement
inside of the service request process.
You should always be identifying them
and then implement them to
provide faster fulfillment times
and take advantage of
automation whenever possible.
This allows you to make sure your policies
are established properly, and
if you have proper policies,
this is going to make
sure your service requests
can be fulfilled with limited
or even no additional approvals,
so that fulfillment can be streamlined,
optimized, and process automated.
This is a great way of doing things.
It minimizes the overhead and ensures
the customer gets what they
need as quickly as possible.
Now, the expectations from users
regarding fulfillment times
should be clearly set,
and delivered based on
what the organization
can realistically deliver.
For example, if you buy
a voucher from my site,
I tell you that you can
get it in under 10 minutes
if it's in stock.
If it's not in stock,
you're going to have to
wait one to two days,
because we have to refill our stock,
and manually fulfill it.
So that's the way we tell you,
as an expectation to our users,
you know what you're getting into.
If I didn't tell you that, you'd order it
and think it was going to
be there in five seconds,
and if it wasn't, you'd get upset, right?
That's the idea here with
service request fulfillment.
You want to make sure people understand
how that fulfillment's going to operate.
Now, sometimes your service requests
are actually going to be miscategorized.
People submit it as a service request,
but it really is a change or an incident.
In this case, you want to make sure
your policies and your
workflows are set up properly
so they can redirect
those service requests
over to the incident management process
or to the change management
process, as appropriate.
Also, some of your service requests
are going to require
additional authorization,
and that might be based on your financial
information security or other policies.
Going back to the example
of a bigger monitor,
you want to go from a 15-inch
monitor to a 27-inch monitor.
There may be a cost associated with that,
so you can't get that
approval on your own.
Instead, you put it in
as a service request
and that goes to your
boss, who then approves
the financial part of
it, or maybe I wanted
to get access to the
accounting shared drive.
Well, that's an information
security concern,
so somebody from accounting
is going to have to approve that concern.
Service request management
is going to depend
on well-defined processes and procedures
as I've been talking about.
The more you can do this,
the better you can track
and automate all of these requests,
minimizing the manpower involved,
and your service request
can have simple workflows
or very complex workflows.
It really depends on
how you need to do it,
based on your organization, what changes,
and what approvals need
to be placed in there.
You want to make sure all the steps
to fulfill these requests
are well-known and proven.
You've tested it, you made sure it worked,
you optimized it, and
then you automated it.
Your service provider can always
agree to fulfillment times,
and provide clear status to their users.
You want to make sure you're
always using that engage arm
so that you're telling
your users what to expect.
If you give them a good
expectation of when it should be,
that's going to help clear
up a lot of the confusion
and a lot of the angst that
your customers may have.
When you're thinking about
your service requests,
remember, a lot of these can be done
through a self-service experience.
Things like password resets,
asking for more share drive space,
a lot of these can be completely
fulfilled with automation,
so when you're doing
service request management,
think about automation.
I think you've heard me say
that a lot in this lesson,
but it's really important inside this.
Also, I want you to leverage
your existing workflow models
whenever possible,
so you don't have to start
building things from scratch.
Any time you have something,
even if it's the manual
fulfillment process,
start looking at it,
how can you optimize it,
and then how can you automate it?
So, I know we just covered a lot
in service request management,
but we're going to talk about it now
from the value chain perspective.
When we think about it from improve,
how is this going to relate?
Well, in this case,
service request management
can provide us a channel
for improvement initiatives.
We can get complaints and
comments from our users
and then we can contribute that
into the improvement process,
so that we can find those trends
and think of how we can make
things better in the future.
When we think about it from
the engage perspective,
we want to make sure that
service request management
is including regular communications
to tell the users what they can expect.
What are the requirements,
what are the expectations,
and what is the status?
When we think about this from the design
and transition perspective,
we have these standard changes
to services that we're requesting,
and we're initiating
them and fulfilling them
as service requests.
Also, in obtain and build,
when I'm requesting something,
it has to be fulfilled, and
it's going to be fulfilled,
that means we might have to
go buy something, obtain,
or build it, under the
build, and this is the way
we're going to do things as
a tie-in to that service.
And then finally, when we talk
about deliver and support,
service request management
makes a significant contribution
to our normal service delivery,
because this activity is
going to tell our users
all the things we can do for them,
and allow those things to be requested.
You might want a bigger monitor.
You might want more share drive space.
You might need a new user account.
All of these things are
things that we can do
and ensure the users get what
they need to be productive,
and it makes sure that
we fulfill those needs.
That's what service request
management is all about,
making sure the users are
getting what they need,
so that they can operate
at peak efficiency.