- In this section of the course,
we're going to discuss the four dimensions
of service management.
Now as we do this,
this is going to relate to the
describe the four dimensions
of IT Service Management
objective from the exam.
This is considered a
Bloom's level two objective,
which means that we're going
to have to describe it.
We're not going to be memorizing
definitions specifically.
But we need to understand
how this model works,
and how it applies in ITIL.
Now when we talk about the four dimensions
of IT Service Management,
what we're really talking about
is four different perspectives.
So if I have in the center,
the value that I'm trying to co-create,
I do that by using different products
and services that I deliver
as a service provider
to my consumer or my customer.
Now, the consumer and
customer has this product
that they want to get value from right?
And that means
we have to deliver that
product or that service.
Now when I go to create
a product or service,
I look at it from four
different perspectives.
And these four perspectives
are what we call the four dimensions
of IT Service Management.
The first one is the
organizations and people.
The second is information and technology.
The third is the partners and suppliers.
And the fourth is the value
streams and processes.
And all around that they
have these external factors
you can see around the side
that are going to impact
the service and products
that we're creating as well.
Now we're going to talk about
each of these four areas,
and those external factors
throughout the rest of this section.