- Where are We Now?
The success of an improvement
initiative depends
on a clear and accurate understanding
of the starting point and the
impact of your initiative.
Now, if you think of an
improvement as a journey going
from point A to point B,
this step clearly defines
what point A looks like.
Think about it like this.
If I asked you to drive
to my office right now,
you'd first need to know two things.
First, you need to know
where my office is,
and I'm located in the Washington DC area,
and second, you need to know
where you are currently located.
If you're in California,
you're going to need to get in your car
and drive east to reach my office,
but if you're sitting in London,
England, you're going to
need to charter a boat
or get on a plane and
then start heading west.
Depending on where you're
coming from is going to dictate
where you're going to, and
how you're going to get there.
Your journey simply can't be mapped out
if you don't know what
your starting point is.
Now, in relation to our IT services,
we need to understand the current state
of our services and our products.
To do that, we're going to
conduct a current state assessment
of the existing services
by determining what the user's perception
of the value is for our services,
what existing skills and
competencies our workforce
has for our services, and what processes
and procedures are involve
in delivering those services.
We may even look at what the
technical capabilities are
of our current servers, our
networks, and other solutions.
If you're looking at your
organization's ability
to deliver the services,
you're also going to look at
your organization's culture
and the prevailing
attitudes of the employees.
Now, as we do all of this,
we're going to be
conducting this assessment
to determine the current state
using objective measurements
whenever we can.
Now, an objective measurement
is something we can actually measure.
It's not just do I feel good
about this or bad about this?
We're going to try to put numbers to it.
These measurements are going
to be used to create a baseline
and this baseline can
be used in later steps
of the process to compare
our progress against
our current baseline or current state.
Now, remember, it's difficult to track
and measure any effectiveness
of your improvement initiatives
if you never determine
where you started from.
Make sure you take the time
to create a good objective baseline before
you move into the next step
of the continuing improvement model.