- [Instructor] Our next value chain
activity is Obtain/Build.
Now, the purpose of the Obtain/Build
value chain activity is to ensure
that service components are available
when and where they're needed
and they're going to meet the
agreed-upon specifications.
Simply put, if I'm going
to build a service,
I need to build it to the design criteria
that I was given from the
design & transition activity.
Now, there are a lot of
different inputs and outputs
when it comes to Obtain/Build.
When we talk about inputs,
we're going to get them
from a variety of sources.
First, let's think about
architectures and policies.
We've talked a lot about this
and this is something
that comes from plans.
Plans is going to output the
architectures and policies
and lots of these different value chains
are going to use those
because if we know what the governance is
and the architecture and the
policies for our organization,
that helps us design and
transition a better service,
or in this case,
obtain and build it to
those proper specifications.
Next, we're going to look
at contracts and agreements.
As we get contracts and agreements
with external and internal
suppliers and partners,
those are all going to come as an input
from engage into this Obtain/Build.
Next, we're also going to
look at goods and services
and these goods and services
are going to be provided
by these external and internal
suppliers and partners.
Again, once we contract for something,
we then are going to get some
kind of good or service for it.
The information,
the interaction,
and the engagement all comes from
the engage portion of that contract.
But, the actual physical
delivery and receipt
of the components,
the goods,
and the services,
that occurs inside the
Obtain/Build part of this activity.
And, that is going to
bring us to our next thing,
which is getting the
requirements and specifications
for what we want to obtain or build.
Where do we get the requirements
and specifications from?
Well, that comes from design & transition.
Somebody has designed this service
and they pass those designs to us
here in the Obtain/Build,
where we're actually going
to install the software,
purchase the servers,
get it all connected in network,
and then transition it into
the real live environment
when it goes back into
design & transition.
Another input to the
Obtain and Build activity
is improvement initiatives and plans.
And, these are going to come
from the improve activity
because the improve
activity has been looking at
how can we make things better?
Once they figure out those
processes and procedures
of how we can improve things,
they're going to pass
that back to Obtain/Build
so they can build those things.
Another thing we're
going to get from improve
is our improvement status reports.
Again, they're going to be
looking at our processes,
our procedures,
the lessons learned from before,
and help us improve
the way we do business.
Now, going back to our engage activity,
we're going to get
something from them as well.
We're going to get changes and
project initiation requests
from engage because as
a customer or a consumer
or an end user,
if I have a problem with a service,
I might put in a change request.
And if I put in that change request,
it's coming in through engage
because it's an external communication.
Once engage gets that request,
they're going to process it
and then pass it over
to us in Obtain/Build
so that we can obtain
or build the new service
to meet that customer need.
Other change requests may also be provided
from deliver & support
because the people who are
delivering and supporting things,
maybe there was a switch that went down.
Well, deliver & support
can put a change request
that says 'Switch number
one needs to be replaced'
and then here, in Obtain/Build,
we would go get a new switch
and replace switch number one.
Again, these processes
are all very interrelated.
And then, we get down to our
knowledge and information.
Again, the same two we've been
talking about a lot already:
knowledge and information about
new or changed product and services
is going to come from design & transition.
We need to know what design
& transition is going to do
for some new service so that we can then
build to that specification.
And, the other thing with
knowledge and information
is anything that comes from a
third-party service component.
That information is going
to come from engage as well
because engage is going to push that out
and get it from our third-party suppliers.
Now that we know all of the inputs,
let's talk about some of the outputs.
One of the outputs is service components
for delivery and support.
As I go and I build a service,
I'm going to build
different components for it.
I might build some software code
or a particular server
or a particular system.
Once I do and it goes into live operation,
it's no longer my problem as Obtain/Build.
It now gets transitioned
over to deliver & support,
who's going to run it on a daily basis
to give the end user what they need.
This can include things like spare parts,
consumables,
new functionality,
systems and software.
All of this stuff is stuff
that we can go and give
to deliver & support.
Generally, when it's something big,
like a new system or a new function,
it's going to go from Obtain/Build
back to transition and from
transition to deliver & support.
But if it's something small,
like a spare part or a consumable,
then it doesn't need to go
to design & transition again
and instead, it'll go
straight to deliver & support.
Let's say for example that I
built a brand new web service
and we want to get it out
into the live environment.
Well, we built it here in Obtain/Build
based on the designs that we
got from design & transition.
Now that we've built it though,
we're going to turn that back
over to design & transition
so that they can transition
that into the live environment
and from them,
it's going to go back over
into the delivery and support.
You can see how all these
processes and activities
are going to tie together.
Another output from this activity
is knowledge and information about
our new and changed service components
to all of the other
value chain activities.
Any time I built something new,
I needed to tell everybody about it
so they know the functionality,
the capabilities,
how long that thing will last,
when it needs to be replaced or repaired
and we can plan for it.
We can design for it.
We can support it.
All of the other activities
are going to rely on this
knowledge & information.
And that's why having a good
knowledge management
process is really important.
Now, when we go back to
contracts and agreements,
we're going to send all that information
and the requirements we have for those
back to engage,
who's going to engage with
those external stakeholders,
those partners,
and those suppliers.
And finally, we're going
to get all the information
about our own activity here
inside of the Obtain and Build
and we're going to collect
that performance information
and improvement opportunities
and pass that over to
the improve activity.
That way, they can consolidate that
and look holistically
across all of the activities
and figure out how we
can best improve ourself.
So, when it comes down to it,
and we've talked about
the value chain activity
of Obtain and Build,
I want you to think about
it pretty simply like this.
Any time we're going to buy
something and install it,
that's going to be part
of this Obtain/build.
If we're coding something and
we're creating a new service,
that's going to be inside Obtain/build.
It's when the thing is
actually being built
and developed and coded
based on the requirements
you got from design & transition.
Once it's ready,
you're going to turn that back over
either to design & transition
to formally transition
it to delivery & support
or in the case of something minor
like a replacement switch
or replacement hardware,
that might go directly
to deliver & support,
which we're going to talk about next.