- Incident management,
this is the next practice
we're going to talk about, and again,
it's one that you need to
know in depth for the exam.
The purpose of incident management
is to minimize the negative
impact of incidents
by restoring normal service operation
as quickly as possible.
Basically, what are you going
to do when something goes wrong?
Now, I mentioned there's a couple of terms
you have to memorize, and
here come our second term.
It's an incident.
An incident is an unplanned
interruption to a service
or reduction in the quality of a service.
Every incident needs to be logged,
managed to the agreed-upon
target resolution times,
and prioritized.
The way we design our
incident management practice
appropriately, is going to make sure
that we think about it
from different perspectives
with different incidents,
so I want to take my incidents
and I want to categorize them
based on the different impacts they have.
Is it a major incident
or a minor incident?
Is it an information security incident
or is it a management
and operations incident?
All of these are things
that we have to think about
as we're going through our
incident management practice.
Now, when it comes to
prioritizing our incidents,
I like to do it based on
an agreed classification.
Everyone should know what
that classification is.
Are we going to use high, medium and low?
Are we going to use a
one through five system?
Whatever it is, you need to know it,
your customers need to know it,
and everyone who supports
the systems needs to know it.
Also, we should have a way to say
what would categorize a high incident.
What would categorize a low incident?
Is it based on dollar time?
Is it based on the person's
position in the company?
Is it going to be based on
how much the thing costs?
Is it going to be based on how long
we think it's going to be down?
All of those are valid
ways to classify it.
It really depends on how your
organization decides to do it.
Also, when you're prioritizing incidents,
you need to ensure that your incidents
that have the highest business
impact are resolved first.
That means if it's something
that's affecting five users
or something that's
affecting 10,000 users,
we probably want to fix the thing
affecting 10,000 users first.
It has a higher business impact.
Or, if it's something that
may be a minor inconvenience
verus something that's costing you money,
you want to get the thing that
costs you money fixed first.
Now, when it comes to incident management,
you want to use a tool to log
and manage your incidents.
This is a way that you
can end up linking them
to configuration items,
to the different changes,
to the different problems,
known errors, and other things.
By having a good system,
it really does make
the knowledge management
piece a lot easier,
and helps you resolve
incidents much faster.
Another thing these can do for you
is they can provide incident
matching to other incidents,
other problems, and other known errors,
so for example, if you
call up and tell me,
hey, the wireless network
in the warehouse is down,
I can log that and it can say, oh,
we've already had three
other people call that in.
We know it's a problem
affecting a lot of users.
We should probably
raise the classification
from a low to a medium,
or a medium to a high.
Again, this is the benefit of having
a good incident management tool.
Incidents can also be escalated
for higher levels of support.
Oftentimes, your service
desk, who's your first person
who's taking in the incident,
isn't going to be the person
who's going to resolve it.
Instead, if they can't
solve it at their level,
they'll raise it to tier two support,
and if tier two can't do it,
it'll go to tier three support,
and you'll keep going up until
you get to the right level
of support to get that resolved.
This routing is typically
going to be based
on the incident's category.
Anyone working on an incident
should provide quality
and timely updates back into
this incident management system
because as we're going to talk
about in the service desk,
your service desk
analyst is the frontline.
They're going to be the ones
talking to the customer,
and when the customer says,
hey, is my ticket resolved yet?
They need to know about it.
If you've been working it and
you haven't been putting it
in the incident management system,
the analyst doesn't know the updates,
and the customer doesn't
get the communication.
Now, when we talk about
incident management,
I want you to remember
that incident management
requires a high level of collaboration
within and between the teams.
Like I was saying, if
you're solving the issue,
you need to tell that to the service desk.
You also need to work between your teams
and across your teams.
When we're working to diagnose
and resolve an incident,
your user might end up
using a self-help option.
They might use calling the
service desk as an option.
The service desk might
contact your support team,
your suppliers, or even your partners.
All of this is collaboration
and communication,
so we have to think about all
of this as we work through it.
And the other thing I want you to remember
is that some incidents can be very major
and some can be minor.
If you have a really major incident,
one of the things you might want to do
is create a temporary
cross-functional team
to address that incident.
For example, maybe our website went down.
Well, I might want to get some
people from finance in here
'cause it's going to affect them,
some people from marketing,
'cause it affects them,
some people from sales,
and then of course all
of our technical people,
so we can figure out how
we can create a workaround
and get this incident resolved
as quickly as possible.
In addition to all of
that, you may be doing
an incident response based on
a disaster recovery operation,
and if this is the case,
you want to bring in the
disaster recovery team as well,
because they know the plans and policies
of what we're going to do
to overcome that disaster.
All of this is going to depend
on your particular scenario
that you're involved
with in your incident.
Let me give you an example.
Maybe your organization is the victim
of a cyber attack or a
data breach that's ongoing.
What's the best way to
handle this scenario?
Well, if it was me and my company,
I might use a technique known as swarming.
This involves gathering
up different stakeholders
who initially all work together
until it becomes clear
which of them is best suited
to lead this effort
and solve the incident.
Once that occurs, we can
then release the others
back to their assigned tasks,
and the lead will take the charge of this.
Now, the reason we do this
is because it gives us
all of the people right away,
and this is really important
when you're dealing
with a major incident like a
cyber attack or a data breach.
I might not know exactly
where that person is
inside the network yet.
Are they dealing with the databases,
the file servers, the web servers?
I don't know, so I want people
from all of those teams here
working with me, that's
what we call swarming,
and then once we figure out,
oh, it was a database breach,
then we can let the web guys
go and the file server guys go,
and we'll still work
with the database team.
That's the way we want
to do this kind of stuff.
It's the way that we're trying
to figure out how we can
best solve our incidents.
When we think about incidents,
I want you to think about the fact
that it heavily relies on collaboration
to facilitate information
sharing and learning,
as well as helping to solve the incident
more efficiently and more effectively.
That's what we're trying to do.
So, when we think about this
through our value chain activity lens,
which ones are going to be affected?
Well, let's start with improve.
When we're talking about improve,
we're going to be thinking
about the incident records
in our incident management system.
These are a key input to
our improve activities.
If we can go in there
and find the frequency
and severity of different incidents,
we can figure out where we
need to put more resources,
time or money to improve ourselves.
Now, if we consider this
from the engage activity,
we have to think about the fact
that incidents are visible to everyone.
Your users are going to know about it,
and your customers are
going to know about it,
so we're going to have to engage with them
and let them know ahead of time
how we're solving these problems,
and the fact that we
know that it's a problem
and that we're going to overcome it.
When we think about this
from design and transition,
if we have an incident, it might occur
in a test environment,
which happens during design.
It might also happen during
the release and deployment,
which is part of transition.
Either way, we want to make sure
the incident management practice is there
to help us ensure the
incidents are resolved
in a timely and controlled manner.
When we think about this from
an obtain/build perspective,
we want to think about the
fact that incidents occur
in development environments too, right?
And so as I'm obtaining and
building things, things break.
How are we going to solve those problems?
The incident management
practice has things in place
to help us with those as well,
because we want to make sure
we're figuring those things out early
before we move it into transition,
and then from transition
over to deliver and support,
which brings us to deliver and support.
Deliver and support is
where we spend a lot of time
in incident management, because this is
a significant contributor
to supporting our users.
Deliver and support's value chain activity
includes the resolving of
incidents and problems,
identifying them, solving them,
and communicating that back to the user.
Again, that goes back
into our engage again.
So, as we're talking, all
of this is really important
inside incident management.
How do we identify, diagnose,
and solve all these problems
as quickly and efficiently as possible?
That's what it all comes down to.