- In this lesson, we're going
to discuss the PESTLE model.
Now before we do, I want
to point out that this part
is not going to be on the exam.
The only reason I'm
bringing it up is because
you may have been asking
yourself back in the
introduction to this
section why do we have these
external factors around the
outside of our four dimensions.
We have a value in the
center and then around that
we had the products and services.
We had our four dimensions
that are the four perspectives
we look at our services,
but there are these
external factors circling
around the outside.
And that's why I wanted to discuss here.
These are known as the PESTEL model,
which is a generic open-source model
that stands for the acronym
of PESTLE P for political,
E for economic, S for
Social, T for technological
L for legal and E for environmental.
Now, these are six things
that are outside of your
organization that you can't control.
There are going to happen to you.
But they are external factors
that you have to think about
when you are designing
a service or a product.
Now these are the things that are
outside your control, right?
So let's think about
one of a great example.
I've used this example a
lot throughout this course,
but the example of Uber or Lyft,
those ride-sharing services.
When they first came out,
they were a completely
different model and so there
was a social component of it.
Would people be willing
to embrace this idea
that they can get into a stranger's car
by summoning them with their
app, they could come up
and you get in their car
and they drive you to your
destination as opposed to
using a traditional taxi.
That's a different sociodynamic
than we are used to.
And so that was something that
people were worried about.
They couldn't really control that as Uber.
They had to just hopefully
get enough people to change
their minds in society
that it became commonplace
and now most of us don't think twice
about taking an Uber, do we?
Another one might be technological.
Maybe you're facing some
challenges as you are trying
to figure out how to build your service
that you don't have the
right technology to do it
because that technology doesn't exist yet.
For example, maybe you want
to make sure you have this
ultra safe encryption and
so you want to design it
with quantum resistant
technology but quantum computers
don't exist yet, so you
can't quite do that.
And when quantum computers do come out,
all of the existing technology
and encryption we're using
is going to be consider obsolete.
And so that's a technological impact
external to our environment
that we really can't control.
There's also legal impacts.
I'll go back to the Uber example.
There are cities and there are
countries that have actually
made it illegal for Uber to operate there.
They said that you have
to have a taxi license
to be able to run a taxi type service
and therefore, Uber cannot
be run there and they have
pushed Uber out of those communities.
That's a legal restriction
that they can't get through
until they can get that law changed.
How do you get a law changed?
Well, you try to get some
political pressure, right?
And so maybe you are going
to have to put effort
in lobbying into changing
the minds of the political
culture so they can change
the law and make it so it's
acceptable for you to run
your service into those areas.
All of these things are things
that are going to affect us.
That's the PESTLE, the political,
the economic, the social,
the technological, the
legal and the environmental.
Again, for the exam, you don't
have to memorize these six.
It's just something for
you think about as you're
considering your services
and you're building them
because it is something
that may impact you
depending on the choices you make.