- What is the vision?
Each improvement initiative should support
the organization's goals and objectives.
The first step of the
continual improvement model
is to define the vision of the initiative.
What exactly are we trying to accomplish?
This is going to provide the context
for all of our subsequent decisions,
and links all of our individual actions
to the organization's
vision for the future.
This vision is going to come
from your top leadership.
It should come from the C-suite;
the CEO, the CFO, the CIO, or others
who have this executive vision
of where we're trying to go
with the organization.
This step of the continual
improvement model
focuses on two key areas.
First, the organization's
vision and objectives
that need to be translated
for specific business units,
departments, teams, and individuals.
So we take this context
and we take it from
the larger organization
and drill it down into our specific cases
that we're doing our
improvement initiative inside.
If we don't do that, it
can be really difficult
for us to know how we're
going towards the right way.
The second thing is you need
to have a high-level vision
for the planned improvement,
and this has to be created.
Somebody has to write it, and
someone has to agree to it.
Normally, this will be
your department head
or upper leadership, if it's going to be
an organization-wide
improvement initiative.
Now, you may be wondering
why is this step of determining
your vision so important?
Well, if we neglect to do this,
we may see some incremental improvements
in some areas or some teams,
but we're not going to see
a holistic improvement across
the organization as a whole.
If you want big improvements,
you need to have a big vision.
Now, the other problem is that
sometimes these improvements
that we're working on
don't actually help to
advance the overall vision
of the company.
Instead, we might be spending
time and money and resources
and energy working on some
non-value-adding activities,
all because we didn't know
what the true vision was,
and all of those resources,
they could've been
invested much better in other improvements
if only we knew what the vision was.
So, by the time you're done
with the "what is the
vision step" of the model,
you should ensure that you know
what the high-level direction is
and that it's fully understood.
You need to make sure that you also have
the planned improvement
initiatives described
and understand the context of
them inside your organization.
Additionally, all of your
stakeholders need to be identified
and their roles have
to be well-understood.
The role of the person or the team
that's responsible for
carrying out this improvement
is also now going to be clear to you,
and you're going to understand their role
in relation to achieving the
overall organization's vision.
And, the expected value from this vision
should also be agreed upon.
That way, we all know
what we're getting into.
Basically, by understanding your vision,
we now know what direction
we should be moving towards
with all of our improvements,
who we're going to be helping with
it and who's going to help us,
and how it's going to effect
the organization as a whole.