- Deployment Management.
This is a recall level of
difficulty for the exam.
The purpose of the Deployment
Management practice
is to move new or changed
hardware, software,
documentation, processes,
or other components
to the live environment.
It may also be involved
with deploying components
to other environments
for testing or staging.
Basically, we used to have
release and deployment
as one practice but in ITIL 4,
release and deployment are
now two different things.
Release is more focused
on the approval process,
where deployment is more
about moving the change over
into the live environment.
And so that's what we're going to focus on
inside deployment management.
As I build a new server or
I build a new capability,
it's going to go through
the change process,
it's going to get approval,
it'll go through the
release management process,
and eventually, it will get deployed
through deployment management
and move itself from transition into
the deliver and support perspective.