- Collaborate and promote visibility.
This is our fourth guiding principle.
Now, when we talk about
this, it's all about
collaborating across our staff
and even with our consumers
and our customers.
When we have an initiative that involves
the right people in the correct roles,
we get a lot of benefit
from better buying,
more relevance, and increased
likelihood of long term success.
Collaboration is all
about working together.
We need to share information.
We need to build trust.
We need to build understanding.
We need to understand that there's real
accomplishment that
can happen when we work
across the staff and get out of
our own little pigeon-hold silos.
For example, if I'm building a new service
and I want to build it all completely in
the IT realm but it's going
to affect the marketing team,
that is not going to have
good long term success.
Instead, I should get people from
the marketing team to work with us
as we build this service for them.
Because that way we understand better what
their roles are and
their intended outcomes.
We understand the way
they're going to work
with with this service right?
And so by collaborating across
we're going to get a better product.
The other part of this is it's
going to increase visibility.
They're going to
understand where we are in
the development and so it's
going to make them happier
and be able to understand
exactly where we are.
And if we're hitting
our milestones, and if
we're going to get the product out in time
to do what they need it.
We look at this there are people and
perspectives for successful collaboration
across all of your stakeholder groups.
You alone do not have the right answers.
But when you work with everybody together
we do come up with better solutions.
This means that the service provider needs
to work with their customers.
The developers need to
work with Operations,
the suppliers need to work
with the organization.
All of these collaborations are
going to give us a better end product.
Now, if we don't have transparency and
we don't give good visibility,
what ends up happening?
Well, we start getting this impression
that work is not a priority.
For example, the people in marketing that
I'm building this site for don't
necessarily know that I've got
50 other tasks that I'm working.
They're only tracking the one.
And they think theirs
is the most important.
And they might only want a
small improvement to their site.
Maybe they want to
change some font colors.
Well, is changing the
font colors more important
than fixing something that has been
down and is costing us money?
Well no, but they don't know that
because you're not being
transparent with them.
So by going through and showing them
and saying, "Hey I understand this is
your priority but it's not the
highest priority right now because
we have other more urgent tasks
that are being dealt with."
You got to be transparent this way.
Show people where your outages are.
Show them what you're working on and
give them an idea of when you're
going to get to their particular problem.
If you have an insufficient
amount of visibility
your work is going to lead
to poor decision making.
Because somebody above
you may not understand
what all the things are that
you're working on right?
And your boss comes in and says,
Hey the marketing director just came
and complained that the font is blue
but it should be green.
I need you to change that right now.
Drop everything you're doing."
And he might not even understand that
you're currently working
on a server outage
that's preventing your company from
being able to process
your credit card payments.
And that's costing you
say, $100,000 a day.
That would be more important to work on
than the green to blue font change right?
So this is the kind of idea of
things you need to think about.
Is making sure that everyone up and down
and across has visibility into what
the organization is working on.
This helps make sure everybody understands
the flow of work, they can identify the
bottlenecks and the excess
capacity that exists,
and we can uncover waste to make sure that
we're all working much more efficiently.
If you work in an agile development area
you may have something like a Kanban Board
which shows everything that people are
working on at that time.
What work is in progress, what work needs
to be worked on, and what
work was already completed.
That's a great way to increase visibility.
Another agile technique
that I've seen used is
what's known and an
"Information Radiator."
This is a bog board in a central area that
shows the progress map of
what's being worked on,
the risks that we've identified,
the issues that have come up,
and other important information.
This is being fully transparent and
showing everybody what you have
and what you're working on.
This is the ultimate in
visibility and collaboration.
So, as we think about
the key takeaways here
from collaboration in visibility,
I want you to think about this,
Collaboration does not mean consensus.
Now, what do I mean by that statement?
When it comes down to it
I want you to collaborate.
I want you to work as a team.
But at the end of the day,
somebody is in charge of this project.
Somebody is in charge of this service.
And that person gets
to make the decisions.
They should take any input
from everybody's suggestions.
But they're ultimately going to be the
ones making the decision.
And that's why
collaboration, communication,
and visibility is important.
Because that decision
maker is going to decide
which trajectory and how we're going to
build that service is going to be done.
Next, I also want you to remember that
communicating is important and
you have to communicate in a
way that the audience can hear.
If I'm working with marketing folks
I'm not going to talk to
them about bits and bites,
and all the technical
details of the service.
Instead, we're going to talk
about outputs and outcomes.
What do they hope to get from the service?
What are they going to put in?
And what are they expecting to get out?
Talk to them in a way they
can hear and understand.
And finally, remember that decisions
can only be made on the
visible parts of the project.
So if you don't have good visibility
and they don't understand all of your
pain points, all of your issues,
and all of your risks, then leadership
can't make the right decisions.
That's part of this
collaboration in visibility too.
Making sure the information is
getting up to the right people
at the right level to
make the right decisions.