- Continual improvement
and the guiding principles.
In this lesson I want to briefly discuss
how we can tie the idea of the
continual improvement model
back to our guiding principles.
You may have thought to yourself
while I was covering those
different steps hey, wouldn't
the
insert-the-name-of-your-guiding-principle
here,
be very useful during
this step, and guess what?
You would be right.
All of the principles are
applicable and relevant
at nearly every step of
the improvement initiative.
However, some of our
guiding principles are
especially relevant to certain steps.
So we're going to go through
the seven steps again
really quickly, one more time.
But this time we're
going to link them back
to our useful guiding
principle for each step
and we're going to figure out
which ones are the most useful.
First we have what is the vision.
When we're thinking about the vision
we want to have a focus on value.
We want to think about collaborating
and promoting visibility
so we can share that vision
across the organization.
And we want to think and work holistically
because we want to create a vision
that works for the entire organization,
not just for a single department.
Our second step, where are we now,
that's going to start with where we are.
So going back to the principle
of start where you are
is a great place.
Also, we want to collaborate
and promote visibility.
We want everyone to know
exactly where we are
and how we're performing.
Third, we want to go to
where do we want to be.
This is where we're going to progress
iteratively with feedback.
We're going to start setting out goals
and start some things into motion.
We also want to think
and work holistically
so we can think about
how it's going to affect
the entire organization.
We also want to think about
keeping it simple and practical.
When I start figuring out
how I'm going to do metrics and measures,
I don't want to have it very complicated.
I want something that's simple, practical,
and easy to measure.
Then I also want to think
about optimizing and automation
because I don't want to have to go
and check all the server spaces manually.
I want to figure out the
capacity metric automated,
and I want to do that
through an optimized method.
So these are going to be the four
that are most important to us.
In our fourth step, how do we get there,
we're starting to plan, right?
Well, when we plan we want to plan
to progress iteratively and with feedback.
We also want to make
sure we're collaborating
and promoting visibility of
that plan to everybody else.
We want to think and work
holistically so our plan is
going to affect everyone in
the organization properly.
And we want to keep our
plan simple and practical.
Our fifth step is where we take action.
When we take action
we're focusing on value.
What actions can we do to get us
the most value the quickest?
We also want to progress
iteratively and with feedback,
incorporating that feedback as we go,
and taking positive action
and continually move forward.
Then we want to collaborate
and promote visibility.
We want to make sure everybody knows
what actions we're taking
and why we're doing it.
Next, we're going to
move into the sixth step
which is did we get there.
When we're thinking
about did we get there,
we're again going to
have a focus on value.
We're going to collaborate
and promote the visibility
of the results so people know
yes, we did it, it worked;
or uh-oh, it didn't,
we need to try harder.
And we want to think and work holistically
again across the entire organization.
That brings us to our
seventh and final step.
How do we keep the momentum going?
Well, we're going to focus on value.
We're going to collaborate
and promote visibility,
sharing the message with everybody else.
We're going to think and work holistically
across the organization.
And now that we've got
something that's working,
we want to optimize it,
and once we optimize it
we want to automate it.
So optimize and automate would be
our last guiding principle.
So as you can see, by using
the continual improvement
along with the guiding principles,
you can create a solid framework
for successful service management.
These concept models
work exceptionally well
with Agile methodologies,
especially with that
progressive iterative feedback,
and we also can use it for
DevOps or development operations
and Lean frameworks as well.
It really does work well
and it is an excellent tool
to put in your toolbox as you move forward
into the real world.