- Design and transition.
This is the next value chain activity
we're going to talk about.
The purpose of the design
and transition value chain activity
is to insure that the
products and services
are continually meeting the stakeholder
expectations for quality,
cost and time to market.
This is where we're going to make sure
that we're figuring out
how this product is
actually going to be built.
This is where we come up
with all the designs for it
and then plan how we're going to move it
from an idea to actually being built
and put out into the marketplace.
There's lots of different inputs
into the design and transition phase.
When we start talking about
design and transition,
we have to take in things
like portfolio decisions
that come out of the planning area.
We also want to make sure we
understand the architectures
and the policies that plans has created.
We're going to take things from
the engagement area as well,
things like product and
service requirements
that engage has gotten from
the customers and the consumers
and other areas.
We also want to make sure that
we're taking in to account
the improvement initiatives
and the plans that come
out of the improve process.
We're also going to be looking
at all those improvement status reports
that came from improve.
So, we can figure out how do we design
things better next time.
We're also going to take a look
at all of our service
performance information
that comes out of our deliver
and support, and improve processes.
Are we meeting the service
targets that have been set?
Have we transitioned
something successfully?
All of these things are
things we need to consider
as we're designing and
transitioning our services
to take them from an
idea, and from a plan,
all the way out into a real usable thing
that is going to be delivered
to a consumer to use.
All of this happens inside
of this design and transition area.
Now, as we start looking at this,
we're also going to take in some things
that come from the
obtain and build process.
Things like what service
components are available.
Obtain and build already
has a lot of things that have been built.
Maybe as we're designing a new service,
we can reuse some of the things
that already exist and use
them in our new service.
And finally, we have to consider
the knowledge and information.
Now, knowledge and information
is going to come from
two different places.
First we have knowledge
and information about third party
service components from engage.
This is where we're
going to be considering
just like we did for obtain and build,
what things are available to use.
But now we're doing it
from a third party partner,
or a supplier perspective.
If we know that our supplier
has this type of capability
then we can help better design
and transition something
that works around that capability.
The other part of
knowledge and information
is the knowledge and information about
new and changed products and services.
This is what we're going to
get from our obtain and build.
As we have built and obtained things,
we're going to get the
product specifications,
the known errors and other information.
And all of that can serve as an input
into this design and transition activity.
Now, as far as outputs from this activity,
we're going to be
looking at getting things
like the requirement
and the specifications.
And passing those over
to the obtain and build.
So, as I've designed
this brand new service
that's going to do voucher
fulfillment for my students.
I need to come up with
what the requirements
and specifications are,
and pass that to the people
who are actually going to buy the servers
and buy the integrations, and
buy the automation software
that's going to allow that to occur,
inside of obtain and build.
Also, if we need to contract something,
we're going to go and
pass that over to engage.
We need to give them the contract
and the agreement
requirements that we need
for service level agreements,
service management agreements
and different contracts
for supplies and partners,
and send that through engage
out to those external entities.
Another output is any new and
changed products and services
that we're going to get from
the design and transition,
and we're going to pass
those and transition those
over to deliver and support.
Another thing we start talking about,
knowledge and information.
We get knowledge and information,
about new and changed
products or services.
We're going to pass that not
just to obtain and build,
but to all of the different parts
of the value chain activities.
Because plans need to know about it.
So, they can figure out what version two,
and three, and four is going to look like.
We need to pass that over to
design and transition ourself
as we design the next version.
We need to pass that
over to obtain and build
so they can build the
things as you design them.
You need to pass that over
to deliver and support,
so they know how to
support it when it breaks.
All the value chain activities
need that knowledge and information
about new or changed products.
And finally, we want to make sure
we're getting performance
information and improvement
opportunities out of the
design and transition
and back over to improve.
As we go through and we
design and build something,
we're going to find out that hey,
when we try to design X system,
we had problems one, two, and three.
We'll pass that over to improve
so, they can come up with ways
for us to improve our processes
and make it more efficient.
So, when we look at this
at the end of the day.
When we start talking
about design and transition
as an activity, think about
taking some idea from plans,
making it into what will be
built in obtain and build.
That's kind of the main focus.
But there's all these
other inputs and outputs
for this activity,
because those are things
that are going to happen
in a non-sequential manner
because things are are
happening all the times
in rapid development when
we're dealing with IT services.