- The service desk,
this is another practice
that you have to know in depth.
Luckily, it's probably the one you
already know the most about,
because most of us have dealt
with a service desk at
some point in our life.
The purpose of the
service desk practice is
to capture demand for incident resolution
and service requests.
It should also be the entry
point or single point of contact
for your service provider
for all of its users.
Now, once that issue
request or query is received
by the service desk, they're
going to acknowledge it,
classify it, own it, and act upon it.
This is the process and the workflow
that's generally used for
a service desk practice.
Now, the reason why this
is your single point is
because your service
desk is going to be able
to take in everything,
whether it's a change request,
whether it's a request for service,
or whether it's an incident,
and they can route it
to the appropriate desk.
Now, this isn't the way service desks
were originally designed, though.
The role of the service desk has changed.
It used to be that we
had a simple help desk
that was there to solve technical issues.
But more recently, it's
become the one-stop shop
for everything between the
users and the service provider.
This new focus of the service desk is
to provide support for
the people and business,
rather than simply the technical issues.
Our service desk has a major influence
on the users' experience
and how the users are going to
perceive the service provider.
And so, it's really important
that we get the service desk right.
Now, because of this, the
service desk has become
really important, in
fact, for most people,
this is one of the
first places you'll work
when you work in IT service management.
The service desk has to have
a practical understanding
of the entire organization
and how it functions,
because they are the gatekeeper.
Everything comes into
them, and then they have
to route it to the right place.
This service desk has to
be the empathetic link
between the service
provider and its users.
And that's why, a lot of times,
you'll find it's not even
the most technical people
that work at the service desk.
The service desk, instead,
focuses on excellent
customer service experiences
with personal contact when
it's needed by the user.
This is why soft skills
are really important
over technical skills for
service desk personnel.
Your support and development
teams need to work
in close collaboration
with your service desk,
passing information to
and from the service desk,
because the service desk is
the one who's going to interact
with your users and know the needs
that they have and the demands.
When the customer calls up and says,
hey, what's the current
status of my ticket,
they're talking to the service
desk, not the technician.
And so, that technician needs
to make sure they're feeding
that information back to the service desk
so the service desk can
engage with the customer.
Now, how does a user
access the service desk
for assistance, though?
Well, this is going to
depend on your organization.
But you may rely on phone
calls, service portals,
live chat with a real
person, a chatbot, email,
walk-in services, text messages,
social media messaging, or
even discussion board forums.
It really depends on how
your company wants to do it.
Now, there are four main
types of service desks.
They are local, centralized,
virtual, and follow the sun.
With a local service desk,
these are going to be co-located
within or physically close
to the users that it serves.
This often is going to
aid in communication,
provides a very clear
presence of a person there,
and it can support a local language
or cultural differences, if needed.
But the big problem is,
it's often inefficient
and expensive, because you're
tying up a single person
to be inside this office, and
they may not have enough calls
to justify 40 hours a week of work.
Now, a centralized service desk,
on the other hand, tries to avoid that.
They try to put all of the
service desk people in one area,
and everyone calls a single 1-800 number
or goes to a certain
website to get support.
This can be very efficient
and cost-effective,
'cause it allows fewer staff to deal
with a much higher volume of calls.
But it might also be necessary for you
to still maintain some
kind of local presence,
because some of the staff
can't fix the problems
on the other side of the world
if they can't touch the desk.
And so, we try to handle
anything that we can remotely
through the centralized service desk,
while still maybe having one or two people
at a local service desk.
Then, we have a virtual service desk.
Now, because of the way we
have technology these days,
particularly the internet
and Voice over IP,
and all the corporate
support tools that we have,
it's possible for us to
give you the impression
that there's a single
centralized service desk,
when in fact, a virtual
service desk is used instead.
This virtual service desk allows agents
to work from multiple,
geographically-dispersed
locations all around the world.
It requires some sophisticated technology,
but it does allow us to have access
from anywhere in the world,
and we can route those calls
to the right agent, no matter what time
of the day it is, across the globe.
Our fourth model is what
we call follow the sun.
Follow the sun is where global
corporations have to combine
two or more geographically-dispersed
service desks
to provide 24-hour
follow-the-sun coverage.
For example, maybe we
had three service desks,
one in London, one in New
York, and one in India.
By doing that, as it's daylight in London,
they would take the calls.
Once it's daylight in America,
the New York office would take the calls.
And then once it's daylight in India,
they would take the calls.
Regardless of where the
customer is calling from,
it would be whichever
service desk was open
at that particular time, so
we can give a full 24 hours
of coverage using those
three service desks.
That's the idea here when we
talk about a service desk.
We want to make sure our user
has a place they can call
and get support from any time they need.
Now, how do you run an
effective service desk?
Well, you need to have effective
supporting technologies.
This is especially true
when you use a centralized,
virtual, or follow the
sun service desk model.
These systems might be things
like telephone systems,
workflow systems, workflow management
and resource planning systems,
knowledge bases, call recording
and remote access tools,
dashboards and monitoring tools,
configuration management
systems, and many others.
Now, when you're going to
put a service desk together,
you have to fill it with employees, right?
What should you look for
when you're hiring employees?
Well, when you're hiring employees
for a service desk position,
you should look for people
who have empathy, emotional intelligence,
effective communication skills,
excellent customer service skills,
an understanding of the business
priorities and the ability
to conduct incident
analysis and prioritization.
Notice, in that list,
I didn't highlight a strong
technical capability, did I?
Instead, a service desk may be technical,
but most of the time,
it doesn't have to be.
Most service desks are more focused
around the customer support
and customer service aspects.
They leave the technical details
to the higher level of tiered support
that's going to come in
when something's wrong.
Now, to finish up this
lesson, let's talk about
how the support desk integrates
with the value chain activities.
First, improve, the
service desk activities are
constantly monitoring
and evaluating support
for continual improvement,
alignment, and value creation.
They're going to get feedback from users,
collect that, and pass it
to the continual improvement
process or practice.
When we talk about engage,
the service desk is there
as our main channel for tactical
and operational engagement with users.
They're the ones contacting and talking
with the users on a daily basis.
When we talk about design and transition,
the service desk is going
to provide a channel
for communicating with users
about new and changed services.
The service desk, again,
is that engage part, right?
So we're going to get this
information from design
and transition, and pass
it out to everybody else.
Also, our service desk
personnel can participate
in release planning, testing,
and early live support.
When we think about obtain and build,
the service desk can also be involved
in acquiring service
components that are used
to fulfill service requests
and resolve our incidents.
Maybe somebody's hard drive has crashed.
You as a service desk analyst might go
and order the new hard drive.
That's part of obtain and build.
And finally, deliver and support.
This is where the service
desk is really focused.
The service desk is the coordination point
for managing all of the incidents,
all the problems, and all
of the service requests.
And so, it's really important
that you get it right
by making sure your service desk
has the right people employed,
that have been at the right training,
and they understand how the
whole organization works
to get the best value for your end users.