- Service Design.
This practice is another one
inside this category that
we're going to discuss
for your general awareness
but it isn't covered
on the exam.
Now service is the practice
of designing products
and services that are fit for purpose,
Fit For Use and that it can be delivered
by the organization and its ecosystem.
Let's break that down a little bit,
cause there's a couple
of key terms in there
that we might recognize.
First, Fit for Purpose.
What does that remind you of?
That's right, utility.
Fit for Purpose is utility.
We want to make sure that our products
has good utility.
They do what we need them to do.
We also have Fit For
Use in this definition.
What's Fit For Use?
Well that's warranty.
We want to make sure
that it meets all of the
standards and requirements
that we were given
as part of our warranty.
And then finally we have this
delivered by the organization
and its ecosystem,
what's that talking about?
It's saying that we have
the capability of doing it.
For example we are a training company.
We have a lot of
capabilities that we can do,
should we be doing video hosting?
Well that's probably not one
of our core capabilities.
So instead, we're not going
to design that service
that we are going to do it in house,
instead we would design it to outsource
that part of our brand.
That way, we can still
make sure we have a service
that is Fit For Use, fit for purpose,
and it can be delivered
effectively by our ecosystem
meaning our partners and suppliers,
as opposed to us the organization ourself.
That's the idea with service design,
you want to think about
your products and services
and how you can best build
them and design them,
so that you're getting the
best warranty and utility,
for your organization.