- Service Configuration Management.
This is another practice you have to
recall the definition for.
The purpose of this service
configuration management
practice is to ensure
that accurate and reliable
information about the
configuration of services,
and the CIs known as configuration
items that support them,
is available when and where it's needed.
So when I think about this,
first we want to talk about,
what is a CI?
Well, a CI is any component
that needs to be managed
in order to deliver an IT service.
This might be a server,
it might be a switch.
It might be a desktop,
it might be a laptop.
All of these could be configuration items.
The way that we track these is as a single
configuration item like
your desktop computer
with Windows 10 and eight gigabytes of RAM
and a one terabyte hard
drive is a single CI,
in most cases, promotes your organization.
So, this is the idea here
that we have to think about
as we're tracking our service
configuration management.
Now, as we figure out what our
service configuration management is
and we know what all these CIs are
and how they're configured,
that means any time we want
to make a change to them
through change control,
this is going to feed back
into the service configuration management
so we can update our database
and know exactly what devices
and what assets we have all
throughout our organization
so we can get the most value from them.