- Business analysis, this practice is one
that you don't need to know for the exam,
but we're covering it for
your general awareness.
Business analysis is the practice
of analyzing a business or
some element of that business
to define its needs,
and recommend solutions
to address those needs, or
to solve a business problem.
This will help you create
value for your stakeholders.
So when I think about business analysis,
you're thinking about this
outside of the IT realm.
Normally you're thinking
about dollars and cents.
How can I solve some
sort of business problem?
And that might be with a
technological solution,
but it might be with an
organizational solution,
or it might be with a new marketing plan,
or whatever it happens to be.
The business analysis, the reason it's put
under this technical
heading inside this category
is because it often relies
heavily on lots of facts
and lots of figures, and
they use a lot of technology
to do the analysis, but
the actual analysis itself
is more of a management function
than a technical function.