- Workforce and talent management.
This is our final practice as
a general management practice,
and this is going to
finish up this section.
This practice again is
not covered by the exam,
but it's one that you probably deal with
on a daily basis.
Workforce and talent
management is there to ensure
that an organization has
the right people with the
appropriate skills and
knowledge, in the correct roles
to support its business objectives.
This practice covers a
wide variety of activities,
focused on successfully
engaging with the organization's
employees and people-based resources,
including how to plan for them,
recruit them, onboard them,
help them in their
learning and development,
ensure you're doing proper
performance measurement of them,
and doing succession planning.
There is a lot to this, in fact the
entire field of human
resources rests inside of
workforce and talent management.
Now, we're not going to go into
all of the details of this,
but think about it this
way, your company is
really nothing without its people.
We want to make sure we
have the best people,
and that means we have to figure out how
we're going to plan to recruit them.
We need to recruit them,
we need to hire them
and bring them onboard, we
want to make sure that they're
being adapted over time,
by learning and developing
their resources, for better abilities,
and, we want to measure
their abilities to make sure
we're getting the resources
out of them that we expect,
and they're performing
to the level they should.
All of this are things
that are important inside
workforce and talent management,
because people are usually considered the
number one resource of any company.
I know in our company,
if we lost a couple of
our lead people, we would
be in really dire straits.
So we want to make sure we
have the right people and
we're developing new people
to take over those roles
when those people decide to leave us,
and that's called succession planning.