- Technical management practices.
This is our third and final category
of practices under ITIL 4.
Technical management
practices have been adapted
from technology management domains
for service management purposes
by expanding or shifting
their focus from a technology
solution to an IT service.
Under ITIL 4, there are only
three technical management
practices covered.
These are the deployment management,
infrastructure and platform management,
and software development
and management practices.
For the exam, only the
deployment management practice,
though, is testable,
and it's only examinable
at the recall level.
For that reason, this is going to be
a very short and quick
section of the course.