- Portfolio management, our next practice
we're going to discuss for your general
knowledge is portfolio management.
This is the practice of
ensuring that an organization
has the right mix of
programs, projects, products,
and services to execute its strategy
within its funding and
resource constraints.
Now, what does this really means?
Let's take my company for
example Dion Training.
There are a lot of different
products, projects, programs
and services that we could be using.
We could be doing a
lot of different things
but we have to figure out
what works with our strategy.
For example, we might make
practice exam courses,
we might make video courses, we might
do live training, we might create apps
in the app store, we might write a book.
There's lots of things that we can do.
And in our first couple of years,
we did a lot of those things;
in fact all of those things.
But over time we figured out
where our true strengths were.
And we figured out what our
vision for the company was,
and we build a strategy around it.
So now, based on that
strategy, we've assigned
certain funding, and
resource and strengths,
the biggest resource constraint is really
the amount of people we have
that can teach this stuff,
and having the right
people on staff to do it,
and so we're limited in the
amount of stuff we can do.
So, based on those
restraints, we figure out
what is the proper mix of
programs, projects, products
and services to give
you the best experience
and give you the most bang for your buck.
For us for example,
inside the ITIL framework,
we do the foundation of
exams and we're going to
do all of the ITIL for exams.
That was a decision we
made, but we are not doing
all of the ITIL three,
intermediate certifications,
because those were coming to end of life
in the next 12 to 18 months
and so it didn't make sense
for our vision and our strategy
to put a lot of resources
into building those exams when
those exams were going to be
sunset in just 12 or 18 months.
Whereas ITIL four is brand new
and will last for many years to come.
That's the idea inside your organization.
You need to think about
what is the right mix
of products and services and programs
and portfolio management
helps you do that.
You figure out exactly
what you want to do,
and then you build towards that.