- In this lesson, we're
going to discuss costs.
Now, the cost of something
is the amount of money
that spent on a particular activity or
a particular resource.
While cost is usually
expressed financially,
it can also be expressed
in nonfinancial ways too.
For example, when we
create a new course here,
we actually measure the cost of the course
in the number of hours spent creating it.
A typical course, like this one,
might require 400 or 500
hours worth of effort
across our entire staff.
This usually is described
in either the measurement
of man hours, or FTE.
Man hours are also known as person hours,
because we want to be
equal opportunist here.
FTEs, on the other hand,
stands for Full Time Equivalent.
And it's used to measure
things based on a single
employee, who works 40 hours per week,
for an entire year.
This equates to roughly
2,000 hours worth of work.
So, if we need to run a web server
to host all of our courses,
that might require half of an FTE.
Or one-half of a person's
annual available work hours
for the entire year.
This describes the number of FTEs, or
Full Time Equivalent
employees that are required
in order to undertake
a particular activity.
Now, while I can measure
things from a an hours
of effort perspective,
this does ultimately translate
back to financial cost.
Each team member on my
team earns a salary.
And if it takes somebody
half of their entire year
to run that web server,
that means half of their salary is tied up
in keeping that web server up and running.
So, it does end up going
back to cost eventually.
But, when we look at our reports,
we're actually more
concerned with the amount
of time things take,
than the amount of money
we spend on 'em.
Now, depending on your organization,
you may choose to measure things based
on the man hours, the
person hours, the FTEs,
or using actual dollar and
cents that are expended.
Either way, the service provider is aiming
to reduce or remove costs,
when they provide a service.
So, if a service provider
can save you more money
than their service is going to cost you,
you're certainly going to look at using
that service, right?
I know I would.
For example,
my internet service provider
has varying speeds available,
that we can choose to
use here at our office.
We can choose to spend $50
per month for 100 megabit
per second connection.
Or, $100 a month for a 1,000 megabit per
second connection.
Which one should we choose?
Well, in our case, we
upload a lot of large files,
because of all the videos that we produce.
And when we looked at the speed that we
were going to purchase,
we decided that paying twice
as much money per month,
for a ten-times increase in
speed, was well worth it.
Because it saves our staff a lot of time
uploading those files.
So, it became an easy decision.
Because spending $50 more per month on the
faster internet connection,
made my staff much more productive.
And it saved us a lot
of wasted labor hours.
And this more than made
up for the additional cost
in the labor savings
that we were able to get.
That's the idea when you look at costs.
If you're going to outsource a service,
or you're going to pay for something,
you want to make sure
it's giving you more value
than what it's costing you.
In our case, spending
twice as much on internet,
gave us 10 times more value.
And so it was definitely worth doing.