- The next value chain
activity we're going to cover
is the engage value chain activity.
The purpose of the engage
value chain activity
is to provide a good understanding
of the stakeholder needs, to
ensure continual engagement
with all of the stakeholders is occurring,
and to promote good transparency
and good relationships
with all of our stakeholders.
Really, when we talk about engage,
think about going out and
talking to other people.
That's what we're really doing
at the heart of this engage process.
This is going to be going
out to our stakeholders
both internally and externally
to our organization.
So when I think about the different inputs
to the engage activity here,
I'm thinking about the
product and service portfolio
that I'm going to get from plans.
When I get the product
and service portfolio,
I then can think about, who do I need
to start engaging with?
Who needs to know about this new roadmap?
Who needs to know that there's
a new product coming online?
Who needs to know what they
can provide into that service
or to that part of that service portfolio?
That's the whole idea
there, is communicating that
inward and outward across the organization
and out to your partners.
Also, we're going to be looking for inputs
for high-level demand for
services and products.
This is something we're going to see
usually from our customers,
and so as part of engage,
we're going to listen to our
customers and what they want.
For example, if I have a hundred students
who reach out to me and
tell me, hey, Jason,
I want you to start offering
X certification product,
we might start listening to that
and go build that certification,
and put that into our plans
and move that throughout
our whole lifecycle, right?
It all depends on what the demand is
for our services and our products,
and we listen to our customers on that.
One of the reasons why we
offer the PRINCE2 certification
is because a lot of my
IDOL students had said,
hey, I want to get a project
management certification.
Will you offer PRINCE2?
And so we went out, because
we had a large enough demand,
and we did that.
Another input is the
request and feedback you get
from your customers.
As you go through this course,
we ask for reviews and feedback from you.
If you tell us that you don't like it
because Jason talks too
long in his examples,
then next time we build a
course, we'll use less examples.
We've gotten a lot of that type
of feedback over the years,
of things we can change and make better,
and we implement that each and every time.
You want to do the same
thing with your IT services.
You're always wanting to get
feedback from your customers
and then using that feedback,
you can make a better product.
Next, we also want to
think about the incidents,
the service requests, and
feedback from your end users.
This may be different from
your customers, right?
In my case, my customers are my users,
but if we look at this
from a large IT stance,
I might have a customer who buys a service
for hundreds of users underneath them.
In that case, I need to think
about the feedback differently
from the customer level
and from the user level.
When you take all that input in,
it helps you in your engagement
to figure out what you're doing right,
and then you can pass that information
over to the improve process,
so they can then work it
into improvement plans.
Also, another input we have is information
on the completion of user support tasks,
from delivery and support.
One of the big things that your engage
is going to be working closely
with, is delivery and support,
because in deliver and support,
that's where your service
desk comes into play.
That's where your
operations comes into play.
That's where you're
going to be reaching out
and touching your end users,
and getting their feedback directly,
so being able to look at that
and feeding that information back
through deliver and support,
into the engage process,
and from engage, out to the other parts
of the service value
chain, is really important.
Next, we also want to consider on input
of our market opportunities.
As we look at the market,
and we see what the demand looks
like and the opportunities,
we can then figure out what our current
and potential customers
and users might want,
and based on that and seeing that
and engaging with the marketplace,
we can determine and
feed that back into plans
to put it into the overall
strategy for the company.
Another input is making sure
we have cooperation opportunities
and feedback being provided
by not just our customers and our users,
but also from our partners
and our suppliers.
For example, we rely on
AWS, or Amazon Web Services,
to host our website currently.
We want to make sure we have
a good partnership with them,
or at least a good supplier relationship,
where we can talk to them and
figure out what other services
do you offer that might
be able to help us?
What type of opportunities exist?
And understanding those
opportunities for cooperation
and feedback from our
partners and suppliers
can help us to better supply
a service to our end user.
Another input we have is our contracts
and our agreement requirements.
As we look at all of those
from across the entire value chain,
we also are going to be
doing all of the engagement.
Any time we're talking about
contracts and agreements,
you can be assured we're talking
about the engage activity,
because we're reaching
outside of our organization
to make that contract happen.
Another thing we're
going to get as an input
to our engage activity is
the knowledge and information
about new and changed
products and services,
both from design and transition
and obtain and build.
You'll notice some of
these things have happened
in multiple different activities, why?
Because this is a coordinated
and interlinked effort.
Next, we have our
knowledge and information
about our third party service components,
from suppliers and partners.
Just like we did before,
we have that again here
inside the engage activity.
We also want to make sure
we're getting product
and service information
from across the lifecycle
and from the deliver and support team.
As they feed that into us,
we can then coordinate it,
and push it out across all
of the different pieces
and the different activities
in our service value chain.
Next, we also have our
improvement initiatives and plans.
We're going to get those from improve,
and as the engagement folks,
what are we going to do with those?
Well, we're going to
tell people about them.
Hey, students, we're improving the course
and releasing a new course on X day.
We get that from the plans,
and then we pass it out
to our customers, our
users, and our consumers.
And finally, we also want to
get improvement status reports
from improve, and then again,
we can share that information
out as part of engage.
When I think about engage,
I always like to think
about telling people something.
I'm communicating with somebody, right?
So what are some of the outputs we have
when we talk about engage?
Well, we have consolidated
demands and opportunities.
As we collected all that
information from the marketplace
and our customers, we're
now going to turn around,
consolidate it, and pass it over to plans
so they can put that into
our overarching plans.
We're also going to look at our product
and service requirements that we got
and we're going to give those
to design and transition
so they can build better services.
We're also going to take
the user support tasks
and requirements and give those
over to delivery and support
so they can actually provide
the end users what they need,
so if you as a student
come to the engage part
of our company, and say,
I need more study guides,
then we can then pass that
over to design and
transition, who can design it,
then we can give it to obtain
and build, who will build it,
and then we give it to
deliver and support,
who will deliver it to you as a student,
and it works that way
where these processes are interrelated.
We're also going to have an output
of improvement opportunities
and stakeholder feedback
as we collect all of that,
because we're the ones interacting
with all of those external organizations.
We're going to take that and pass it
over to the improve process or activity,
so they can work with it.
We're also going to get things like change
or project initiative requests,
and we're going to get all
of those, consolidate them,
and pass them over to the obtain/build.
Again, we're dealing
with contracts, right?
And agreements, and if we get
those contracts and agreements
from the external and internal suppliers,
we're then going to pass those
over to obtain and build,
and design and transition, so
that they can get the services
and products that those
contracts rely upon.
We're also going to be
looking at the output
of knowledge and information
about our third-party service components,
because we collected all that information,
but we as engage aren't
going to do much with it.
Instead, we want to pass
it to the plans folks,
the design folks, the transition folks,
the obtain and build folks,
the deliver and support folks.
All of them need this information,
and we're the people who collect it,
so we're responsible
for passing it back out.
And finally, one of
the things we collected
was service performance reports, right?
We got all of that information
from all of the different
parts of the service,
and now we want to communicate
that back out to our customers.
Hey, our availability is 99.999%
as measured by X, Y and Z.
Let me give that report to the customers
so they know what they're getting.
That's the idea in engage.
Engage is the glue that makes
all of this service work.
It's all of the communication that occurs.
Things come in, things get processed,
and things get pushed out,
to and from all the different
activities, processes,
customers, stakeholders, consumers,
and suppliers and partners.
All of that works because
engage is at the center of it.
It's all the people who make
the communication happen.