- Categories of practices.
Over the next three
sections of the course,
we're going to cover all 34
of the ITIL four practices.
These 34 individual practices
are divided up into three categories.
General management practices,
service management practices,
and technical management practices.
This begs the question though,
what exactly is a practice?
You may remember from our
service value system lesson
that there was a portion of the diagram
that called out these practices.
Well, a practice is a set
of organized resources
designed for performing work
or accomplishing an objective.
Each practice is going to support
multiple service value chain activities,
and it includes resources based on
the four dimensions of
IT service management.
So, in this section of the course,
we're going to focus on the
first 14 practices of ITIL four.
These are known as the
general management practices.
But, before we dive into those
general management practices,
let me cover what you
need to know for the exam,
because we're going to
cover a lot of information
during the next three
sections of the course.
First, you need to be
able to recall the purpose
of 15 of the ITIL practices.
I'm not going to list each
of those 15 right now.
But instead, as we cover each
practice in it's own video,
I'm going to tell you whether you need
to recall it for the exam or not.
For these 15 practices though,
you need to remember the definition,
since these are at the recall level
of knowledge for the exam.
Just as a reminder,
there are 34 practices
inside of ITIL four,
and while I'm going to cover
each of these at least briefly,
this is going to help you get
a general awareness of
each of the 34 of them,
you only really need to know 15 of them
for the foundation level of the exam.
And of these 15, there are six of them
that you have to know more in depth.
Again, when I cover
those specific practices,
I'm going to remind you that
these are very important
and you're going to have
to pay more attention
than just knowing the definition.
In fact, as we start
each of these sections
covering the different
categories of practices,
we're going to first cover the practices
that you have to know in depth.
Then, we're going to cover the practices
that you simply need to
recall the definition for.
And then, we're going to
finish out each section
with the practices that aren't covered
by the foundation exam, and instead,
are being covered just for
your general awareness.
As we go through these three
sections of the course,
we're also going to cover the seven terms
that are under the recall level
of knowledge for the exam.
And we're going to do this throughout
our discussion of these practices.
These are the IT asset,
event, configuration item,
change, incident,
problem, and known error.
When we get to them in the lessons,
I'm going to remind you again
that these are the terms
that you have to memorize
the definitions for.
So, with all of that said,
let's dive in to the general
management practices.