- Governance, in this
lesson we're going to
briefly revisit the concept of governance.
And you see it here inside
the service value system.
It's going to be part
of that internal piece
that takes our opportunities
and our demands,
works it through that middle
of the service value system
to come out the other side as value.
Now what is governance?
Well governance is the means by which
an organization is
directed and controlled.
I used the example
earlier, if you think about
your government, like the US
Congress, they do governance.
They provide the laws and regulations
that the rest of the company will follow.
Well inside of your organization,
you run governance as well.
Governance may be set up
by those in the C-suite,
your CEO, your CFO, your CIO, your CSO
or other high level executives.
You're going to come up with the way the
organization is going to
be directed and controlled
and then pass that down through governance
down to things like guidelines
and regulations and standards.
ITIL at its core is a
framework for governance.
But it's not a directive
It's not going to tell you
that you have to follow
everything the way that ITIL say it is.
ITIL instead is a best practice
and you can write your
governance based on ITIL.
Now when we look at governance
at a large macro-level
in your organization,
it's the way you're going to do things.
You may come up with
processes and activities
and procedures for how
you're going to handle
something like change management.
Every time you want to
have a new server installed
it's got to go through this process
that has 15 different steps and these many
different approvals at this level.
That is part of governance.
The way you're going
to control and organize
and direct your organization.
That's the whole concept.
So if you think about governance like laws
but within your organization,
that's kind of the big concept of it.
And it is part of this
service value system
because that governance is
what you're going to build
your processes and your activities around
to make sure their inline with
the governances you put out
at that high level of your organization.