- Organizations and people.
When we discuss the
concept of an organization
inside of ITIL 4, the
organization is not limited
to a service provider organization,
or an internal information
technology organization,
or even an information
technology organization at large.
Instead, we're just looking at this
as a generic organization.
But, what exactly is
an organization anyway?
Well ITIL 4 defines an organization
as a person or a group of people that has
its own functions with responsibilities,
authorities, and relationships,
to achieve its objectives.
Notice this definition is pretty generic,
and again this is done on purpose
by the creators of ITIL,
because it allows ITIL
to be more widely used and
adapted to any organization.
In ITIL 4 there are two basic roles
that an organization can fulfill.
A service provider is a role performed
by an organization in
a service relationship
to provide services to consumers.
Conversely, a consumer is a role performed
by an organization in the relationship
that uses or consumes those services.
Organizations vary in size
and complexity as well.
Now, organizations can also
vary in their legal structure
in that they can be a single person,
a team, or even a complex
multinational corporation.
What really bounds an
organization together
is a set of common objectives,
relationships, and authorities.
Now, this may seem strange,
especially when
considering a single person
that can act as an organization,
but it really does work
this way in the real world.
When I created my company,
Dion Training Solutions,
it was created as a sole
proprietorship originally.
I was a single person
operating as an organization
in all of my business relationships.
Now, an organization
can be a team of people
working towards a common objective too.
As my company has gotten bigger,
we now have two teams
of people which make up
two distinct organizations
within the company.
One is the training team, which I lead,
and the other is our operations team,
which my director of operations leads.
Now, the director of operations
happens to be my wife,
but she has her own team
and people who work for her.
This is an example of how people organized
around common goals within a
larger business organization
to achieve common objectives
in a coordinated method.
Now, in most of these cases,
the common objectives are
usually trying to create
value for the consumer, but the way value
is actually achieved
has changed in ITIL 4.
Previously, value was considered something
that was delivered from a service provider
to the consumer of the service.
But this wasn't entirely accurate
the way it was done in the real world.
In fact, it was so
inaccurate that saying like
"Delivering something it easy,
"but delivering something
of value is hard,"
began to spring up all throughout
the IT service management industry.
So instead, ITIL 4 recognizes that value
must be cocreated by the service
provider and the consumer.
Now, what does this mean
for us in the real world?
Well, let's take this
course as an example.
My team and I have spent a lot of time
preparing this course,
filming this course,
editing this course, and
publishing this course
so that you could get value from it.
And I truly believe
this is the best course
that's out there today.
And as such I place a lot of value
on the content, and I hope you do as well.
But, let's look at it from your
perspective as the consumer.
Is this course truly valuable?
Well, you've exchanged some
of your hard earned money
to get access to this training,
so you probably feel that
it has some amount of value
or you wouldn't have given me your money
to access this course.
Now if you're like most students,
you probably are going to measure this
based on the fact of seeing if it actually
prepares you to pass the foundation exam.
But, for you to achieve
that desired value,
passing the exam, we have to
co-create that value together.
As the supplier, I've provided
you with all the videos,
the quizzes, the practice
exam, the web server,
access to the training,
downloadable PDFs, all of that.
But, as the consumer, you have to actually
watch those videos, study the definitions,
practice with the quizzes,
take the practice exam.
Not to mention, you have to have a laptop,
a tablet, or a phone, to
even access these videos
and be able to watch
them, as well as a stable,
high speed internet connection.
To achieve the desired outcome
in value from this course
we both have to work
hard and meet our ends
of this obligation.
That's the idea of co-creation of value.
By the service provider, me and my team
and you the consumer.
This is how it work inside of ITIL 4.
Now, as much as I'd love to be able
to simply create the value for you
as soon as you make the purchase,
we don't have that technology yet
to instantly load up the
information into your head.
This isn't The Matrix after all.
Instead, you have to have to help me
to create the value we both want,
which is for you to pass
your certification exam
on the first attempt.
As the supplier, I can try really hard
to deliver that value,
but if you as the consumer
don't actually cooperate
and turn on the videos
and watch them, well then the value simply
won't be created because
the value is the outcome.
It's you getting that certification done.
This is why relationships
between organizations
such as the supplier and the consumer
have become very complex.
In the simplest form, the provider would
deliver a service, the consumer
would pay for the service,
and the provider then uses that money
to create more services,
while the consumer
uses the current service they paid for.
Now, if both sides are
getting the value they desire
from that transaction, then
this is mutually beneficial.
If the value is not achieved by either
of these sides though, then it's likely
that this relationship
will soon come to an end,
and no more value will emerge from it.
Unfortunately, the real
world is much more complex
than the simple example of
value creation I just gave.
At any moment an organization
can be a consumer
and a provider for multiple services.
Let's take my organization for example.
I'm a supplier in relation to you,
but I'm also a consumer in my relationship
with my web hosting provider.
These are just different hats being worn
by my organization, depending
on which perspective
we're looking at things from.
This means that when my organization
is acting as a consumer,
we co-create value
by consuming services, and when
we're acting as a provider,
we co-create value by providing service
to other organizations and people.
Organizations recognize
that value is cocreated
through an active
collaboration between providers
and consumers, as well
as other organizations
that are part of the relevant
service relationships.
These service provider
and service consumer roles
are the two generic roles that
an organization can fulfill.
People though can fulfill
three other types of roles.
This is the role of a user,
a customer, and a sponsor.
The first role is that of a user.
A user is simply a person
who uses a service.
The second role is that of a customer.
A customer is the person
who defines the requirements
for a service, and takes responsibility
for the outcomes of the
service consumption.
The third role is that of a sponsor.
A sponsor is a person
who authorizes the budget
for service consumption.
The term sponsor is also
used in some organizations
to describe an organization or department,
or an individual that provides financial
or other support for an initiative.
While these are the three roles,
these roles could be
fulfilled by different people
or all three of these
roles could be fulfilled
by the same person.
Let's consider a simple
scenario where all three roles
are going to be filled by the same person.
Maybe it's been a few years and you decide
to buy a brand new car.
Let's say you're all excited about
all the technological improvements
that have been made in the world of cars,
and you decide to get one that can perform
semi-autonomous driving, like a Tesla.
As a user, you're really excited to drive
your new Tesla because it
has so many cool features
like the autopilot, the
comfortable leather seats
and a really fast electric motor.
As a customer though, you
may not see a big difference
in the features between
a Model S and a Model 3,
so you're trying to decide which model
best meets your requirements
and helps you achieve
your outcomes most efficiently
when you're consuming the service
of this semi autonomous vehicle.
Now in your third role as a sponsor
you start to weigh the cost of the Model 3
versus the Model S, and
you try to determine
which one should you budget for
in order to meet the needs
of your semi-autonomous car
that's going to drive you
from point A to point B
and get you to work each day.
Now, all three of these roles
have competing interests.
The user wants the best features
when they consume the service,
but they'd probably be happy with either
the Model 3 or the Model S.
They're both really nice cars after all.
The customer in you actually defines
the requirements though for your new car.
They define that one has to be able
to drive semi-autonomously.
They want one that can drive
at least 200 miles before
needing to be refueled
or recharged, and other kind
of requirements like that.
Your third role is that of the sponsor,
and this is where things
come from a cost perspective.
While I might like the Model S,
it sells for almost $100,000.
Can the Model 3 still meet all
of the customer's requirements
even though it sells for only 60,000?
Well, if so, then the
sponsor would rather choose
the less expensive option.
So, whenever you buy yourself a new car,
you're really balancing these three roles
before you make the decision,
and you're doing this
all inside your own head.
Now, let's consider a
little bit differently.
Let's say we're going to
buy a car for somebody else.
My daughter is almost to the age
where she's old enough to drive,
and so she's going to be
the user in this scenario
because she wants her parents
to buy her first car for her.
She doesn't care how much it costs.
She doesn't have any requirements.
She just knows that she's
going to consume the resource
and she needs to be
able to get in and drive
from point A to point B.
In this case, this
means that she can drive
wherever she wants, and
she'll be able to drive
whatever her mother and
I decide to buy for her.
Now, my wife on the other hand
is going to be our customer.
She's going to set the
requirements for this service,
the car in our particular example,
and this service is going to
have to meet those requirements,
and she's going to be the
one taking responsibility
for our daughter's actions
when she consumes that service.
In this case, when our daughter is driving
my wife is going to be
responsible for whatever happens
because she is the customer.
Now, my wife may create some
requirements for this new car.
She might say that it
has to have four seats,
that it has to have four doors.
Maybe it has to have a
driver and passenger airbag.
The car might have to be
less than 10 years old.
Whatever the requirements
is that she decides,
she has that ability
because she is the customer.
Now, our third role is the sponsor,
and this is the person who is
going to pay for the initiative.
In this case, the one of
buying a car for my daughter,
I am going to be the sponsor.
I am going to have to pay for this thing.
I have created a budget for this car.
Let's say, no more than $10,000,
and that means the customer, my wife,
can pick any car that
she wants for the user,
my daughter, but this car has to be
within that budget of $10,000.
So, I guess my wife isn't
going to be able to go out
and buy her a brand new car,
even though the customer
may want that, or the user may want that.
Instead, the customer has been allocated
a specific budget, and they
have to stay within that.
So, this is the same type
of thing that happens
in business all of the time.
Sometimes in business you get to act
as one, two, or three of these roles
depending on the scenario.
For example, you may define what is needed
for your business team, and
you may have the authority
to allocate and authorize the budget
for those requirements,
and you're going to be
both the customer and
sponsor in that case.
But, your team members
are going to be the users
because they're going to use what you buy.
This is actually a great position to be in
because the person authorizing the budget
is also the person making
the requirements decisions.
Unfortunately though, in a
lot of large organizations,
the person who authorizes
the budget for an IT service
is not a customer or a
user of that service.
And this type of disconnect
can actually cause problems
because the sponsor who
funds the requirements
and the customer who
creates those requirements
often have arguments over what
those requirements should be.
Because, the sponsor's
focused on the efficiency
and cost savings, whereas the customers
are focused on the
requirements and the users
usability of this service.
This can create a gap between the user
and the customer's interest as well.
As a service provider,
it's our responsibility
to recognize these three generic roles
on a consumer side, and to
work with them appropriately
to ensure the right
service is being delivered
and supplied to meet those needs.
This means we need to
ensure that the financials
work for the sponsor,
that the requirements
are met for the customer, and the users
get what they expect in
usability of our service.
At the end of the day, we want to achieve
user satisfaction, customer satisfaction,
and sponsor satisfaction
because when all three come together
we're more likely to have repeat business
from the consumer's organization.