- The next practice we're going to discuss
is Service Financial Management.
Now, service financial management, again,
is one that's just for
your general knowledge.
It's not covered on the exam.
This practice is focused on
supporting the organization
strategies and plans
for service management.
It does this by ensuring
that the organization's
financial resources and their investments
are being used effectively.
So if you've ever decided
to make the recommendation
to your boss that we should
go and buy X, Y, Z system
or X, Y, Z software product
and install it in our system,
at some point, he's probably asked you,
"Well, how much is it going
to cost and is it worth it?"
Service Financial Management
is that whole backend process
to verify that we have enough money
to buy the things that you want to get
and that what you want to
get is going to give us a
good return on our investment
so that we can actually
use our capital in the most effective way.
There's a ton of things that we can buy
with our organization's money.
We want to make sure
we're doing it responsibly
and that we're going to get
the best bang for our buck.
Service Financial Management
is all of those backend things
that the accountants are going to do
and the business analysts are going to do
to ensure that our company
remains financially solvent
and that we're able to continue operating
because we have money
to pay our employees,
pay for our services,
pay for our contract,
and keep the business afloat.