- Did we get there?
We have come a long way in
our improvement journey.
For us, it may have been
10 or 20 minutes of video,
but in real life, we may
have just spent three
to six months to create and
implement the improvement
we wanted to see.
Now it's time to check in on our progress
and see if we made a positive
or a negative change.
The sixth step, did we get there,
involves checking our new normal.
Basically, where are we today,
and comparing it against
the original baseline
from step two that we took at
the beginning of the process.
Too often, once an improvement
plan is set into motion,
people just start to assume
that the expected benefits
are going to be achieved.
They run off and they start
on the next initiative
and they stop measuring or
worrying about the current one
you're working on.
In the real world though,
the journey to reaching
an improved state is usually
found among the pathway lined
with a lot of obstacles.
Success is simply not guaranteed.
It must be measured and
it must be validated.
So, in step six, we're going
to take another measurement
just like we did back in step two.
We're going to use the
exact same processes
and then we're going to
compare those two measurements.
Let's go back and use
our college GPA example.
We wanted to reach a 3.3 GPA
by the end of the semester.
If we just looked at your report card
and we saw you earned
a 3.4, then we did it!
You've improved your score
and took it up above a 3.3.
That's great.
Now on the other hand,
if you earned a 3.2,
we missed the mark.
Based on our new measurements,
we now have a new baseline
and we can determine
what we need to do next.
This is where we pick
up in the next lesson,
the seventh and final step.