- How do we get there?
It's finally time to
plan for some changes.
Up to this point, we've
agreed upon the vision,
we've created our baseline to determine
what the current state
actually looks like,
and then we determine what the proper
goals and metrics are for us to aim for.
Now, we want to ask the fourth question,
known as step four, how do we get there?
So in step four, we are
going to create a plan.
This plan may be
straightforward and direct
and provide us the quickest route
to completing a single,
simple improvement,
or it could be more complex,
more involved, and made up of a series
of twisting roads or starts stops.
The most effective approach
to executing the improvement
may not be clear at the beginning
of our planning efforts.
You may not know what right looks like.
And so, if this is the case,
sometimes it may be necessary
to design experiments
that are going to test
which options have the most potential
so you can figure out
which path to go down.
Either way, we want to plan
for how we're going to go
and get to the desired set of goals
that we set out for ourselves.
And we're going to break
the improvement initiative
down into workable chunks or units.
After each portion is complete,
we're going to reassess where we are
and if that planned set of actions
is getting us closer to our actual goals.
If you don't have a plan,
remember, you're planning to fail.
There is nothing worse than
an improvement initiative
that flounders and fails simply
because no one ever created
a plan of action for the
organization to follow.
Be a leader, determine how
we're going to get there,
and then we can move into step five
and finally take some action.