- Welcome to the complete course
for the ITIL 4 Foundation
certification exam.
In this course, you're going to learn
everything you need to
know to take and pass
the ITIL 4 Foundation exam
on your first attempt.
In addition to that,
you're going to be exposed
to the entire ITIL 4 framework.
So you can learn how to best use it
within your organization.
So whether you're taking this course
to learn about the ITIL 4 framework
or you're taking this
course to prepare for
the certification exam
so you can get a new job
or advance in your current organization.
This course has been designed specifically
to teach you everything
covered in the official
ITIL Foundation textbook
and it's designed as a
complete textbook replacement.
Now before we dive into
the course materials
let me provide you with a
quick introduction to ITIL.
If your boss enrolled you in this course
you may not even know
what ITIL is all about
or what it's used for.
Well, ITIL is a framework
for service management.
But I guess that begs the question,
"What exactly is service management?"
Well service management
is a set of specialized
organizational capabilities
for enabling value
to customers in the form of services.
We're going to talk a lot
about service management
throughout this entire course.
In fact, the entirety of Section Two
is dedicated to the topic
of Service Management.
Now ITIL was designed
to provide organizations
with a comprehensive framework
for IT service management.
In fact, ITIL is the most popular
and widely used information technology
service management framework
in the entire world.
It's one of the reasons
that ITIL Foundation
has such a high demand,
because most large companies
have built their IT
service management systems
and processes around the idea and concepts
of the ITIL framework.
Now I know I've gotten you
excited about ITIL, hopefully
and I need to take just a
small detour in the course
to introduce myself and share
with you four important tips
to help you learn better
during our time together.
Now first, my name is Jason Dion
and I'm the lead instructor
here at Dion Training Solutions.
I've been working in the
IT and cyber security field
for over two decades for
organizations both large and small.
In all of these organizations though
there's been one common
thread and that's ITIL.
Now when I'm talking
about small organizations
I'm talking about companies
with less than 20 people.
Small companies like my own.
When I talk about large organizations
I'm thinking about some
of my previous positions.
My last one in particular
I was with an organization
that spanned six continents,
dozens of countries
and millions of end users.
And guess what, all of these
organizations they ran on ITIL.
So I'm not just an instructor,
I'm also a practitioner of ITIL.
And I've been using it for decades.
Now rest assured you are
in great hands with us.
In fact, I'm an authorized
instructor for ITIL
and my company is an accredited
training organization
for PeopleCert on behalf of AXELOS,
the creators of the ITIL framework
and the certification exams.
In fact because we're an ATO,
all of our courses are reviewed by AXELOS
prior to us releasing them to you.
And this ensures that you're getting
the quality training
required to pass the exam.
And now for my four tips
for success in this course.
First every video in this course
has the ability for you to
turn on closed captioning.
Each video is captioned
by a real live human
and checked for accuracy.
This allows you to read
along with the course
if you need to.
Many of my students who speak English
as their second language, really
love having those captions
playing along with the videos
and this helps them aid
in their learning and understanding.
Now if you want to enable closed captions
simply click on the CC button
in the bottom of the video player.
My second tip is about playback speed.
I've gotten some students
who say I talk too fast.
I have others who say I talk too slow.
Either way, you get to control
the speed of the instruction
by clicking on the 1x button
in the bottom of the video player.
If you want me to teach faster,
simply select 1.25x or 1.5x.
If you want me to teach slower
simply click .75 or .5x.
Either way, faster or
slower, the choice is yours.
The third and probably one
of the most important tips
is about our student support group.
We have a student support group
with several thousand other students
who are learning ITIL and other IT
and project management certifications
through all of our courses.
If you want to join the fun there
you can find us at
facebook.com/groups/diontraining
and you can request to
join our private group.
There's not extra cost to
you by joining this group
and it's there to help you.
In this group, we answer questions,
put out additional free content
and help support each other
through our IT careers.
So if you want to ask a question there
all you have to do is post it
and you'll likely get an answer
within just a few minutes
because most of the time,
there are thousands of
other students, both past and present
who join the conversations there.
So if you're on Facebook,
I highly recommend
joining the group today.
Now if you aren't on Facebook,
you can still ask your questions
if you get stuck during this course.
Simply click on the Q and A tab
of your course learning page
and enter your question there.
Either myself or one of my team members
will answer your question there
within one to two days in most cases.
Like I said, the Facebook group,
you're going to get something
answered much quicker
because we have thousands of
people there to support you.
If you do it here in the Q and A
you'll get an answer once we
get back to work the next day
and we can help you out.
Now the fourth and final tip
is that this course comes with
a downloadable study guide
as a complete resource for you.
You can download this PDF and
it's attached to this lesson.
To access it, simply download
it from the resources
in this lesson and then
you can print it out
and refer to it during
your offline studies
and as you go through
the rest of this course.