- Service management practices.
Service management practices
have been developed
in the service management
and IT service management industries
over the last 20 to 30 years.
Under ITIL 4, there are 17 practices
that are going to be in the
service management category.
We're going to briefly cover all of them
in this section of the course.
Now, of these 17 practices,
you need to know six of them in depth,
and you need to know four of them
at the recall level of the exam.
On the exam, you have to be
able to understand and explain
how change control, incident management,
problem management, service
desk, service level management,
and service request management
practices work and function.
Also, you need to be able
to recall the purposes
of IT asset management,
monitoring and event
management, release management,
and service configuration
management practices.
After we've covered those first 10,
then we're going to go and
cover the rest of them.
And these are ones that
we're going to cover
just for a general awareness,
not that you need to
know them for the exam.
This includes availability
management, business analysis,
capacity and performance management,
service catalog management,
service continuity
management, service design,
and service validation
and testing practices.
But again, these practices won't be
on your certification exam.