- Let's discuss a few details
about the ITIL 4 Foundation exam.
If you're like most of my students,
you're probably taking this course
because you want to become
ITIL 4 Foundation certified.
Maybe you're working
towards a certification
to advancing your current career
or maybe it's because you're
trying to get your first job
in the information technology field.
Either way, this course
is designed to help teach
you everything you need to know
in order to pass that exam.
To help you focus your studies
throughout the course though
it's important for you to understand
how the exam is designed.
The questions on the
ITIL 4 exam are focused
on you having the ability
to recall or understand
the concepts from this course.
Now, the word recall and
understand are the keywords here.
If a question is focused on your ability
to recall something,
this means you have to be
able to identify a definition
or a term from the
answer choices provided.
For example, if the exam
provide you with a definition
for a particular term
that we use in the course,
it's going to provide it to
you word for word the same way
we presented it inside the course
and then you're going to be provided
with four different terms
and you have to select
the appropriate term that
matches the definition given.
Now, this is a great
example of a question using
the recall level of difficulty.
On the exam, you're going
to get nine questions
that are considered recall questions.
For that reason, it's really
important to be familiar
with the definitions that
we present in this course.
All of these definitions
are provided to you
in the downloadable study guide
and they're going to be
displayed on the screen
whenever I'm teaching them to you.
Now, if a question is
focused on your ability
to understand something, this
means you have to be able
to describe or explain
the definition of term
or a concept based on
the answers provided.
For these questions,
the exam isn't looking
for an exact word match.
Instead, you might get
an example of something
and you have to determine
the correct ITIL practice
or term that relates to it.
If you pay close attention to this course,
you're going to learn
the concepts of ITIL 4
and be able to answer
those questions on the exam
without too much difficulty.
Now, how do you take the
official certification exam
and become ITIL 4 Foundation certified?
Well, Acellus and PeopleCert
make it quite easy
because you don't even have
to get in your car and drive
to a testing center like many
other certification exams.
Instead, you're able
to take the exam online
from the comfort of
your own home or office
using the PeopleCert
web proctoring service.
To schedule your exam, you do
need an exam voucher though
because this covers the cost
of the certification exam itself.
You can buy the exam voucher
directly from PeopleCert
on their website at a
cost of $349 or you can go
to diontraining.com and
purchase your exam voucher
at a special discount rate
of $299 that's available
just for my students.
Because we're an authorized
training organization
for ITIL 4 Foundations,
we're able to buy these vouchers in bulk
and we pass the savings
on to our students.
Now, once you order your vouchers
is delivered to your email
within about 10 minutes
and you can then schedule
your certification exam
for the day and time
that's most convenient for you.
So, now that you know what
to study in terms of recall
and understanding and you
know where to buy your voucher
and how to schedule
your exam, what's next?
Well, let's talk about the exam itself.
There's some key facts and
figures that you need to know.
First, the exam is timed.
You're going to get 60
minutes to take the exam.
Now, if you're not a
native English speaker
but you're taking the exam in English,
you can go ahead and get
an extra 15 minutes of time
on the exam if you request
it during your scheduling.
This will bring your time up to 75 minutes
if you request a time
extension from PeopleCert.
Now, for all of us
English speakers though,
we only get 60 minutes.
Don't worry though, 60
minutes is plenty of time
for this exam.
Most of my students finish
in about 30 minutes.
Now, as for the questions,
the exam only has 40 questions
and the exam contains only
multiple choice questions
on the exam.
So, again, this exam is about
recalling an understanding
not memorization and not
comprehension in depth.
So, you won't have to write
out a definition word for word
or pull up an answer out of thin air.
Instead, it's always an
a, b, c, or d choice.
To pass the certification,
you have to answer at least 26 questions
out of 40 correctly.
This equates to a 65% or
higher on the exam for you
to pass it and earn your
ITIL 4 certification.
To best prepare for the exam,
I recommend you take a
lot of practice exams.
We've included quiz questions
and two full length practice
exams with this course.
When you're taking a practice exam,
I recommend aiming for 75%
or higher to consider it
a pass because this will give
you at least a 10% buffer
in case you ended up having a bad test day
or you get nervous when
taking a timed test
or certification exam.
Now, this is because every
time you take the exam
you have to buy a new voucher
and you only want to have to take it once.
Now, I've said you're going to
get 40 questions on exam day
and they're all multiple choice,
but they are made up of
three different types
of multiple choice questions.
We call these classic
missing word and list.
Let's take a look at each of these.
First, we have a classic question.
For example, which character
was created by Walt Disney?
A, Bart Simpson, b, Mickey Mouse,
c, Fred Flintstone or d, Garfield?
Well, if you know cartoons,
you probably know the
answer is b, Mickey Mouse.
Now, you may see a few
classic questions on the exam
that are shown is what we call
a negative classic question.
This is symbolized by the
word not in the question.
So, if you're asked
something like which of these
is not a car brand?
A, Ford, b, Saturn, c, Cisco or d, Toyota.
You hopefully realize that
Cisco is not a car brand
but instead is networking gear.
In fact, Cisco is a very popular brand
of networking equipment but
the other three are car brands.
So, we would say Cisco is the
right answer in this case.
The next type of question is what we call
a missing word question.
On the exam, this is
shown by a question mark
that would represent a
single word or a short phrase
of two, three or four words.
For example, a or and
blank is a type of fruit.
Is it a, apple b, carrot,
c, onion or d, celery?
Well, the answer is a,
apple because b, c and d
are all types of vegetables.
This makes the sentence read
as an apple is a type of fruit.
Our final type of question is what's known
as a list question.
You're probably going to
only see one or two of these
on your ITIL 4 Foundation exam though.
These questions ask it so that
more than one correct answer
can be provided.
So, you're going to get a numbered list
and you'll have to choose the right answer
that represents two of
the correct list items.
For example, which ingredients
are in a PB&J sandwich?
One, peanut butter, two,
apples, three, bacon
or four, grape jelly.
Well, as a parent who made
a lot of PB&J sandwiches
in my life,
I can tell you that the answer is one,
peanut butter and four, Jelly.
So we have to find the
letter that corresponds
with answers, one and four in it,
which in this case is d, and
that becomes our answer choice.
So, now that you know all about the exam,
I hope you're ready to start
learning all about ITIL 4.
Let's get started.