- Our fourth and final dimension
is Value Streams and Processes.
Value streams and processes
are going to define
the activities, the
workflows, the controls
and the procedures that
are needed to achieve
the agreed-upon objectives.
These are things like the activities
that the organization
is going to undertake,
how those activities are organized
and how value creation is ensured
for all of your stakeholders
efficiently and effectively.
Now when we talk about this,
let's start with Value Stream.
A value stream is a series of steps
that an organization undertakes
to create and deliver
products and services
to its service consumers.
This is going to combine
all of the organization's
value chain activities.
And we're going to spend
a lot of time talking
about value chain activities.
In fact, we have an entire section on it.
So let me give you an
example of a value stream.
A value stream is going to
have a series of steps, right?
So let me give you three steps.
I want to go and have lunch today.
So I'm going to go drive
to a fast-food restaurant.
I'm going to go walk inside and
I'm going to go up to the front
and I'm going to order
a hamburger and fries.
That's step one, the order process.
Then I get to step two
which is I'm going to wait
while they cook my food.
And then step three they're
going to deliver that food to me
and I can eat it.
That is a value where we're
going to have a transformation
from the raw materials,
we're going to get the order,
take the raw materials, make this burger
and then deliver it back to Jason
so Jason can have his lunch.
That's a value stream of three steps.
There's activities in
there that are going to add
to the value of this such as
when they cook the hamburger
and they put on the
ketchup and the mustard
and then they deliver
it to me at my table,
that's all value added.
It gives me value and that's
why I'm paying for it.
But there are some things
that are not value added.
For example, when
they're cooking the fries
there is waste oil that happens.
That's actually considered waste,
they have to throw that away
and pay to get rid of that.
That is a non value-adding activity.
There's also things like
when they get the packaging
with all the hamburgers
and they have to throw away
that package, that's waste as well.
When I leave the table and
I leave my burger and fries
and make a mess, that's a
non value-adding activity
for the organization 'cause
they have to spend time
and money to go clean up that mess, right?
In everything we do, there's things
that add value and there's waste.
And in business, we always
try to minimize the waste
and increase the value.
So that's a basic example
of some value stream activity, right.
We have these three steps,
we're going to order it,
we're going to manufacture
it, we're going to deliver it
and those are value-adding activities.
But there's also those waste activities,
those non-value adds as well.
What we want to do is we want
to optimize the value stream
so we can minimize the amount
of non value-adding activities
while increasing the amount
of value-adding activities.
Once we do that and we get it right,
we then want to automate that
process as much as possible.
So I was talking about
ordering hamburgers for lunch.
Well, if you've gone into
a McDonald's recently,
a lot of them are moving to automation.
They're eliminating the
order-taking process
and getting rid of the cashiers.
And instead they have these giant tablets
that look like giant
iPads and you go in there
and you order your food there
and you pay with your credit card.
It completely eliminated
what they consider
to be non value-adding activity,
having a cashier take your order.
Now they're passing that
work on to you as a consumer
and they're focusing on cooking the food
and handing it to you.
That's the idea here with
optimization and automation.
Now we look at these processes,
what exactly is a process?
Well, it's simply a set of interrelated
or interacting activities that transforms
some input into an output.
Processes are designed to
achieve a specific objective.
In my example, we had a value stream
that was made up of one process
with three different activities;
the ordering, the
manufacturer and the delivery.
And they achieved a specific objective.
That objective, getting
Jason his lunch, right?
And that's the idea of the process,
input some amount of
activities and then an output.
And by well defining your processes,
you can improve your productivity
and then you can also get it optimized
so you can automate it
as much as possible.
And this is why we have our value streams
and processes together in this dimension
because as we're looking at
our products and services,
we're going to ask
ourselves some questions.
we're going to say, what is
the generic delivery model
for the service?
What are the steps that we need to do
to make this service work?
Basically, what's the processes
and which set of processes,
when we put them together gives
us the right value stream?
What are the value streams
that are going to be involved
in delivering the agreed-upon
outputs of the service?
So if I think about
giving you video delivery
of this course, there's
a lot of different things
that have to occur.
And we break those down into
what the value stream is
and then each of those pieces,
those steps are the
processes inside of it.
We have to think about who
and what is going to perform
each of those required service actions?
Again, breaking it down into
the individual processes
so we can figure that out.
And that's why this is
considered our fourth dimension
as we're looking at this and figuring out
how are we going to give you that product
or that service by doing some processes
as part of a value stream.