- Plan.
The first value chain activity
we're going to discuss
in this section is known as Plan.
The purpose of the Plan
value chain activity
is to ensure a shared understanding
of vision, the current status,
and the improvement direction
for all four dimensions of
the IT service management,
and all of our products and services
across the organization.
This is your executive vision.
It's where we want to be,
and then the plans to get us there.
As we look at the inputs
to the Plan process,
we're going to be looking at policies,
requirements, and
constraints that are provided
by the organization's governance body.
We're also going to be
looking at consolidating
all of the demands and opportunities
that are being sent to us
from the Engage process
that we're going to be talking
about in a few minutes.
We're also going to be
looking at all of the
value chain performance information,
the improvement initiatives,
and the plans that are provided
from the Improve process.
We're also going to be looking
at improvement status reports
from the Improve process.
We're going to be looking
at knowledge and information
about our new and changed proxy services
from our design and transition or
obtain and build processes.
We're going to take that
knowledge and information
about third party service
components as well,
coming in from the Engage process.
All of this is things that are
going to go into our planning,
so we can figure out how we
can best get our services
to where we want them to be.
If you're familiar with the old ITIL ways,
it used to be known as strategy.
A lot of that is now part
of this Plan process.
Now, all of that is the inputs,
what comes out of the Plan process?
Well, we're going to be looking
at three levels of Plans.
We have strategic plans,
which are those big organizational plans.
We have tactical plans, and
we have operational plans.
And this is kind of big, middle, and small
as we get down into the weeds.
We also have portfolio decisions
that are going to be made,
so we can decide what services
are we going to bring online
so that we can pass those
to Design and Transition,
so they can actually design
and build those services,
and figure out how to make them a reality.
When we talk about Plan,
we're talking about
the big, overarching way of thinking about
how we're going to get somewhere.
We also want to think about
our architectures and our policies,
and those are things that
we're going to output
and give to Design and Transition.
Now what do I mean by
architectures and policies?
Well, maybe part of our plan means
that we're going to use
cloud architectures.
That means the Design
and Transition should
no longer be trying to build
server farms for us to use.
Instead, they should be
looking at getting things
on the Amazon Web Services,
or Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud.
That would be an architecture decision
that's going to come out of plans,
and be given to Design and Transition.
As we want to give things
back to the Improve process,
we want to tell them,
based on our planning,
we think these are things
that can be improved,
these are improvement opportunities.
So, we'll pass that back to
the Improve process as well.
Another thing we're going to
give to the Engage process
is our product and our service portfolio.
As an organization, we're
going to create the roadmap
of what we want to build
and what we want to get
over the next, say, three or five years.
Once we have that plan in place,
we give that to Engage,
and they're going to go out
and engage with customers, consumers,
as well as service
providers, to figure out
how we can build what we
want to get from this plan.
And that engagement is
going to happen by going out
and making contracts or making connections
to get what we need.
Which brings us to the last thing.
Engagement also is going
to go out as an output
from our plans and get the contracts
and the agreements in place
so that we can actually
give that into the Design and Transition,
and then to the Build team,
so they can build what
it is we're envisioning.
That's the idea.
When you hear about plans
inside the service value chain,
I want you to think
about the fact that we're
thinking about big plans.
We're talking about roadmaps.
For example, in my
company, we have roadmap
that says over the next three years,
these are the different
certification programs
that we're going to support and
create videos and exams for.
If it's not on that roadmap,
we're not going to put effort towards it,
because that is our plan.
That is what we're going
to be going towards.
That is our big, overarching,
strategic vision.
Now, from that strategic vision,
we have a tactical plan
that says in the next year,
we're going to do these
three certifications maybe.
And then we have operational plans
of how we're going to build one
of those individual courses.
So it goes from the big
plan, to a medium sized plan,
down to the very detailed
operational plan.
That's the idea here
when we talk about plans
inside the service value chain.