- Continual improvement.
So we've spent a lot of time
going through each of the pieces
of the service value system.
In the last section we
covered the middle block
which was the service value chain.
Now we're going to move
to the lowest block
which is continual improvement.
You'll notice here that it is called out
in this purple block.
Now right above continual improvement
there's a block called practices.
And practices are going to be
the 34 distinct idle practices
that we're going to cover
throughout the course.
And oddly enough, continual
improvement is one of those 34.
So why is continual improvement
pulled out in the diagram
as its own activity shown here
in addition to the fact
that it's a practice?
Well, it's because continual
improvement is that important.
In everything we do we should
always be trying to improve.
And when we look at this
from the exam perspective,
continual improvement comes up twice.
First, you have to be able to recall
the purpose of the continual
improvement practice.
Notice the key word there is recall.
That means you have to be
able to know it word for word
and be able to identify
that definition on the exam.
Second, you also need to be
able to explain or discuss
how continual improvement
and the continual improvement model
fits within the service value chain
and the service value system.
So we're going to spend
this section of the course
talking specifically about
continual improvement.
Now, I said you have to be
able to recall the definition.
So, what is that definition?
Well, the purpose of the
continual improvement practice
is to align the organization's
practices and services
with changing business needs
through the ongoing identification
and improvement of services,
service components, practices,
or elements that are
involved in the efficient
and effective management
of products and services.
So, this is a very long definition.
But you need to be able to know it
because if they give you something
where there's a fill in the blank
you have to pull in the right word.
If they give you this definition,
you need to be able to identify
that it is the continual
improvement practice.
That's the level of knowledge you need
for the recall part of the exam.
Now, as we go through
the rest of this section
I'm going to present to you the
continual improvement model,
how it fits into the service value chain,
and walk you through each step
of that continual improvement model
so you can understand it
and explain it on the exam.