- Welcome to this section of the course
on the Service Value Chain.
In this section of the course,
we're going to be focusing
on the fifth major objective for the exam.
This states that you have
to be able to understand
the activities of the Service Value Chain,
and how they interconnect.
Underneath this objective,
there are two sub-objectives.
It's to describe the interconnected nature
of the Service Value Chain
and how this supports value streams,
and to describe the purpose
of each of the value stream activities.
That includes Plan,
Improve,
Engage,
Design and Transition,
Obtain and Build
and Delivery and Support.
So back when we talked about
the Service Value System,
we had one inside block
that showed us the service value chain.
Well, in this section of the course,
we're going to break that block open,
and look at all of those different pieces.
As you can see here,
we have things
like Engage,
Plan,
Improve,
Design and Transition,
Obtain and Build,
Deliver and Support
and Products and Services.
And all of those are
going to work together
as part of this service value chain.
Now, there's a couple of
important things to know
when we look at a diagram like this.
This is not shown to introduce
a linear sequence of events.
If you happen to be familiar
with ITIL version three
or the older version of ITIL,
we had what we called
the service lifecycle,
And it was a sequence of
actions in a linear format.
So we would start with a strategy,
and then move to design,
and then move to transition,
and then move to operations,
and then we move to continual
service improvement.
And we work through
those five life cycles.
Here in ITIL 4 we don't do that anymore.
This is not a linear sequence.
Instead we normally are
going to start with Engage,
but we don't always have to.
And based on that we're
then going to touch
into other areas of that interior cube.
And as we look at that central cube
with the activities that are in there,
we have three major groups.
We have Design and Transition,
Obtain and Build,
and Deliver and Support.
These are what are referred to
as the central activities
inside the service value chain.
And these can interact in any order
between each other and with
the other activities as well.
Another important thing to know,
is this overlap that
exists between Improve
and the other areas of
the service value chain.
You'll notice that Improve is shown
in the lower half of this diagram.
And here's this overlap
of this purple band
that goes from Improve
to Improve and Engage.
You have Improve to the activities
inside the central cube,
such as the Deliver and Support,
the Design and Transition
or the Obtain and Build.
We have Improve in the
Products and Services.
All of these are here to
show us that feedback loop
that exists between each part
of the service value chain
as it moves through the improvement cycle
and the continual service improvement.
Now you also need to understand and manage
the perceived value of
this service value chain,
because it's going to drive
the demand for the next order,
the next product,
the next service
or the next iteration of
your service relationship.
Now the reason why we call
this a service value chain,
is because all these
actions are linked together.
So there's a lot of
interactions that occur
between these different practices.
This service value chain
activities are going to represent
all of the different steps
that the organization
is going to take in the creation
or co creation of value.
Each activity is going to
contribute to the value chain
by transforming this specific
inputs into desired outputs.
And so as we take things
from demanding opportunity,
it goes through that service value chain,
getting additional value added
in coming out the other side
as the value and the desired outcome
that we want for our services.
That's the way that we're going
to be looking at all of this.
And so to convert these
inputs into outputs,
these value chain activities
are going to use different combinations
of the 34 ITIL practices that
we're going to to discuss
throughout the remainder of this course.
Each activity can draw upon internal
or third party resources.
They can look at different processes,
different skills and competencies,
from one or more of these 34 practices.
They don't have to be done individually.
They can be combined together too.
And that's the whole idea here.
As we start getting
these inner relationships
through the service
value chain activities.
All of the incoming and
outgoing interactions
with all of the different parties
that are external to
your service provider,
are all performed through the
Engage value chain activity.
That's why it's one of those first ones
that normally occurs.
Anytime you want to new resource,
that's going to be obtained
through the Obtain and Build activity.
Anytime you want to plan something.
Any planning is going to occur
through the Plan activity.
When you try to improve things,
that's going to happen
through the Improve activity.
You're kind of getting
the idea here, right?
All of the different things that we do,
are going to be bend into one or more
of these different buckets.
As we create and modify,
and deliver and maintain,
and support a component,
a product or a service,
all that's going to happen
inside that central cube.
Between Design and Transition,
Obtain and Build and Delivery and Support.
As we look at our products and services,
our demand and our value,
these are not considered
value chain activities, right?
Those go back to our service value system.
Those are our inputs and our outputs.
So the inside is what we're
really looking at here.
That's Engage,
Plan,
Improve,
Obtain/build,
Delivery and Support
and Design and Transition.
As we look at those,
that is what we're going to be focusing on
in this section of the course
and we're going to dive
into each one of those in
their own separate lecture,
as we move forward.