- Improve.
The next value chain activity
I want to focus on is
the improve value chain activity.
The purpose of the Improve
value chain activity
is to ensure continual improvement of our
products, services, and practices
across all of our value chain activities
and the four dimensions
of IT service management.
We take a lot of different
inputs into the improve activity.
We're going to be looking at things
like product and service
improvement information
that we get back from deliver and support.
As we talk about deliver and support,
these are your operations personnel.
They're the ones who are
running the service desk,
and running all the
servers and the services.
So they're constantly getting
feedback from your end-users,
from your consumers,
and from your customers.
We also want to take
stakeholders' feedback in
from the engage process.
As we look at that, that
might be things between
us and our suppliers,
or us and our partners,
or us and our consumers.
All of that is information
that's coming back in
through engage and engage
is going to take that
and pass it over to the improve activity
so improvements can be made
based on that feedback.
We also will look at the
performance information and
improvement opportunities
that are provided from all of
the different value chain activities.
As we're measuring things
across the lifecycle,
and across all of our
processes and activities,
we want to make sure that's
being fed back to improvement
so we can figure out how can we do things
better, cheaper, faster, more efficient,
whatever the case may be.
We're always trying to improve
to get more value for less cost.
And then, we also want
to look at all of the
knowledge and information about our
new and changed products and services
from design and transition
and obtain/build.
So as we're going through and building
a new server, or new service,
we want to get that information
and pass it back to improve
because then, improve
can look at it and make
suggestions and recommendations
of how to do this
better, cheaper, faster, etc., right?
We also are going to look at all the
knowledge and information about our
third-party service components
from the engage perspective.
So, the improvement is also then
getting information from engage
from our partners and our supplies.
Because maybe our supplier's moving
from a self-hosted environment
into a cloud environment
and that new information
can factor into our planning
for improvements in the future.
Well, we start talking about outputs
from the improve process, this
is going to be things like
improvement initiatives and plans
for all of the other
value chain activities.
The improve is looking across the
entire service value chain
and service value system.
And as they look at that,
they're going to figure out,
"Hey, build and obtain,
you guys could have
done this for half of the
price if you had done thing X."
And they'll make that
recommendation or that plan
of how to do it better next time.
We're also going to have value
chain performance information
from plan and from the governing body.
As we get that information,
we're going to be able to pass
that back out to those folks
and make sure that we can use that
improve information out across the field.
Also, we're going to be looking
at our improve status reports
for all the value chain activities.
As we've taken all this
information in from everybody
and we figure out how
we're going to improve it,
we're going to put those
status reports back out
and say, "Here are the recommendations,
and here's how you can improve things."
Again, it's that whole idea
of continual improvement
over and over again.
If we have recommendations
for contracts and agreements,
we're not going to give
those directly to the
consumers or the service
provides or any of our suppliers.
Instead, we're going to pass
that back to engage because
they're going to be our conduit
to all of those external agencies.
And so that's the way
we're going to do that
with any improvements for
contracts or agreement language.
And finally, we have our
service performance information
for design and transition.
As we get all of that information,
and we look at how we can improve it,
we're also going to push that
back to design and transition
so they can design and transition
better services next time around.
This all goes back to the
bottom line of continual improvement.
When we're thinking about the
value chain activity
of improve, just think,
how could we make things
better, faster, cheaper, easier,
better functionality,
whatever the case may be,
however we can move and get
more improvement and better results,
that's the idea inside
the improve activity.