- Measurement and reporting.
Measurement and reporting is
another one of those practices
that's not covered by the ITIL 4 Exam.
But it's a good one to
know because there are
pieces of this that we
have discussed already.
Now, measurement and
reporting is the practice
of supporting good decision making
and continual improvement by decreasing
levels of uncertainty.
We do this by measuring things.
If you remember back in our
continual improvement model,
we talked about measuring
and creating a baseline.
And then, after we took
action, we went back
and measured again to
see how things changed.
That's what measuring and
reporting is all about.
When discussing measurement and reporting,
two key terms come up a lot.
It's KPIs, or Key Performance Indicators,
and CSFs, or Critical Success Factors.
We've already discussed both of these back
when we talked about the model
inside continual improvement.
Now, when you talk about
measurement and reporting,
remember what I said very
early on in this course.
It's very easy to measure outputs,
but it's difficult to measure outcomes.
One of the difficulties of this practice
is being able to figure out what things
you really should be measuring
and are you measuring
the right things.
Because we want to make
sure we're measuring
the outcome and not just the outputs.
Again, this is an entire field with people
who are dedicated to it.
You're going to get people
from business analysis
that are going to be working in this field
that really help you drive those numbers
and figure out what are those key metrics
that your business needs.