- What is value?
Well in ITL 4, value is
the perceived benefits,
usefulness, and importance of something.
Now I know this is very generic.
But let's dig into the short
definition and explore it a bit
because value is an
extremely important concept
inside of ITIL and service
management in general.
First, notice in the definition
that value is perceived.
This means that the amount of value
something has is always subjective.
Who gets to determine this
perceived amount of value?
Well the privilege is reserved
for the recipient of the value.
So let me give you an
example to help clarify it.
There's two roommates, Julia and John.
One afternoon, they both decide
they want to go get an orange.
They walk over to the refrigerator
to each get themself an orange
and find that there's only
one left in the fruit drawer.
They begin to fight with each other
because each person really wants
that orange for themselves.
Julia says she values the orange more
and she should have it.
But John quickly retorts that
he values the orange more
and that he should have it.
Neither person explains to the other
why they want the orange.
Instead they don't tell
them about the value
they perceive that it has.
But being omniscient as the
narrator in this example,
I know exactly what each of them
wants to do with that orange.
Julia's hungry and she desired to have
a sweet and healthy afternoon snack.
So if she gets the orange,
she plans to cut it apart,
eat the sweet, juicy flesh inside of it,
and throw away the peel.
Now in her perceived value of this orange,
the inside of the orange
holds 100% of the value
and the peel is garbage, it's worthless.
John on the other hand, he's a baker,
and this afternoon he wanted
to make some orange cupcakes.
So he needed the orange peel
to be able to zest it into the batter.
If he gets the orange, he
intends to simply use the peel
and throw away the orange and
sweet inside into the trash.
Unlike Julia who places
100% of the orange's value
on it's ability to be eaten
as an afternoon snack,
John believes that that part of the orange
is completely worthless.
Instead, he places 100% of the
value into the orange peel.
Now I'm sure you can see the
interesting thing here about value.
This one orange could
serve 100% of the needs
for each person involved
in this transaction.
If only they could communicate
their true desires for that orange.
They could both have 100% of the value
because the value is perceived
by the end recipient.
And in this case, our two roommates
each view it differently.
Now to the grocer who was
the original supplier of this orange,
he sold that orange for a single dollar.
Had he'd known that they
both value that $1 orange
for different reasons, maybe he would have
cut the orange apart, separate the insides
away from the peel and sold
each portion for a dollar each.
And if he done that to
each of the roommates,
he would have doubled the
orange's value for himself.
Now I know that sounds a little crazy,
but I bet on exam day you're going to
remember about this orange and value.
You're going to remember
that the amount of value
that something has is based on
the recipient's perception
of that value right?
It's the recipient that actually is
expected to get the
value from the products,
from those relationships,
from those services,
from whatever it is we're
expecting to deliver,
or to facilitate the value for them.
Because of this, value is
always considered subjective.
And it can be quite different
from what the original
supplier planned for.
It may be different from what they
had described the product as
or what service it was going to fulfill,
and from what we originally agreed to.
This subjectivity should be captured,
measured, and evaluated because
this is what we have to
work with as an organization
that performs service management.
Now let's get back to our
definition of value once more.
Value is the perceived benefits,
usefulness, and importance of something.
As I said before this definition
is a bit generic right.
This is because it uses this
vague term of something.
This word was specifically
chosen by the creator's of ITIL
because service management goes beyond
just services these days.
Because the perceived benefits
and usefulness of something
really do depend on the context
that it's being talked about.
In each given context, we
know what that something is.
And we know what it means
in the value definition.
But in a generic definition like this,
we can't simply list all of
the things something could be.
So something becomes that placeholder.
Because when we talk about value,
value is really based on
these relationships as well.
And we're going to discuss those
service relationships in a future lesson.