- Think and work holistically.
This is our fifth guiding principle.
This principle says that we
should take a holistic approach
to service management and this requires us
to have an understanding
of all of the parts
of the organization and
how they work together
in an integrated way.
Think about this like your car.
Your car, you get in and you drive,
and your output of that or outcome of that
is that it gets you
from point a to point b,
but that car is a complex
piece of machinery.
There are lots of different systems,
from the engines to the
brakes to the transmissions,
to the air conditioning.
They all have to work together
to make that system work.
Now if you understand it from end to end,
that's understanding it holistically.
You have to understand everything
and how it works together.
Now as somebody who drives a car,
do I really need to know every
single piece of that car?
No, I need to know the
holistic approach to it
and that way I can
understand its simplicity,
of if I put the key in and I turn it,
that's going to turn on the engine
and allow me to drive to my destination.
Now as we look at our IT services
and IT service management,
we have to make sure that we're addressing
all four dimensions
because this will make
sure that we're thinking
of things in a holistic manner.
I'm going to consider my
organizations and people,
the information and technology,
the partners and suppliers,
and the values streams and processes.
If I use those four dimensions
of IT service management,
those four perspectives,
I'm going to make sure that I
have a good holistic overview
of how that service works
and then if I want to get a
little more tactical with it,
I can go ahead and look at
the service value system
for that particular service.
I'm going to look at the input,
the demand and the opportunity,
as it goes through the middle
of the service value chain
and it goes through the governance
and the continual improvement
and the guiding principles
and then out the other side,
as the desired outcome or value.
Again, by using these two frameworks,
the four dimensions and
that service value system,
I really can understand things
in a much more holistic way.
Now as I look at things
from a holistic area,
I want you to remember
that systems are complex
and you have to recognize that
these systems are complex.
There's a lot of inputs and
there's a lot of outputs.
Things are rarely as simple
as steps one, two, and three.
Generally, there are
steps one, two, and three,
but they're impacted by another series
of processes or steps that
are outside of itself.
If I'm running something
like a web server,
well I'm going to have the
website and the code for that
but it also has an
underlying operating system
and an underlying server
and an underlying network,
an underlying connectivity
and all of those are interrelated.
If I understand the
complexity of the system,
I can then understand the
simplicity of the system
on the other side of it
and I'll explain that in a
little bit here, as well.
Another key to working
holistically is to collaborate.
And we talked about collaboration
in the fourth guiding principle.
Collaboration really
is the key to thinking
and working holistically.
If I work in IT, I might
understand all the bits
and the bytes and the
servers and the connectivity.
But I might not understand
what the larger business
is looking for to get out of this service.
So as I look at this service,
I want to make sure I'm collaborating
with the people who are going
to be selling the service,
the people who are going to
be marketing the service,
be supporting the service,
and if we all look at it
from all our different perspectives,
we can make sure we're
looking at this thing
in a holistic and integrated way.
Whenever possible, we want to
look for patterns of interaction
between our different system elements.
What are the things that are
going to get inputs or outputs
from this system and
affect the way it performs.
To make something truly simple,
you have to understand
all of its complexity
and then once you
understand the complexity,
you can proceed to bringing it back up
to a simple representation.
For example, recently I was
working with an organization
and we were trying to better understand
the way their cyber
security posture was set up.
Their cyber security posture had dozens
and dozens of different systems.
All working together
to hopefully give them
a good cyber security posture.
Now as we wanted to figure
out what the complexity was
and to simplify it,
we had to go through and bring in people
from all of the different programs
that were being run
across the security stack
and as we did that, we
started figuring out
okay, this program does
functions one, two, and three.
This other one does
functions four and five.
This other program does functions
one, four, five, and six.
And we had to start laying
out in deep complexity,
each of the interactions
between all of these different systems,
so we can then look simply as we step back
and say okay we are fully
covering this service
from a security perspective holistically.
Again, if you want to
make something simple,
you have to first understand
the complexity of it.
Then you can go through
and try to minimize
as much of the complexity
and represent it as a
simple solution at the end.
Finally when you're working holistically,
you also may want to consider
the use of automation
because automation can
help us to facilitate
working holistically across our staff.
If we consider the example
of an incident management system,
your service desk is probably
going to be the entry point
for any incidents that are
reported to the organization.
They're your first line help desk
and ask people call in
with their problems,
they're going to log those,
categorize those, and tag those.
But at that point, the system
can then use automation
to make sure those get put
into the right department
for them to be able to work it.
For example, if you had a
a hard drive that failed,
you're going to call the help desk,
they're going to put in the ticket
and it's going to get routed over
to people who support hardware.
If you're having trouble
accessing a certain website,
that might get routed to a different team
and it's going to be working
across the entire organization that way
but this IT service, this
service of incident management
is going to be something
that's going to be holistic
across the staff
and we're going to use
automation to help support that.