- Organizational change management,
this is our next practice, and again,
it's for general
awareness, not on the exam.
Organizational change
management is the practice
of ensuring that changes
in an organization
are smoothly and successfully implemented,
and that lasting benefits are achieved
by managing the human aspects of changes.
Now, this is different
from change management
you may have dealt with
in the technical world.
In the technical world,
maybe I want to make a change
to the baseline, I want
to take this server
and I want to add an
additional hard drive.
That would be change management,
but it's not organizational
change management.
Instead, we find organizational
change management
often occurs as part
of process improvements
and continual improvement processes.
Now, if I'm going to go through
and change the processes
of how we do things, or the
way we conduct business,
I have to help change the
culture and the acceptance
across that culture,
within the organization.
This is why it's important to manage
that human aspect of changes.
We want to make sure that we're
getting the humans involved
so that they can change things,
and that those changes are long-lasting.
That's what organizational
change management is all about.
It's how I keep the momentum going,
when I'm dealing with a
continual improvement,
because without that change of the person,
those changes are going to be short-lived,
so we have to change the
organizational culture
along with it,
and that's what organizational
change management
is really focused on.