- Where do we want to be?
Coming out of step two,
we now know where we are
in terms of our baseline.
This now begs the question,
where do we want to be?
Let's pretend that you're
back in college again.
When you started the school
year, you had a vision.
This is step one.
And your vision was you're going to own
a 3.5 grade point average.
Now you just finished your first semester
and you got your grades back.
Unfortunately, you didn't
do as well as you thought
and you earned some B's and some C's.
Now you're looking at
your grade point average
and you see that you earned a 2.9.
That's the second step.
Where are we now?
We're at a 2.9.
Now you need to decide if this semester
is going to be different and
if you've made that decision,
we're going to go ahead and try to do
some improvement initiatives.
You might study longer
or study differently.
Now you've decided that by
the end of the school year,
you want to have a 3.3 GPA.
And by the end of next school year,
you want to achieve an
initial vision of 3.5.
This is what we're going
to be doing in step three.
We're going to decide where we want to be.
Both in the short term and the long term.
During this step, we're going
to perform a gap analysis.
This is going to look
at our overall vision,
where we currently are
and where we want to be
over some amount of time.
Based on this analysis,
we're going to be able to
determine what that delta is,
what the gap is.
So, for example, if I say
I wanted to have $1,000
in my bank account, but
I only have $100 today,
well, the gap is $900.
1,000, where I want to be versus
the $100 I currently have.
Therefore, we need to figure out a way
of what we're going to
do to get us $900 more.
Now in the case of IT systems,
it's usually not going
to be monetary related.
It will be based on
some key metrics though.
This is going to be based on things
like critical success factors or CSFs
or key performance indicators, KPIs.
Either way, in the business world,
we refer to these generally as metrics.
These metrics are what we're
going to use to measure things
and figure out what the gap is.
Now it's important to note here
that our vision from step one
may be something that
is totally aspirational
and never going to be obtained truly.
The reason for this is
because sometimes our vision
is going to be beyond
what we can ever get to.
Let's use the example of
our college GPA again.
Let's say your vision
was to graduate college
with a perfect score.
A 4.0 GPA.
Well, based on our current
state that we found in step two,
we're never going to be
able to reach that 4.0
because we already earned
some B's and some C's,
which is going to lower
our overall average.
Now that's fine.
We can keep the vision
of graduating with a 4.0,
but we know we're never going to reach it.
Maybe we can get up to a 3.8
but we'll never get to 4.0.
It's just the way math works, right.
So now, here in step three,
we're going to create smaller
goals that we can reach
as we try to get closer and
closer to the actual vision,
whether or not we ever obtain
that actual vision in the end.
So now in step three,
we're going to figure out
where do we want to be and
we're going to set our goals.
We're going to agree to those
key performance indicators,
those metrics, such as the KPIs
and the critical success factors.
But at this point, we still
haven't taken any actions
to actually improve, right.
We've just set out our
goals, but that's okay,
because next in step four,
we're going to begin to formulate our plan
in order to start taking some action.