- Organizations and People.
Now this is going to
be the first dimension
we're going to consider.
Now even though we've listed these
one, two, three, and
four, for ITELS purposes,
there not necessarily in a
given order of consideration.
They are just listed that way so
we can have a way to present
it to you inside this video.
But I really do think that
organizations and people
is the first one we need to talk about
because it is really one
of the most important,
and one of the hardest to get right.
When we talk about
organizations and people
from the service management perspective,
we're thinking about the way
we're going to form our
organizational structures
to support the services and products
that we want to deliver to our end users,
which is those customers
and those consumers.
Now when we talk about
these formal organizations,
this can be something as large or macro
as the way we set up our business.
Is our business going to
be a sole proprietorship?
Is it going to be a limited
liability corporation?
Is it going to be a
multi-level conglomerate?
Is it going to be based
in the United States
or is it going to be based
outside the United States?
All of those things are formal
organizational structures.
But then as we get a little bit
tighter into the organization,
we think about the way we set up
the organizational hierarchy
inside the organization.
Are we going to have a
very vertical organization,
or a very horizontal organization?
Let me give you a couple examples of this.
My company, we happen to be
a fairly flat organization,
we're fairly horizontal.
And that means, because we're small,
we only have five to ten people
who work for us at any given time,
we can talk to each other directly.
We don't have to go up
through bureaucratic channels.
But some places I've worked before
have had hundreds of
thousands of employees.
As somebody down in IT, I
can't go and talk to the CEO.
It's just not the way it works.
I would talk to my manager,
and that manager would
talk to his manager,
and eventually that message
might get up to the CEO.
That's a very vertical organization.
And so these are things you
have to think about when you're
deciding how you're going to
structure your organization.
If you're going to be very
flat and very horizontal,
that means you might be
able to do things quicker,
and faster, and be more creative.
But if you're very vertical,
you might be much more process oriented.
And so these are the kind
of things you think about
when you start thinking about
are we going to deliver our services
through a very formal
organizational structure?
Also when you think about organizations,
how are you going to break up the company?
Are you going to have it broken up into
sales and marketing as one department,
and then the IT services in another?
And then the help desk in another?
And the administration in another?
Well that all depends.
And that's all going to come down
to that formal organizational structure.
Now once you figure out
what that structure is,
you have to staff it with people, right?
We have to find all the right
people to do the right jobs.
And that's the required
staffing and competencies.
That's that whole human resources
part of this whole thing.
So once we figure out
that we have this company,
and we have all these different
departments we've created,
now we have to hire the right managers
and leaders for each of those departments.
And, all the right people
for those departments.
And then we have to make sure those people
stay up to date with their skills.
I don't know about you,
but I've been working in IT a long time,
it's been about 20 years.
And computers today
and the way we run them
is completely different than
what we did 20 years ago.
All along the way, my
managers and my leadership
had to make sure I was
going back and getting
new training and new skills
to make sure my competencies
stayed with the current
technologies that were
out in the world today.
And then we have to think about the
roles and responsibilities
for each person.
What is each person's
role in this company?
What are they going to do?
If you're going to be
the everything person,
and in small companies you sometimes
have everything people,
where you have somebody
who is going to be the
teacher, and the editor,
and the marketer, and
the sales person, right?
But in most companies
if you're large enough,
you're going to have a single
role or responsibility.
You're going to be an accountant,
and maybe not just an accountant at large,
but you're going to be
a specific accountant
for a specific account or
a specific customer, right?
This is the idea of roles
and responsibilities.
I have people that come to me all the time
and say I want to get into the IT world,
I want to be in IT.
I say, great, what do
you want to do in IT?
Because there are hundreds of
different jobs inside of IT.
You need to figure out what that goal is,
what that role is that you want to attain,
so that way we can figure
out what the right path is
to get you there.
And this brings us down to
our fourth consideration
under organizations and people.
And this is what we call culture.
When we talk about culture,
we're talking about the shared values
and attitudes of that organization.
And this is by far the
hardest thing to get right.
So if you look at a company
that's out in Silicon Valley,
a lot of these startup companies,
they have a very friendly
culture, it's very informal.
You might walk up to
the CEO of the company,
and be like, hey Brian, how's it going?
But if you're working for
somebody like IBM that's a big
company that relies on
processes and procedures,
and everything is done in
this big formal method,
well that's a different culture.
If you look at Facebook,
and you look at IBM,
and you look at a hospital,
they're going to have
three different cultures.
Now, is one of those right
and one of those wrong?
Not necessarily.
It all depends on how your
organization wants to set it up
so they can take care of its organization
and the people inside of it.
Now another part of culture
is the communication
and how are we going to communicate
within the organization.
Are we going to be formal or informal?
Are we going to do it
in person or by email?
All of those things are things that
are a cultural thing
inside your organization.
How much trust and transparency
is there in the company?
Do your leaders up top tell you
what the plans are for the organization?
Do they share the vision?
Do they share the goals?
All that stuff starts at the top
and then works its way down.
If you have bad culture at the top,
you're going to have bad
culture at the bottom, right?
And so we need to make sure we're
getting the right culture
out to our people.
And finally when we're
talking about leaders,
we need to have leaders who have
a vision of where they want to be,
and they need to be
advocating for the values
and for that vision.
So if we're going to say that,
you know our most important thing for us
is making sure that our
people are taken care of,
but then every time your
people have a problem,
you kick them to the
curb and you fire them,
that's not really living the
values you've been setting.
And so you want to make sure as you're
thinking about all this stuff,
how that culture is
going to work together.
So when we think about that organization,
that's all of those pieces.
And then we have the other side of it,
which is the individual people.
Individual people have a lot
of things as well, right?
We have each person has their own
management and leadership style.
Your CEO may have one vision,
and your first level manager
has a different vision,
or a different leadership style, right?
And that's going to be an issue.
And so we need to think about that
when we start talking about
organizations and people.
And also have to think about the people
and updating their
skills and competencies,
like I talked about before.
How we're going to
communicate and collaborate
with our people on our team
and outside of our team.
How we're going to share the knowledge
and share all of our specializations.
And then we also want to think about
how we're going to
facilitate value creation.
Because at the end of the day,
the whole thing about culture
and organizations and people,
is to be able to do something, right?
Creating that product,
creating that service,
which gives value to that consumer.
And if we can't create
value for our consumer,
we're not going to be in
business for very long.
So that's why we have to think about this.
When we think about products and services,
the first dimension we
think about it from,
is through the lens of the
organization and the people.
How are we going to set
up the organization?
How is it going to function?
What kind of culture it's going to have?
And how do we take care of the people
so that the people can deliver
those products and services?