- Monitoring and event management.
This is another one you have
to recall the purpose of
and there's a term that were
going to have to define.
Let's start with the purpose.
The purpose of monitoring
an event management practice
is to systematically observe
a service or a service component,
and record and report
selected changes of state
identified as events.
And events is the word that
we're going to have to define.
Now this practice identifies
and prioritizes infrastructure,
services, business processes,
information security events,
and then it establishes
the appropriate response to those events,
including responding to the conditions
that could lead to potential
faults or incidents.
Event management is
really important for us.
And this brings us to the
term that we need to memorize.
This one is called an event.
An event is any change of
state that has significance
for the management of a configuration item
or a CI or an IT service.
For example, an event might be
when you log in successfully,
or when you fail to log in successfully.
It might be that the bandwidth is exceeded
for a certain threshold.
It might be that the
free space on a server
gets below a certain threshold.
These are all things that could be events.
We want to make sure
that we take some action
based on these events.
And depending on what the event is,
that's going to tell
us what we need to do.
The event might be something
that's informational,
or it might be a warning,
or it might be an alert,
depending on the severity.
If it's something informational,
like we had a successful
login, that's fine,
we don't have to take any
action, we might just log it.
But if we have something
like a login failure
that happened three times,
that might become a warning
and we want to figure
out why did that account
try to log in three times incorrectly.
If we have something like
the free space on a server
gets below 10 gigabytes,
that might be an alert
because it might cause a server to crash
if we run out of disk space.
That's the idea here with
the event and monitoring.
We want to make sure we
understand what events there are,
and we monitor them to decide
what actions need to be taken.
Some of those actions need to go out
and get into the problem
management perspective,
or the incident management perspective.
But again, here inside
of the event monitoring,
we're really focused on the event,
which is any change in
state that has significance
for the management of
a configuration item,
a CI, or an IT service.