- So at this point, we've
discussed service management,
value, organizations and people,
and services and products.
In this lesson, I want to briefly consider
the concept of a service offering.
The reason I'm spending this
lesson on service offerings
is because it's a concept
that you need to be able
to describe and discuss on the exam.
This concept falls under the
understand level of knowledge
for the certification exam.
Now, first, what is a service offering?
Well, a service offering is a description
of one or more services designed
to address the needs of
a target consumer group.
In essence, a service provider
is going to present their
services to customers
or consumers in the form
of service offerings.
Which describes one or
more of their services
that are based on one or
more of their products.
Now, service offerings can include goods,
access to resources, and service actions
as part of that service offering.
Let's take my own company
as an example of a service provider.
We have many different
products that can help you
when you're studying for
your certification exams.
We have courses on ITIL, PRINCE2,
and numerous CompTIA certifications.
Each course contains a set of
videos, that's one product,
a practice exam or two,
that's another product,
and some amount of
access to the instructor
to ask questions, that would be a service.
Now, for example, when
you look at all of this,
you may be watching this video
as part of a single service
offering that you've paid for.
Maybe you're watching it as a
part of a subscription service
where you pay every month for
access to videos like ours
and maybe you've paid for
this as a single course.
It really depends on where
you're accessing it from.
You likely got a
different service offering
depending on where you end
up getting our course from.
For example, on our own website,
we don't offer one time purchases
that give you unlimited access for life,
instead, we run a
subscription based service,
where members get access
to every single
certification course we offer
for a low monthly fee.
Because of this, we have our video courses
and our practice exam courses
and students get access to hundreds
of practice exam questions
as part of that particular
service offering.
Now, other places where we
distribute this course though,
they may not offer a
monthly fee based service
where you can have as much as you want
for as long as you want.
Instead, they may treat the course
as a single product to be sold.
For a one time payment, you're
going to get all of the videos,
the study guide, and maybe
one or two practice exams.
And if you want more practice exams,
well, they're going to treat
that as a separate course
and you're going to have to
pay an additional payment
to get those.
I think you're getting the idea here
as I'm talking about this of
what a service offering is.
It shows you how we can group
and sell those different
products and services
multiple times in multiple different ways,
depending on the consumer
we're trying to reach.
You may have seen this with companies
that offer things as a monthly service
where different service offerings happen
based on the different functionalities
at the different price points.
For example, I use Hulu at my home,
which is a video on demand service.
Hulu has a few different pricing tiers.
The cheapest option is about $8 per month
and it gives you all of
the TV shows you want
but you have to watch commercials.
Instead, we decided to opt
for the next higher price
which is going to allow
us to pay $12 per month
but it eliminates all
of those commercials.
Now Hulu has even added a third tier.
They have a $40 per month
offering and this gives you access
to all of the TV without commercials,
but it also gives you
access to live news, sports,
and other things in a
cloud-based DVR service.
So as you moved up the pricing tier,
you got additional services
as part of that service offering.
Now, let's go back one more time
to the definition of a service offering.
If you remember, a service offering
is a description of one or more services
designed to address the needs
of a target consumer group.
Now remember, service
offerings can include goods,
access to resources and service actions
as part of that service offering too.
So before we close out this lesson,
we're going to quickly
define these three items.
First, we have goods.
Goods are things that are
supplied to the consumer.
These are things that are transferred
from the service provider to the consumer
and once that occurs,
the consumer is now responsible
for that future use.
For example, if you went
and signed up for a new service offering
from your local cellphone provider,
they're going to give you
a phone that you can use,
but you're now responsible for that phone.
If you break it, you're going
to have to pay to get a new one.
If you lose it, and somebody
makes a thousand dollars
in long distance calls,
well, you're going to be
the one getting the bill.
The goods, meaning the cellphone here,
were transferred from the
service provider to you,
and now, you as consumer
are responsible for it.
The second thing the service might offer
is to provide access to resources.
This means, that access to resources
is granted or a license
is given to a consumer
under some agreed terms and conditions.
My website is a great example of this.
When you purchase a
membership at my website,
you're given access to the videos,
the practice exams, hands-on labs,
and all of the other
stuff that we have there.
You're given a license to use them
under the terms and conditions
that you agreed to when you signed up.
These resources all remain
under the service providers control
and the service provider
is responsible for ensuring
that you can use them in
the way it was promised.
Now, here is where
things get a little messy
for consumers sometimes though.
Sometimes you may not like
the way the service provider
is willing to let you use their service.
For example, our website
doesn't allow videos
to be downloaded because we're
a subscription based service.
So if you stop paying your
monthly subscription fee,
you stop having access to those videos.
Therefore, we don't want you
to have them all downloaded
on your hard drive where you could sign up
for our service one day,
download all 20 of our courses
and cancel service the next day.
This is because we didn't
transfer the ownership
of that video to you,
instead we're just giving you
the access or a license to it
to use it and watch it as much as you want
as long as your
subscription remains active.
Now, if you don't like
those terms and conditions,
you're going to have to
find a different course
or a different way to purchase that course
that does allow you to
have that one time payment
where you can download it and
use it as much as you want.
But again, that's up to the relationship
between you and your service provider.
As a service provider,
we control the resource and
we're giving you access to it
under this service offering.
Now, the third thing that might be a part
of a service offering is a service action.
This is an action
that's performed to
address a consumer's need.
Let's use the example of a
piece of software you might have
a license for when you're
building a website.
For example, our website
uses a piece of software
as the basis of our
learning management system.
We paid for the software
with a one-time fee,
and we were given rights
to use it indefinitely,
as much as we want without
having to pay any recurring fees.
Now, this falls under that
goods category, right?
Well that part of it does
but for that one time fee,
we're not going to get any support
and we're not going to get
any updates or patches.
And if we want that technical support
for the software including the patches
and the security updates,
then we're going to have to pay
for that part of the service offering
which is considered a service action.
Because of this, we have
opted to pay an annual fee
to the company and in return for that,
we have 24 hour a day, seven
day a week technical support,
access to their staff, and we
can ask any questions we want,
and we also get access to
all the security updates
and patches as they're
going to be released.
So that's the difference
between goods, access to
resources, and service actions.
Goods are going to be
transferred over to the consumer.
Access to the resources is going to let
the consumer access them
on the terms and conditions
in the license that's been granted
from the service provider.
And service actions are
going to be covering
things that are going to be ongoing things
like technical support
and customer service fees.
That's the way you need to
remember it for the exam.