- Problem management, this is another one
that you need to know in depth.
Now for the exam, I want you to remember
the purpose of problem management.
This is to reduce the
likelihood and impact
of incidents by identifying actual
and potential causes of incidents
and managing workarounds and known errors.
In this definition, there's two key terms
that you need to be able
to recall for the exam.
They're the words problem
and a known error.
Now a problem is a cause or potential
cause of one or more incidents.
Remember, an incident is an unplanned
interruption to a service or a reduction
in the quality of that service.
If this happens more than once
to the same type of thing,
then it becomes a problem.
Sometimes though a problem can
be classified as a known error.
A known error is a problem that has been
analyzed and has not been resolved yet.
For example, we recently underwent
a website migration from
one server to another.
During that migration,
we found that the log in
link on our website was routing
users to the wrong place.
And it was preventing them from logging in
and accessing their training.
Now while our web developer
was working to resolve
the underlying issue,
we were able to notify
our users of this issue and we told them
that we had a known error
and gave them a direct
link to use to access the login page.
By giving our users this direct link,
we created what's known as a workaround.
A workaround is a solution
that reduces or eliminates
the impact of an incident
or problem for which a full
resolution is not yet available.
Sometimes these workarounds
will help you to reduce
the likelihood of incidents
from occurring again,
and these workarounds are documented
in your problem records.
Workarounds can then be
created at any stage,
and they don't need to wait
for you to fully analyze
the problem and have the
full complete solution done.
Instead, if you have a
workaround that's been documented
early in the problem control stage,
then this can be reviewed and improved
after the problem analysis
is fully completed.
So when we talk about problem
management, at its core,
we have three major steps inside of it.
The first is problem identification.
The second is problem control.
And the third is error control.
When we talk about problem identification,
here's what we're looking at
things like trend analysis,
identifying what recurring
incidents or major
incidents have happened, we're
looking at all the supplier
and partner information,
the software developers,
testers, and projects that are on-going.
And identifying any possible issues
that may turn into problems for us.
When we look at problem control,
we're trying to prioritize
and manage based on the risk.
We might have 5 or 6 or 7 problems,
but we only have enough time and money
to solve one of them right now.
Which one should we do first?
Well that becomes a prioritization
and risk management decision.
Also, we want to do our problem analysis
from the perspective
of all four dimensions.
We want to think about it
through all four of those lenses,
because it might be a problem
that can be solved with people
as opposed to technology or vice versa.
And then we go into error control.
With error control
we're trying to identify
potential permanent
solutions for this problem.
This allows us to reassess
any status of known errors
and improve our workarounds
so that we can solve
a lot of these problems.
Problem management is a
practice that relies heavily
on other practices as well.
Problem management has a
large amount of overlap
with the incident
management, risk management,
change control, knowledge management,
and continual improvement practices.
Each of these practices
will either provide
an input to problem management,
or receive information
from problem management
to better do their own jobs.
Now when we think about problem management
and the value chain activities,
it does impact a lot of them.
Let's start with improve.
When we think about
improve, problem management
and doing it effectively is
going to provide us a better
understanding of what needs to be done
to reduce the number
of incidents, thereby,
improving our services and our products.
Now engage on the other
hand, is going to be where
we take problems that
have significant impact
to our services, and tell our users
and our customers about it.
If we're telling our
customers or users something,
that's engage.
When we think about it from
a design and transition
perspective, problem
management is going to provide
information that helps
us to improve testing
and knowledge transfer from
those who are designing
and transitioning those
services into the real world.
And once they hit the real
world to deliver and support,
that's when your service
analysts have to know about it.
When we look at it from an
obtain and build perspective,
it's very similar to this.
Problem management activities
are going to help us
identify product defects
that are managed as part
of the overall value chain activity.
And we want to transfer that
information to the transition
team and to the deliver and support team.
And when we look at the
deliver and support,
problem management is
going to make a significant
contribution here, just like
incident management did.
Because as we identify
repetition of incidents,
we can then try to find
timely incident resolution
and solve them for the longer term
by solving the underlying problem.
That's the way we want to do this
as we look at problem management.
We want to find things that
happen again and again and again
and solve the root cause,
instead of having to keep
playing Whack-a-Mole with all
of the minor little incidents.
That's the whole goal here,
inside of the project management practice.