- Infrastructure and Platform Management.
Now, this practice is another one
you do not need to know for the exam.
But instead, we are going to cover it
so you at least have heard about it,
and you'll understand it a little bit
if somebody asks you about it.
When we talk about the infrastructure
and platform management practice,
it's really responsible for overseeing
the infrastructure and the platforms
that are used by the organization.
Now, what this really means
is that it's going to
enable the monitoring
of the technology solutions
that are available,
including solutions from third-parties.
So when I think about the
platform or the infrastructure,
I think about the servers, the software,
the network, all of that stuff.
Well, the people who are monitoring it
to make sure it's up and working properly,
that is part of infrastructure
and platform management.
This tends to be a very technical domain,
and it's one that's covered
by technical personnel
who are responsible to make sure
the systems are
up-and-running at all times.
Normally, this is people inside
your network operations center
or your security operations center.