- The Guiding Principles.
In this section of the course,
we're going to take a look at
the seven guiding principles
in ITIL 4.
Now this is important because on the exam
there are two exam objectives
that are going to cover
these seven guiding principles.
The first is to describe the nature,
use, and interaction of these
seven guiding principles.
And the second objective
is to explain the use
of these seven different
guiding principles.
And this is important
because we're not going to
have to memorize those guiding
principles necessarily,
or figure out what their definition is.
But we're actually
going to have to explain
and describe, which is a
level two level of effort
inside the exam.
So if I give you a scenario and I explain
what one of these guiding principles is,
you should be able to pick out and say
this guiding principle
relates to that scenario.
Now, before we go and dig into all of that
we have to go and think about
what is a guiding principle?
Well, a guiding principle
is a a recommendation
that's going to guide an organization
in all circumstances.
That's right, guiding
principles can be used
to guide an organization in their work
as they adopt a service
management approach
and adapt ITIL guidance to
their own specific needs
and circumstances.
This means that all organizations
are going to integrate
the use of multiple different methods
into their overall approach
to service management.
The way you do service management
and the way I do service
management might be different.
But, we both should be based
on the same guiding principles.
Because these guiding principles
are applied universally
to every initiative out there.
Now when we talk about applying
those guiding principles,
these guiding principles
are going to help us
to encourage and support our organizations
in their continual
improvement across all levels
of the organization.
These, as I said, are applied universally
to all of the initiatives, but also
to all of the relationships
with your different
stake holder groups.
So as we talk about the consumers
and the customers and the stake holders
across the organization,
all of these people
need to be considered when you're thinking
about these guiding principles.
For example, the first guiding principle
is known as focus on value.
Now with focus on value it
can, and should be applied,
to all of your relevant stake holders
and respective definitions of value.
We're not going to just consider the value
for the consumer, but we
also want to look at it
from the value for the customer.
We want to look at it for the value
for the service provider.
All of those different people
and stake holders need to be getting value
from whatever the service is we're doing.
And so that's a way that
we look at this stuff,
for example as we're looking at the focus
on value principle.
Now, as an organization
I'm not going to use
just one or two of these principles.
But I should consider all seven of them,
and determine which ones are relevant
for each situation and
how I should apply them.
Not all of the principles
are going to be critical
in every situation.
But you're probably
going to find that five
or six, or even seven of them,
may apply to your initiative.
And so you want to think
through each of them,
kind of like a check list,
to make sure you're thinking
about your service in a holistic way.
As you do this and you
review each of them,
you have a way to determine whether or not
they're appropriate for your service
and should it be applied.
Now, I mentioned a lot about
these guiding principles
so far but I haven't even
told you what they are.
Well, throughout the rest of this section
we're going to focus on the
seven guiding principles.
The first is focus on value.
The second is start where you are.
The third is progress
iteratively and with feedback.
The fourth is to collaborate
and promote visibility.
The fifth is to think
and work holistically.
The sixth is to keep it
simple and practical.
And finally our seventh one
is to optimize and automate.
So, let's get started looking
at our seven guiding principles.