- The next practice we're going
to discuss is risk management,
and again this is just for
your general awareness,
but it one we've talked about earlier
on in our course, because we did talk
about those four things
you can do with risk.
When we talk about risk management,
this practice is focused on ensuring
that an organization understands
and handles its risk effectively.
Now, when we look at risk,
there are four things
you can do with it.
You can avoid risk, you can mitigate risk,
you can transfer risk,
or you can accept risk.
When you avoid risk, you're
going to change the situation
so that risk doesn't exist anymore.
I like to use the example
of if your company
has a computer that's running Windows XP,
that's a highly risky event.
Well, you can avoid that risk completely
by turning off that computer,
upgrading it to Windows 10,
and now you have that
risk completely avoided,
because you're no longer having the risk
of having this old, outdated system.
Now, mitigation on the other hand,
is where we're going to
put some things in place
to help lower the amount of risk.
For example, if I wanted to drive
my car from here to the store,
I'm not going to drive
it 60 miles an hour.
I decided I'm going to
drive it 30 miles an hour.
That lowers my risk
because it gives me more
time to react to issues.
That's a risk mitigation.
When I talk about risk transference,
that's when I'm going to transfer
the risk to somebody else.
In the example of my car,
I have an insurance policy on my car.
If I get into an accident,
I'm not the one who assumes that risk.
The insurance company is.
They're going to pay for the damages,
because I paid them a
premium and that transferred
the risk from me to them
for that financial issue.
And finally, we have risk acceptance.
If you have a risk that's small enough,
you might just decided
you're going to accept it.
For example, there are risk
every day that you deal with,
and you just simply accept them.
When you get in the car to drive to work,
there's a risk you could
get into an accident.
Yes, you've transferred
the financial risk,
but if you get into an accident
you're still going to get hurt, right?
Well, you figured that
that risk is small enough
that you have accepted that risk,
whether willing or unwillingly,
so that you can drive your car to work.
That's the idea when you
deal with risk management.
It's identifying all the
risks that are going to exist
for our product and services,
as well as our projects
as we're deploying them.
And then we try to mitigate them,
transfer them, avoid them, or accept them,
and that way we know
what we're dealing with.