- Continual improvement.
Our first general management practice
is continual improvement.
And for the exam, this is
the one you need to know
in depth from this section.
For this one, you need to be able
to explain continual improvement,
what its purpose is, and how it applies
throughout the value chain.
So when we talk about
continual improvement,
what exactly is its purpose?
Well, the purpose of the
continual improvement practice is
to align the organization's
practices and services
with changing business needs
through the ongoing
identification and improvement
of services, service
components, practices,
or any other element involved
in the efficient and effective
management of products
and services; basically, how
do we make things work better.
That's what continual
improvement is all about.
Now when we think about
continual improvement,
there's a couple of key
things that it focuses on.
First, we wanta encourage
continual improvement
across the organization.
We always wanta be aiming
for something bigger, better,
faster, cheaper, or more efficient.
The second key function of
continual improvement is
to secure time and budget
for continual improvement.
It's really easy in an
organization to keep working
on the same things day in and day out
and not think about how to improve.
You wanta make sure you're
securing that time and budget
so we can continue to work
on improving our processes.
Next, we wanta think about identifying
and logging improvement opportunities.
Anytime you're working on
something, you might have an idea
and say, "You know, this would
be better if we did x thing."
At that point we wanta log
that down, identify it,
and that way, eventually, we
might be able to get back to it
and cause that improvement to happen.
Another thing we wanta
think about is how we assess
and prioritize our
improvement opportunities.
You may have a hundred great ideas,
but which one should we work on first?
That's part of continual improvement.
We also wanta think
about how we're going to
make a business case for
those improvement actions.
At some point, you need to get budget
for your improvement, right?
So you're going to haveta think
about how we're going to be able
to do that and make the case for it up
to your senior leadership
or your senior management.
Maybe you're going to say
something like, "Hey, boss,
"I think we should do
this improvement action.
"It's going to take us 20
hours right now to build it,
"but it's going to save
us 10 hours a week.
"So in just two weeks, we're
going to make up that time.
"It's a great idea."
That would be an example of
making your business case.
Next, we wanta think about
how we're going to plan
and implement those improvements;
and we wanta figure out
how we're going to measure
and evaluate the improvements
and the results of those improvements.
Again, we've talked a lot
about this when we talked
about the continual improvement model
in the last section of the course.
This is just the formal practice
that is going to work that model.
And we also wanta make
sure we're coordinating
our improvement activities
across the organization.
Remember, we wanta think
holistically and act widely
across the organization
for the best improvements.
Now when we're working
with continual improvement,
there's a lot of different tools
that we can put into our toolbox.
These are things like methods,
and models, and techniques.
This is things like lean
methods where we're trying
to reduce waste, multiphase
projects where we're trying
to organize the way
we're going to do things
and get incremental improvements.
We might do maturity
assessments to figure out
how mature our organization is,
and are we operating at peak efficiency.
We might be using development ops
so that we can develop
things quicker and faster
and get them into market.
We might use something
like a balance score card
where we look at the improvement,
and we look at it through the lens
of those four different
dimensions of service management.
We also might be using agile
improvements and techniques.
We might be trying to get some quick wins.
Or we might even do a SWOT analysis.
And a SWOT analysis is something
that they teach in business school.
It's where you list out the
strengths, the weaknesses,
the opportunities, and the
threats; and then you figure out
how that applies to your given initiative.
Now all of this is great.
And there's one more technique or tool
that you should be using,
and it's called a Continual
Improvement Register.
Now a Continual Improvement
Register or CIR is a database
or a structured document that we use
to track and manage all
of the improvement ideas
from the identification
through final action.
So, as I said before,
you might sitting there;
and you come up with a great idea.
Well, if you just think about it
and nothing gets done, we're
never going to improve.
So instead, you should submit
that idea into the CIR,
the Continual Improvement Register.
From there, we'll log it in there.
And, eventually, we're going to figure out
whether or not we're going to
work on that improvement idea;
and if that improvement has a
low, medium, or high impact,
and what the resolution is.
Did we decide to do it or
did we not decide to do it?
And if we decide to do it,
when are we going to decide to do it?
And how are we going to plan for it?
So that's the whole idea.
Here's an example of a CIR.
Here you can see that there
are three different things
that are listed and the impact
for each one: medium, medium, and high.
And then the last column
there would be where we said
what we're going to do with it.
Yes, we're going to do this initiative,
and we're going to start it
in quarter one of next year.
Whatever that plan is,
we wanta make sure we're capturing it.
The last thing I wanta talk
about in continual improvement
is how it's operated when you talk
about continual improvement
with the relationships involved.
We like to put this in as a pyramid.
So if we start at the
bottom, and we start thinking
about our partners and
suppliers, how can we improve
our relationships with
partners and suppliers?
Well, we can do that by
going through and looking
at our contracts, including
how we're going to measure,
report, and improve those processes.
Then we look inside our
entire organization,
which is the next large
audience that we have.
And from there, we wanta try
to get active participation
and continual improvement initiatives
as a core part of everyone's job.
When it comes down to
it, continual improvement
isn't the job of the
continual improvement manager.
It's the job of everyone
in the organization.
And then we have the
continual improvement team led
by the continual improvement manager.
Their job is to lead
the efforts and advocate
for the practice across
the entire organization.
They're the ones trying
to get everyone else
in the organization to join in the fight
and help us improve.
And then all the way at
the top of the pyramid,
we have those few leaders at the top.
And those are going to be
the ones who going to try
to embed continual
improvement into the way
that people think and work by
providing that proper vision.
And so this really does hark back to
that continual improvement
model we talked about.
If we look at this pyramid
and we do it from the top
to the bottom instead, we
start seeing the leaders
who come up with the vision,
which is the beginning
of our continual improvement model.
Then we have our continual
improvement team,
and that team is the ones who are going
to be doing the baseline assessments
of where we are and
determining where we wanta be.
They're also going to
help develop the plans.
But then when we wanta take
action, we have to do that
with everyone in the organization
including our partners
and suppliers outside the organization.
And then we're going to
reassess where we are,
and then figure out how do
we keep this momentum going,
and do it all again.
You could see how this
all ties in together
time and time again.
Now, the last thing I
wanta talk about here
in continual improvement
is how it integrates
with the different value chain activities.
So if we look at how continual
improvement is going to work
inside plan, the continual
improvement practice is applied
to all planning activities.
We're going to look at
the methods and techniques
to make sure that they're all relevant
for the organization's current objective
in the context in which we're operating.
When we start looking at this
from the improve perspective,
the continual improvement practice is key
to this value chain activity.
It's all about improvement.
It structures our resources
and our activities
to enable that improvement at all levels
of the organization and across
the service value system.
Now as we look at the rest
of the service value chain,
and we look at the value chain activities
of engage, design and
transition, obtain and build,
and deliver and support,
each of these value chain
activities are subject
to continual improvement
because we're always trying
to improve our practices,
our activities, and our processes.
And the continual
improvement practice itself
is applied to all of these.
As you can see, the continual
improvement practice
is inside everything we do inside ITIL 4.
We're always trying to
continue to improve.
If we go back and look at the
service value chain again,
you see that improve touches
all of those inner cubes
and the engage process
with that purple line.
That's because it impacts
every single one of them.
That's the key here.
Continual improvement is
the key to our success
in ITIL 4 because we never
want to stop improving.