- Our third technical
management practice is
Software Development and Management.
Again, this one is not
covered by the exam.
The software development
and management practice
is responsible for
ensuring that applications
meet stakeholder needs in
terms of their functionality,
their reliability, their
maintainability, their compliance,
and their auditability.
So, whether we're developing it in-house
or we're going to be deploying
other people's software
into our environment,
it's going to be handled
through this practice.
So if I'm going to go ahead and
install Windows Server 2019,
that is going to be done
and managed through software
development and management.
We're going to make sure
that that software meets our
functionality needs,
our reliability needs,
our maintainability needs,
our compliance needs,
and our auditability needs.
Now, we're not going to be
the ones who are going to push
that out into the environment.
That's going to happen through release
and deployment management.
But we're going to make
sure we're tracking it
all along the way and we
know what applications
are out there that are meeting
our stakeholders needs.