- Partners and suppliers,
this is our third dimension.
Now, partners and suppliers
are really organizations
and people, but they're not going to fit
under dimension one.
The reason is we talk about organizations
and people who are internally focused.
We're looking at our
company and our organization
and the people that support it.
When we talk about partners and suppliers
we're talking about things external to us.
Now, the other question
that comes up often,
is why do I have to call
it partners and suppliers?
Aren't they one and the same?
Well, no, there's a
difference between people
who are your partners and
people who are your suppliers.
And we'll talk about that in this lesson.
First, let's consider this.
There are the service provider
and the service consumer
and they have that relationship.
We talk about that back in section two.
When we talk about that,
there are some people
who are consuming something
and somebody who is providing that.
Now, in our organization, we
may be the service provider
and we're selling things
to our customers, right?
Or our consumers.
But we're probably also taking things in
that we're going to use and in
that case we're the consumer
and the somebody else
is our service provider.
That might be a partner of ours
or it might be a supplier of ours.
Now, whether you're going to
use a partner or a supplier,
is going to depend on your
organization strategy.
You're going to think
about is this something
that is critical to
our business and if so,
you probably need it more
as a partner relationship.
If it's something that's not as critical,
it might be in the supplier relationship.
Well, let me give you an example of this.
My company is in partnership
with PeopleCert and AXELOS.
Now, PeopleCert is the people
who are going to test you
for the ITIL exam and
AXELOS are the people
who write the exam and
all of the text books.
Because of our partnership with them,
we get access to the text books
about six months to a year
before they're available for students.
That gives us time to get them, read them,
learn all the information
and then build all the practice exams
and the courses for you.
Also we get all the
objectives ahead of time.
All of the stuff is things
that AXELOS and PeopleCert provide to us
as part of our partnership.
And because we are aligned
with them in this partnership,
we get all these critical
business functions
and we get input into them
and they get input back to us.
That's a partnership.
Now if I look at a supplier
relationship on the other hand,
my company has a bunch or
printers in our office.
Now if you want to get
some paper for the printer,
or you want to get some ink
and toner for the printer,
that's a supplier.
I'm going to go up on Amazon,
I'm going to order some stuff,
Amazon's going to drop
it on the front door
and we're now going to
have paper and toner
and staplers and things
like that for the company.
I don't need to know what
Amazon's going to be doing
in the next six months to be able
to make sure that supply order
is going to continue to go on.
Because if Amazon stops doing
printer and toner and ink,
I can just pick somebody else to do it.
It's a commodity.
But if AXELOS decide that
they were going to turn off
the ITIL certification, and
no longer offer it anymore,
that's something that's very
critical to our business,
and we need to know about it.
So that's the difference
between this partnership
and a supplier relationship.
With a partner you have a lot more buy in,
you have a lot more two way communication.
You might share plans and road maps.
For example, AXELOS has already told us,
when the next part of the
ITIL certification comes out,
the foundation is the first level.
And then there are five other exams
that allow you to get up
to being an ITIL Master.
We already have the roadmap and know
when those are going to happen,
so we can build all those
products to that partnership.
With a supplier I don't know
if Amazon's going to change the type
of paper they're going
to supply next week,
but I really don't care.
As long as it's eight and a half by eleven
and it's white and it goes in the printer,
that's fine by me, right?
It's a big difference when
you're dealing with a partnership
versus a supplier.
Now, this is going to influence
your supplier strategy.
You're going to have to think about,
do I care about price most?
Do I care about quality most?
Do I care about being
able to exchange it out
with different people?
Let me give you a couple
of examples of this.
Let's say you're building your technology
and you're going to build a new website.
You decide you're going
to host it on the Cloud.
There's three major providers
for Cloud right now.
You have Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure
and Amazon's AWS service,
the Amazon Web Services.
You can use any of those three.
They're all fairly equivalent, right?
But you need to understand
when you pick one,
that it's pretty painful to have to move
from one to the other.
And so you probably want to pick one
with a long term strategy
of staying with it.
Because once you pick one,
you're going to get your staff
trained to that certifications.
So if I'm going to go with
Microsoft, I'm going to get a bunch
of my folks Azure qualified.
If I go with Amazon, I'm going
to get the AWS certified, right?
And we're going to build
ourself around that strategy.
It's not as easy moving from Azure to AWS
as it is to go from HP paper
to Boston paper, right?
Paper is paper, it still
fits in the printer.
And so there's a different
level of supplier there.
But it's still a supplier.
You're not going to
necessarily have a partnership
with AWS where they're going
to give you their roadmap
for the next five years.
That's not the level of
partnership you have.
And so these are going to be
some of the different factors
that are going to affect
whether you're going to be
more of a commodity based
and look for the lowest price
like you might for ink
and toner and paper,
or if you're going to be looking
at other factors that have impact,
such as reliability,
quality, track record.
If I'm going for a web provider,
those are things I care about,
or all the way on the other side,
we have those partnerships,
where we're fully involved
with the long term goals
and strategies of that organization.
Now, the last thing I
want to talk about here,
is this concept of a service integration.
Now, with service
integration, a lot of times,
you're going to have a lot of
different things out there.
If I look at the service that I use
to be able to provide my videos to you,
I have a video service out
there, I have a store front,
I have a website, we have Cloud hosting,
we've got five or six different things,
that we have to tie together to make sure,
that we deliver the videos to you,
the way that you want to get them.
Now, we do that all internally,
because we want to make
sure it's done right.
And because it's a reasonable number,
four or five or six different services.
But if you're in a very large company,
you might have a lot
of different suppliers.
I worked in one organization,
where we have thousands
of different suppliers,
because we had a hundred
thousand employees,
it was a huge organization.
And so we didn't want to have to deal
with all of those people individually.
Instead, we hired a third party,
called a service integrator
and it was their job to
do all of the management
of all of those suppliers for us.
And so we would pay the integrator
and they would reach out
to all those different organizations
and manage those relationships for us
and make sure we got
the products we needed
at the time we needed and
the delivery we needed.
And so if you're going to integrate
in a bunch of different services
and a bunch of different suppliers,
those service integrators
can really be helpful.
So to summarize
partnerships and suppliers.
When we talk about partnerships,
this is where you're going
to share common goals
and risks with the partner.
You're going to collaborate
to achieve the desired outcomes you want
and you're going to make sure
that you're both in it together.
So in the example of
AXELOS and PeopleCert,
and DION training, we're
all in it together.
I AXELOS starts not selling exams,
because their brand goes down,
then employers don't want
people to get certified in it
and that hurts my business as well.
And so we're all in it
together to make sure
that the brand stays good,
the employers still want it
and that ITIL is still valuable.
Now, when we start talking about
suppliers on the other hand
we're talking about
goods and service, right?
This can be done through formal contracts.
There's a clear separation
of responsibilities.
I pay X amount of dollars
and I get X amount of band width.
Or I get X amount of Cloud space,
or I get X amount of reams of paper.
Whatever those things
are, that's all handled
through contracting
and it's a deliverable.
I pay you for this, you
do this amount of work.
When you outsource a function,
that's considered a
supplier, not a partnership.
Now, every organization and
every service is going to depend
on some extent on other organizations.
Whether they're partners or suppliers.
There is nothing you
can do that you're doing
without any other partners out there.
Something out there is doing it.
That might be that you have
a supplier like Microsoft
that provides you Microsoft office
when you pay a fee.
It might be your internet
service provider,
who you're paying a
monthly fee to get online
to do your business.
Whatever it is, there
is something out there
that is part of this
partners and suppliers.
And a lot of times there are
a lot of these somethings
which is Service
Integration and Management.
Service Integration and
Management involves the use
of specially established
integrators to ensure
that the service relationships
are properly coordinated.
Now what does that mean?
Well if you think about it, there's a lot
of different moving pieces here.
If I go and look at my
website for example,
I have the website that has
to be coded by a programmer.
I have the graphics
that need to be added on
by a graphic designer.
I have somebody who needs to
host this with a web server.
I have the videos hosted on
a different video server.
I have somebody who does
the credit card processing.
We've got five or six or seven
different suppliers involved
just to be able to run a
simple E-Commerce website.
And probably more than that
if I started listing them all out.
Well, we can either do the
service integration internal
to the organization, meaning
that I can go and work
with all of these individual vendors
to make sure the product works properly,
or I can outsource that
to a service integration
and management person.
And if I hire a service integrator,
they'll do all of that for me.
So I can contract to them,
they can go out to all of
those third party vendors,
get it all working
and then just bring me
back the results I want.
In that case they become
a service provider to me,
doing service integration and
I become the service consumer,
consuming the service that
I just outsourced to them.
Now, should you use a service integrator?
Well, that depends on your
organization strategy.
Your strategy when it comes to partners
and suppliers and integrators
is all going to be based
on your goals, your culture
and your business environment.
There's a lot of different
things going on out there
and figuring out what
your supplier strategy is,
is something that's going to help.
For the exam though, you
just need to remember
that we have partners and suppliers.
Partners are more closely
tied into our business.
Suppliers tend to be
more commoditized things.
And if you can keep that straight,
you'll do great on the exam.