- Change Control.
In this lesson, we're going to talk about
the Change Control practice.
Now, for the exam, this is one
of the ones you need to know in depth.
You need to be able to recall it's
definition and purpose, as well as
terms associated with
it, and how it operates.
So, let's get started.
The purpose of the Change Control practice
is to maximize the number of successful
IT changes by ensuring that the risks
have been properly assessed, authorizing
changes to proceed, and
managing the change schedule.
Basically, Change Control is what
we used to call Change Management.
It's all about making sure that
before we make a change,
we understand the risk,
we know who's approved it, and
we manage it on the schedule.
So, when we do this, this
is all a balancing act.
We want to balance the
beneficial effect of changes
against protecting ourself from
adverse effects of changes.
Just think about it this way,
every time you change something,
you're introducing a risk of failure,
and so the change has to be worth while.
We like thing that are
stable and working properly,
but we also like new features and value.
And so, a lot of times
we have to make changes,
but that's going to effect
the stability of the system.
And so, we want to be
able to manage that risk
using risk management, as
well as this Change Control.
Now, the scope of Change Control
is defined by each organization.
This is something that
is going to be decided
by your governance, your policies,
and your procedures within
your particular company.
It's going to include all
of the IT infrastructure,
the applications, the documentation,
the processes, the supplier relationships,
and anything else that might directly
or indirectly impact a product or service
that we're going to change.
Now, I mentioned there were seven terms
that you had to learn definitions of
during the study of our practices.
Well, here's the first one.
It's called a change.
Now, a change is the
addition, modification,
or removal of anything that could have
a direct or indirect
effect on IT services.
There's actually three
different types of changes.
There's standard, normal,
and emergency changes.
A standard change is something
that is preauthorized.
It's something that we can implement
without additional authorization.
This is because it's something
we do all of the time,
the risks are well understood, and
therefore it's going to be low risk.
A good example of this would be
if somebody calls up and
asks to reset their password.
That is something that
a service desk analyst
can do on their own, they don't need
any kind of approval, because
it's already been preauthorized.
This is a simple, well understood change,
but it is still a change to the system.
Our second type of change is
what we call a normal change.
These are changes where authorization
is going to have to be gained, but
that level of authorization is
going to be based on the different
types of change and how risky it is.
So, if this was a low
or a medium risk thing,
but we don't consider
it a standard change,
it's going to go through
the normal process,
and the person who approves it
is called a Change Authority.
If it's going to be something that is
low or medium risk, that Change Authority
might be your supervisor or their boss.
But if you have a major change,
this might be something
that is really complex,
it's going to need a
higher level of approval,
and it's going to go all the way up
until we get a very
senior Change Authority.
Again, this is going to depend on
how your organization does it,
how much tolerance they have to risk,
and how they want to set it up.
Let me give you an example
of a normal change.
Let's just say, you wanted
to upgrade your server
from Windows 2012 to Windows 2019.
This is a major change,
so we want to make sure
we properly plan for that change.
We want to make sure we get the necessary
coordination done ahead of time,
and we want to make sure all the
right approvals have been done
before we ever attempt to install
that new server software.
That's the idea here with a normal change.
We're going to schedule it, and plan it,
we're going to go and
get a down time for it,
and we're going to do that change
and make sure it all worked properly.
We've got time, we're not in a rush.
Now, sometimes though, we are in a rush,
and this is when things
come up like an emergency.
And so, we have emergency changes.
These are going to be expedited,
and their going to have
an expedited assessment
and authority process.
It may be that there's a
separate change authority
for something that is an emergency.
For example, I used to
work as an IT Director,
and normally for a big change,
I had to go up to my boss who is the CIO,
but if it was an emergency,
I was the Change Authority
and I had permission
to make those changes.
So, I might get a call
at 2:30 in the morning
on a Saturday, and they'd say
that our file server just crashed.
The hard drives in it are completely dead
and they need to be replaced with
spares from a backup server, and
while we're doing that we need to
change some of the configurations.
Well, this is going to
constitute a change,
but we don't have time to go through
all the necessary paperwork of
a normal change requirement.
So, instead, we're going to go through
an Emergency Change Advisory Board.
We're going to get people together,
quickly decide on how risky it is,
do our assessment, and either approve
or disapprove this
because it's an emergency.
We need to get this server back up.
Then, when we come back
in on Monday morning,
we can worry about going back and
doing all the normal change
requirement paperwork,
and going through the regular processes
to make sure everything has
gotten updated in the system.
That's the difference.
An emergency is when you're really
trying to get something
back online quickly,
because something is broke and
it needs to be gotten up right now.
A lot of organizations
will use their emergency
as something as a normal way of business.
You don't want to do this.
And what I mean by this is, just because
somebody wants the change done today,
doesn't mean that it's
necessarily an emergency.
It may be they just forgot to plan.
So, you have to think about what
really is an emergency
versus what is normal
and should go through the normal process.
If something is broken and you need
to get the server back online,
that's usually going to be an emergency.
Now, as I said, the person or group who
authorizes the change is what
we call a Change Authority.
In very fast moving organizations,
it's common to have this decentralized,
and we might have many
different Change Authorities
depending on what's going on.
In fact, if you're doing
software development,
your Change Authority might be
the person sitting next to you.
It might be that you review their code
and approve it and they approve your code.
But in big organizations, a lot of times
we want to do things much more formally,
and we'll go through this
normal change process,
and have a formalized Change Authority.
Now, once something has been approved from
the Change Authority, it goes
on to the Change Schedule.
The Change Schedule is used to help us
plan those changes, assist
in communicating that,
and helping to avoid conflicts
and assign proper resources to it.
Let me give you a good example of this.
This weekend, I want to upgrade my website
and we're going to be down for an hour
while we change servers.
That's something that I'm going to
email out ahead of time
to all of my students,
so they know this Friday
if they try to log on,
they're not going to be
able to for that hour.
That's the idea of having
a Change Schedule in place.
We already know what's going to happen,
we can tell you weeks in advance,
and that way everybody knows.
It's well coordinated, well
planned, and well communicated.
And by doing that, I can make sure
I have my top level guys sitting there,
ready to go when we make this change.
So, if anything goes wrong, we have
the A list people there who
can fix it and make it right.
So, when we talk about
all of this change stuff,
it does effect different parts of
our Value Change activities.
For example, we have a part in Plan.
Changes for our products
and service portfolio,
our policies, and practices all require
some ammount of control and planning.
And so, Plan is going
to help us with that.
We also have a lot of
improvement initiatives, right.
And when we go through
improvement initiatives,
those are going to have to
have to be changes made.
For example, if I want to move from
an older server to a new
server, that's a change.
And so, we're going to
use the Change Control
as part of the Improve activity, as well.
When we talk about Engage, our customers
and our users need to know what
kind of changes are coming,
when down times are, and they should
be able to expect the
nature of that change.
Again, by communicating
this, we're engaging
with our customers, so we're going to
use that Engage activity.
Then, if we look in our
Design and Transition,
these changes are all designed
and initiated somewhere, right?
Usually in Design, and then Transition.
Once we approve a change it goes
into transition to be made into a reality
and put into our real network.
Now, this is where the
Change Control activity
is a major contributor
into the transition phase.
Then, we're going to obtain
and build things, right?
Anytime I want to change something,
it means I'm probably
buying something new,
whether it's software, or it's hardware,
or I'm building some kind
of custom software in house,
all of that goes on in the Obtain/Build.
Once it's ready, it's going to be an input
into this Change Control practice,
so that we can get it approved
and transitioned onto the real servers.
And then, finally, Deliver and Support.
Changes can have an impact
on Deliver and Support.
They can have a huge impact there,
because if I put a new server on
that changes the way they
have to do their processes,
that changes the way
they do their procedures.
All that stuff is going to be changed.
We also want to make
sure we are communicating
the changes both to our users, but also
to the personnel who have
to support those users.
If I don't tell the Service Agents
that we went from server
2012 to server 2019,
and they now have to support 2019
without any training,
that's not going to be good.
So, change is going to make sure that
we're thinking about those
type of things, as well.
We want to make sure everybody
knows what change is coming,
and we communicate that
well so everyone is ready.